hello everyone and welcome to episode
134 of the 10-minute Ming challenge this
week we're going to be going back to the
roots of the 10-minute modeling
Challenge and I'm going to be doing
something pretty simple I'm going to do
box modeling from scratch and I'm going
to slap a bridge into the game of unfair
Rampage Nightfall which I made and it's
currently on Steam nextfest so if you
haven't checked out the free demo make
sure to head over there and have a look
at it and download it and give it a play
I'll keep it up online as well for a
couple of weeks after steam next Fest
ends cuz there's a lot of games going on
right there and speaking of that I'm
going to start this uh like Intro by
just having a look at Steam nextfest and
just I'll probably fast forward it
because I'm going to see how long it
takes until I find my game in the list
of games there I've gone as Incognito
here under stealth stealth mode like
James Bond but without just like a o z
um that's without the seven I guess
they've changed it this year they don't
do the live stream slots like they did
previous years and I'm a bit un unhappy
about that because it was really good
when we did line War and um we had steam
nextfest when you had your live stream
slot we I think we had over a thousand
people coming to the stam page right
then so it's was a little bit sad to
hear that this month or this time around
on this next Fest they've like they
dropped their focus on that one and it's
over 3,000 games participating in Steam
nextfest so I have a feeling that it's
going to be very difficult to attract
any attention this year but we'll uh
we'll have a look at it and maybe learn
a few things from it anyway and I'm also
discovering that I'm I'm finding quite a
lot of cool games that are coming out so
I'm actually going to do a little video
maybe where I play test some of those
demos that should be fun but I'm going
to look here now steam power.com SL sale
SL nextfest home and I'm just going to
like press play and then I'm just going
to skim through as under stealth mode
here let's see how many we go one 2 3 4
I'm
1,1 1 102 13 104 low poly
cool
95 906 97 908 909 9,10 91
92 93
94 9
1,4 I got
it okay 94
no 1,4 I can't can't even count I I know
there are over 3,000 games so I'm
guessing I'm pretty lucky anyway that
I'm in like in the first about 1,000 so
I'm not expecting a massive like flood
like the flood gates are not going to
open to come to see my game and I don't
even know if anyone will notice it to be
honest but it's going to be an an
important journey to see the wish list
I've picked up a little bit maybe I'm
getting like 60 or 70 a day now and it's
a long way to 10,000 wish lists but I'm
going to I'm going to have to do some
tradition marketing as well J in my
Discord is uh telling me as well that I
need to do traditional marketing too
which of course I have to do so I have
to figure out some way reach out to some
other YouTubers and get some streamers
doing it and look at other ways to
advertise it maybe I have to be a little
bit active in different forums and stuff
but it's a tricky balance not to spam
but to like to spread your word uh so
we'll we'll see how it goes I'm sure
it'll be all right like this game a few
Reflections that I did there's a lot of
games that are coming out of course and
a lot of them look are look pretty nice
there were a few of them that really
caught my eyes that I've actually got to
check out I'm going to look through my
recording and see cuz there was like
three or four or five games there like I
want to have a look at this one
89 that looks cool
189 I have to look at that
one
19 oh that looks
nice 24 2 15 oh very close to my
characters that's cool 293 294 295 that
look nice
294 295 297
308 that looks nice 308
309 oh that was CGA 328 cool 328 329 low
poly 336 3357
358 that looks cool ooh I have to
remember that one 358 359 445 446 447
that looks nice
oh like it
448 467 468 low poly 469 cool skiing oh
I did snow like that 47 503 nice 504
cool whoa 6 I have to remember
that 675 6794
695 nice as well ooh
nice 696 69
809 this is cool I'm going to make a
game like this I love it I have to check
that one 789 7 so and another reflection
I did that there was a lot of low poly a
lot of col for low poly stuff kind of
cool to see and uh I'm I don't know
maybe not so good for me because it
it'll like melt in my low poly style
will start blending in with everything
else so I mean but it's kind of cool to
see that it's uh like it's on a on a
good pop rise another reflection I did
was that there was a lot of Nic looking
games a lot of quirky ones and a lot of
fun stuff and it's fun to see Indies
being able to really like go at it and
just create whatever they want without
the pressure of a publisher to shove it
down their throat what they want them to
publish what could be making money so a
lot of weird little quirky games are
coming out which is cool I also saw a
bunch of horror games and I think that's
because um about a year and a year and a
half and two years ago there was like a
gap in the market and we had all the
piggy things and Five Nights at Freddy's
and stuff so I think all of those games
are starting to hit the market now so
it's probably going to flood the market
with with horror games instead and I
horror games never been my thing I don't
like anything horror stuff so I'll just
stick to like action or Adventure or a
combination of the two so should be kind
of cool in my last video I showed the
little Pac-Man ghosts that my daughter
had uh been crocheting and she's been
added again first she made this one and
it's so
fluffy she made this one it's a it's a
little cow and it's super super smooth
it's like the the yarn that she's used
is like so nice and fluffy so and she's
going to open up a little business and
sell these in some local markets and see
how that goes and I think we're even
going to look at uh setting something up
online for her so maybe we can auction a
few these off or something and jzilla is
already like expressed her interest to
get this one so we U we're working
things out there and today she made this
one took 7 hours it's a little ballerina
with a little uh like little skirt on
and everything and she's really
progressed she started earlier this year
and she's H 10 years old now and she's
crocheting like a little crochet master
so I have to go and buy some more yarn
soon and I think we're also going to
have a challenge where she's going to be
crocheting something and I'm going to be
3D modeling the same thing so we'll
probably put a video up on that in in
the series that should be a lot of fun
as well all right let's head over to
blender now and I've got a little start
scene going here and this is the box
that we're going to be starting from
I've placed two of the stone blocks here
from unfair Rampage and uh they're going
to be acting as a little connector
because I need to build a new bridge
between here this is the bridge that's
already in the game and uh um for every
time you cross a bridge it's the same
Bridge so I really want to model five
different ones cuz there are five
different Bridges to cross and the first
one is like a broken Wood Bridge and the
second thing I'm think I'm going to do
some sort of a stone bridge here and see
how that goes and I think after I
modeled it I'll spend a little time to
just Tweaky if anything's broken and
then I'll bring it into the game as well
so we can see that what what that one
looks like so I think that's what we're
going to do I'm going to put my my phone
in aircraft mode CU I'm not going to fly
anywhere but I don't want it to be
going in my speakers or in my microphone
so let's do that first of all batteries
all right clock let's put 10 minutes on
the clock here timer 10 minutes and
we're going to be enabling screencast
Keys we need that so you can see what's
going on and let's resize that a little
bit and let's get started so this is
going to be my reference these are my
little anchor points and this is the one
that we're going to be modeling from
I've got my pix pal texture see we got
uh proportional smooth blah blah blah
that's all right let's get started
ready uh Stone Bridge for unfair Rampage
Nightfall in Ready
Steady go and we're off woo yep all
right so Ty ined mode and uh eight
select everything scale s to scale and
scale on the y axis scale on the xaxis
I'm going to make it a little bit wider
like that control R Loop cut and we'll
do 20 Loop Cuts ni and round and then
three to face select shift select these
two and then I'm going to do
proportional and then uh I guess I'll do
like an arc like this sharp
gz and then we'll do something like this
don't know why I don't get a perfect
circle here so or like an arch so let's
manually change these as well so I'll go
g z and then just try to tweak it a
little bit I don't know it doesn't have
to be perfect that's a good thing this
uh back in these days so scale Zed and
then we'll just flatten this as well and
then El select the link and bring it up
to here something like that will be will
be good I'll select these and uh like
actually I'll shift select these no I'll
I'll control select and then okay to
there e to extrude Middle click to like
snap it on the axis and then bring it
down to there and then scale should I
scale these I'll shift select these and
think I'm going to scale this a little
bit on the Y axxis probably better ways
to do this but let's go something like
that I don't know
H we'll see how it goes and then I'll
alt select on this edge here cuz that
ring selects everything around shift
select shift select these and ALT e to
extrude long face normals and just get a
little like I don't know something
something there a little something
something and I've got an itchy nose bad
timing
8:30 all right so it's I think it's
actually L select link scale Zed let's
flatten this whole thing out a little
bit like this and also I'm going to do
some foundations here or something I
don't know I'm I'm not going to like pay
like too much I'll just do it's actually
better if it's a bit irregular on both
sides so it like looks a bit different
so I'll just do e to extrude S to scale
it down there a bit and then uh I think
e to extrude uh I'll move this scale on
the Y AIS or something cuz these are
going to be disappearing down into
foreverness so I'm not too bothered
about these things and uh I'll do the
same I'll actually do Shifty to
duplicate it scale on the Y
axis1 and we'll move it here and I think
I need to do uh let's see back face
calling I currently see in this view so
alt and recalculate outside just in case
there those are inverted and let's put
some weird Stones here as well I'm going
to be make this a bit wonky so it
doesn't look so like perfect it's not
perfect but I'm going to do like
something like I'll put some stone
blocks here how we doing
739 so I'm just going to go e to extrude
it's actually better the the worse it
looks the better it is cuz it's like a
like they they like they just took stone
blocks back in the day didn't they so
and did what they could with it
so I think I'm going to do actually I'm
going to still have a little Arc maybe
gz and bring this okay and I think I'm
going to do this one now smooth
something like that I don't know doesn't
really matter too much uh so why am I
spending so much time on it then control
R Loop cut scale on the Y AIS okay no o
proportional off scale xaxis to here and
then I'm just going to go like control
select there shift select there control
select there e to extrude it a little
bit like this and then I'm going to do
F3 check D select that was already
selected cuz I use that one so much and
it actually selected the wrong ones I
wanted make sure this one's active and
then check your deselect okay I want to
make sure apparently this one's active
check your deselect there we go and then
now I'm going to select that that one's
active F3 check your D select and then
we'll do e to extrude these and I wonder
if I can flatten these uh comma or
period individual Origins scale z0 yeah
that's good so I've flattened all those
out a little bit that should do and uh
maybe just for some I don't know some
more I'm only going to be seeing one
side actually so I'm not going to spend
much time on the backside there at all
and let's get some more stone blocks
here we'll do Shifty to duplicate this
one I just got like a little nice Trio
here of blocks and then let's make
control shift B losing my voice for some
reason why is that happening control b
control no I'm actually doing control
shift B to Bevel up a Vertex that's how
you have to do that on control shift B
just get some control shift B not all of
them but a few of them like that
different sizes GG to slide the vers
here now on these sides here so they're
not like perfectly triangular something
like this maybe that'll do that's my
favorite word in the world that'll do so
there we go change that one a little bit
maybe move this one in and this one
we've got three blocks going there so
now I'm going to L to select the link
here and then make sure I'm in side view
and then I'm just going to like shift d
to duplicate these in a few placees
Shifty to duplicate it root okay I'm
going to take individual off so period
median Point rotate okay I'm in perfect
side view here so not going to be too
picky about these things rotate there
and then root shift d to duplicate I'll
make sure I keep that pattern a little
bit Shifty to duplicate and here we're
like a bit going a bit off the thing but
that's okay I think we're fine with that
I'm not going to put them everywhere so
Shifty to duplicate that on Shifty to
duplicate there and then now maybe I'll
just shift select a bunch of these and
see if we can just jumble them a little
bit more there must be better ways to
make this random drop the one random
down there g z o for proportional and
then maybe scale them no G to move it
and I don't know I'll just move a few of
them manually like this just to get a
little bit more irregular stuff G all
right so I think we'll oh I not going to
duplicate the ver duplicate that one G
all right so now I think I'm going to do
like a few bevels here as well I'll
select a few of these random control B
not shift B this time because we're
doing uh just bevel on the edges so it's
only vers that you do control shift B
it's control B for like these ones and
then maybe I can slide these in I've got
proportional on I don't
care and control I'll just jumble this
up how we doing 352 so time's going
pretty fast I've noticed 10 minutes is
not a long time
in case anyone's not noticed so rotate Z
okay rotate X there we go all right I
should probably jumble a few of these as
well I'll select a few of these and then
I'm actually going to do a few of the
backside as well cuz you might be able
to see a few of those so and a few of
these like randomly select control shift
B to Bevel these ah oh yeah W it's a big
impact there we go that's it so and I'm
also going to do something here I think
I've got to do some for form of stone
block to make it a little bit more
interesting here so e to extrude this
one L select the link scale on the y-
axis bring this in here and then we'll
do control shift B to like bevel these
and maybe we'll do should we bevel this
whole thing control control B to Bevel
that whole thing control yeah contrl R I
think I'm going to do actually control R
I can't really do these anymore okay so
we'll just keep it like that then
fine but I'll still like make it a
little bit more irregular like this
there we go and then I'll do Shifty to
duplicate this one and rotate it all the
way around to here and we'll do shift d
to duplicate it down here scale on the Y
AIS G to move it in and rotate it a
little bit so it's off Shifty we've got
2 minutes to go and here we'll do GG
slide that on GG slide that on and then
move that up to there and Shifty to
duplicate this one rotate a little bit
on the Zed the wonkier the better that's
what I say and GG slide this one this
can be very irregular like that grab
this one El select the link Shifty to
duplicate it bring it down scale Zed and
a flat one here and scale y That's fine
Shifty to duplicate that one rotate on
the x- axis and scale it scale Zed again
GG and now let's just mirror these I'm
lo my voice again for some reason shift
e to duplicate this one scale y minus
one and we'll do rotate and then
just jumble these a little bit El select
the link scale scale Y and El select the
link scale y make them a bit wider like
this and I think I need to put more like
blocks here as well we only got one
minute to go so I'll put some wood stuff
on here as well and we'll fix these in a
second so Shifty to duplicate that scale
it down and I'm I'm going to do like a
wood thing here I don't know should it
come out here yeah e l e to well e to
extrude G we'll move this into some dark
wood color there and let's just move
this one up to here I don't know these
found these might be a little bit too
big compared to the other bridge I'm
seeing now but never mind who cares
Shifty to duplicate it scale it on the Z
axis scale down move it in maybe to
there and e to extrude it and then
should we do shift e to duplicate it
scale it down scale on the x-axis press
X there scale it up a little bit again e
to extrude and move it into here and how
we doing 42 seconds so I'm just going to
put a few of these here so L select the
link three shift d to duplicate them
we'll do maybe every other should we do
that so there shift d to duplicate it
and Shifty hopefully um with it being
even yeah lucky me cuz the number of oh
didn't copy that one so l l 19 seconds
Shifty to duplicate it shift d to
duplicate it shift d to duplicate it
shift d to duplicate it alt G to no I
was just joking shift d to duplicate
that shift d to duplicate it scale it
down bring it down e to extrude and E to
extrude bring it up e to extrude bring
it up e to extrude e to extrude bring it
down um e to extrude and bring it
down there we
go so that's my bridge in 10 minutes
it's got got these I I think I'm going
to mirror these on the other side so we
can officially stop the clock here I
have no idea what this one will look
like in the game yet but it is a
different style from from that Wood
Bridge anyway so I'm going to save this
one for now contrl s and then we'll do
F2 we'll call this stone bridge and then
it wouldn't be a true infancia 10-minute
Ming challenge unless we just fix it up
a little bit it's a little bit rough
around the edges so let's see what we
can do and uh and tweak it what do we
need to address here I think uh I'm
going to do Shifty to duplicate it cuz
we have the original there and let's see
where where is my Stone Bridge I've got
a lot of aets here from the game there
we go so I'm going to hide that one and
let's just work a little bit on this one
so the first thing I'm going to do is
I'm going to I think we're a bit too
close to those so I don't want Zed
fighting here uh so I want to make sure
that the polygons are a little bit more
above than like you'd normally so
they're not fighting on the same vertex
space there so I'm going to do extrude
that one a little bit and maybe we'll
extrude this one a little bit to there
and then we'll do I think I'm also going
to do like I I don't like when
everything's perfect
perfect even though I'm a perfectionist
I don't like it control R I used to be a
perfectionist now I'm not anymore uh so
G because when everything's like super
aligned and super perfect it looks a bit
boring so I'm just control R doing
some stuff here and then scaling it
maybe control R here
this one scale it down G to move it and
I I used to do everything like in
perfect Symmetry and perfect shape
symmetry is still good though we're not
going to be bashing on symmetry so
regret that I regret that I said that
already no one beats no one messes
around with with the Symmetry is the
best thing ever but let's uh not go for
symmetry this time scale it down G to
move it and control R I just want it to
look a little bit like more natural
control r
uh G uh control r g there we go so
here's our little foundation and now I'm
going to do I have to do L to select the
link l l l l l l l l l l l l l l l l l l
i was actually proud I hit all of those
in nice succession so I'm going to do
shift d to duplicate this scale x minus
one and then alt n because I need to
recalculate outside you don't see that
but the normals were all inverted after
that little Flex move there there and
I'm going to just move into that there
and that's because the bridge is going
to be moved from here so I do need to
see like those parts there I'm also
going to darken this part of the bridge
I think a little bit compared to the
stones that I've extruded so that was
just like a little subtle down and I
think I'm going to do the same for these
two Foundation things move it maybe a
little bit even darker on those
something like that and also I should do
on all of these I'm going to do shift G
when I've selected one of these triangle
faces and I'm going to do select
everything that has the same number of
polygons sides so that selects all my
little Edge wear ones and I'm going
going to go a little bit brighter on
those not much just a little Tad you
don't really see it much here but I
think in the game uh if I remember
correctly it'll be a little bit more
noticeable I also think I want to make
it less regular here so contrl R going
to Loop cut this I don't care too much
that it's a lot of uh vers here cuz you
don't you only see one bridge at a time
and it's going to be cold uh as soon as
you go out it's not going to be cold
when you go out it's going to be cold
when you go out cu l l something Ed or
whatever my spelling is terrible I think
I'm half dyslectic to be honest because
I I really struggle to even spell my
name sometimes so I don't do it too
often yeah so g
y GX oh okay I need to do o for
proportional
GX and then we'll just we're on like
this jumbled thing so I'm just going to
move it into there I think that's fine
yeah that's good and here I think I'm
I'm also going to do like I'll shift
select a few of these just want it more
less
perfect G to move that something like
that we'll do maybe I'll do a few
extrusions here as well so or I'm not
going to extrude these I'm going to do
shift the to duplicate them move them up
scale them down slightly so they
disappear G and then Al the extra long
face normals in case I changed my mind
so and I'll do Control Plus move them in
and I don't care that there is some
geomet tree that's hidden inside now cuz
the overdraw on these the trees are a
lot worse I should be addressing those
if anything so I think something like
that it looks hideous actually to be
honest so credits to me for making stuff
look horrible rotate maybe if I put a
few more and stick them out a little bit
less or something I don't know Shifty to
duplicate G rotate
maybe I don't know I don't know this
reminds me of the dungeon we did like
maybe four episodes ago or something
like that it's a bit similar the style
there maybe I'll just move it a hide a
little bit more into
here G okay maybe something like that
and these are bothering me quite a lot
to be honest uh I think I need to do
some beveling in here just in case you
see these on the side as well so control
shift B here and we'll do the same
here and maybe like that control shift
b control shift B on that on oh too much
control shift B and something like that
and these are too perfect as well G to
move it g to move that g to move it up
and world I think i' if there was a
contest in Worlds itches nose I've won
it like every time I record I even had
to go to Ai and Google how come I get an
itchy nose and it said if you're nervous
it could itch but I'm not nervous so
what's going on what else could it be is
it cuz I'm concentrated
no maybe I am nervous without even
knowing about it probably not though so
El select the link I'm also going to
bring these up and Shrink them down G to
move it and we'll put a few more Stones
here maybe I'll just rotate this one the
one here the better or it's going to be
fun to see this in the game cuz I don't
really know what it's going to look like
to be
honest G and I don't know if that
Foundation was such a good idea I'm
actually going to do control B to Oh No
Control B to Bevel that on GG to slide
it I just want it to be like have some
nice weird angles for the for the low
poly light to reflect off to be honest
and these are going to be like there's
going to be more of these blocks coming
down here so you're not going to see
this too much and I'll probably just
slap a big old collider on it so it's uh
not going to be
so like you're not going to be able to
destroy the bridge anyway it doesn't
need to be destructible so scale it down
G and we'll grab this this one too L
select the link Shifty duplicate that
one scale it down move it in something
like this and then maybe this Edge
contrl B bubble on I I keep doing
control shift B because of the ver mode
control B
GG move this in we're still on
proportional so with the random that's
absolutely fine cuz I like it to like
still offset everything like that a
little bit control maybe I'll do contrl
B down here and GG to slide that on GG
and that's good I don't care about end
gon here either it's perfectly fine I'd
say so control shift B that one I want
to slice for some reason all right so
maybe something like that we can try
this in the game now and see what it
looks like maybe H I'm not so happy with
the fact that these are like this so
I'll move that on maybe I'll do G to
move it out to here
G okay maybe we'll just see what it
looks like first and I also think I'm
going to do like a fake ambient
occlusion here so I'm going to let's see
I'm going to select
these shift select them and then just go
darker on those as well that are
underneath there and the same thing I'm
going to do here I'm going to do here
and control selector here and then
control plus a few times
there and then here I'm also going to do
a like darker like that so it looks like
a bit of a shadow thing not not happy at
all about these blocks to be honest so
let's see if I even keep
those and then maybe I'll do a darker
one there does that make sense just for
some feature I think so don't know why
but and maybe I'll do e to extrude
that okay without that
one so we'll do tabing TI mode
proportional off and then I'll
do uh e to extrude in a little bit why
am I doing that Global Med point is
everything inverted alt n recalculate
outside and then I'll do oh it's because
I did the I probably select it all the
way around so e to e to extrude it in
there we go maybe I'll do something like
that don't know why but I have a feeling
I have a good feeling about it g to move
it down that's good that makes some sort
of a feature there as
well and contrl B on this one bevel
contrl B GG I have no idea how much
extra time I spent here now but please
forgive me control
B little Edge we there no that looks out
of place all right so now we're going to
bring this uh into the game and see what
it looks like and see what I need to fix
so it's called Stone Bridge that's fine
so contrl s mark it everything's one
object that's perfectly fine file export
fpx I'm going to do selected objects I'm
going to go fpx units scale and then
apply transform cuz we don't have uh an
Armature on this one don't need
animation and stuff so that's it and my
project name is still called Soul
Harvest before I picked the name of
unfair Rampage so we go into Unity Soul
Harvest assets meshes and we're going to
call it Stone Bridge 01 for some reason
fpx and Export and now let's go into the
game and it should already be in here so
if we do uh doooo let's see I'm going to
go open this one
up and go
to meshes we have that one here and
stone bridge this this going to be
interesting this might look absolutely
hideous I don't know Stone Bridge we
don't need to bring the material in cuz
we're using the same material for
everything everything else fine don't
have to do much about that so now let's
go into my prefabs folder here and we'll
go into level segment bridge is that
one level set
segment first why don't have a bridge
one here
end is this one double
click yeah this is the
one this uh is one this is one of the
segments that's what what they look like
so I'm going to duplicate this
one and then we'll call it P2 instead I
guess and
set in the world record again itchy
knows sorry if I'm disgusting anyone
tough luck Look Away children there we
go bring it in we've got the bridge here
somewhere so we got meshes Stone Bridge
I remember here we go drag it into like
here
somewhere and rotate it on the let's see
rotate hot keys from Unity is not
working here or from uh well from Unity
they're working cuz this is Unity so how
many degrees am I rotating this thing
now all right
so transform let's see need to go to 90
there we go and I need to slap the
colors on here now so let's go for my
infancia pix pile texture
materials pix pile urp Stonebridge let's
go mesh render lit let's replace replace
you with the infancia pix pile texture
and sorry Bridge you're going to go but
I'm first also going to put a collider
on you so I see what I've done here
going to do mesh collider and it can be
it doesn't have to be convex it can be
concave but we also have let's see this
is ground layer on this bridge
right there we go ground yeah so I'm
going to go on this one and select layer
ground where are you these are my layers
in the game ground layer W to move here
bit of a different key and we'll delete
you it's been nice knowing your bridge
and put you stone bridge in here as well
and we'll snap you into place there so
we' got a little bit of an issue because
the water there is uh flowing like
through the thing it's not
optimal so we'll have to figure out how
to solve
this so maybe I can just do let's scale
this thing and make it a little bit
wider not that wider so let's go this
one off
I should probably try to fix this
instead somehow but let's just put the
bridge higher then shall we why not
there and we can make a little staircase
here so these blocks I can just uh go
control D to
duplicate and now we need snapping back
on here so this is how I design my
levels in this game very simple I don't
use like a tile map editor or anything
like that so I'm going to be doing like
this instead and we'll do control D
duplicate that one to there contrl D to
duplicate and crl
d and there we go then we're going to go
contrl D to duplicate this one bring it
into there contrl d control D and contrl
D A little staircase coming up to
Here There we go so that looks a bit
stupid cuz I've got this tree here so
let's raise you
up I like to keep the purple Treese
there because it's uh like
it's uh reminds me that I've reached one
of I I mean I've got the purple trees in
other places as well we need to switch
this one to Global and bring that My
Little Foundation block up there
decorative there we go and then maybe
we'll also bring these decorations up as
well so we can see the grass up here so
we'll snap those up there a little bit
difficult to
see but I think we're all
good there we go bring it down to there
and I'm also going to create some more
decorate decorations I only have this
one grass prefab that I need to do and
see that these are swaying as well this
is a Shader that I made in Shader graph
so it just over time it adds Some Noise
uh I have it on the trees as well I
think it works really good on these
little I should cover that in a video
too I guess so contrl D to duplicate
that one into there and these are not
really that perfectly aligned either but
rotate maybe I'll do something like that
that looks stupid that they're coming
out this way I don't care I think it's
fine control to duplicate that one and
there we go we got a little stairs
coming up there I'll do the same on this
side cuz there's no point hiding these
little nice grass strands on the back
here so I'm going to control Z move them
up to here and what else did we have
this difficult to see here actually I
just realized again that you can do the
same hot Keys as you can in
uh uh Unreal Engine so if you right
click and do W ASD you can actually
navigate here so that's kind of cool
control D to
duplicate and these are not going to be
seen much cuz it's non-destructible here
but control D to duplicate that one and
I I don't really see what I'm doing
here to be honest but that's okay if you
if I don't see it like looking from
behind no one's going to see it from the
front either so I think we're good
something like that maybe
and I think I might add a little bit
more like detail to this um at some
point but I think we're going to give
this one a go now
so maybe we'll do
uh here now I need to just modify the
game a little bit to see here in the
level
prefab so we're going to go
to do you know what I can do actually I
can try it straight away so instead of
running all the way to a bridge now cuz
that would take some time I can go into
my prefab
if I find it again
so P comes uh before s true and we've
got level here somewhere this is my
giant like level thing this is the first
level and then it just spawns a whole
bunch of things I've got a little
setting in here where I can do test only
this segment so this is a little thing
that I did so it and I can search here
why don't I use that
level okay and I need to go to assets
here and then we'll
see P2 end this is the one we created so
now we'll only have this level segment
in the game here so we'll see how that
goes so it won't be any enemies now but
that's
fine play and we're going to be off now
wooo here we go oh jump
shoot and okay why did it not put my oh
I modified the wrong one
now I modified the the other one all
right never mind so I cop it and then I
modified the original but that's okay
that's not a problem I'll just fix
it here we go that's good it gives me a
chance to do the new spin kick on this
uh character instead then check this
out woo there we go oh there's our
bridge and I can run across it the rails
are a little bit big I look like a
little on there
[Music]
what and what happens if I shoot this
yeah oh but it works I mean I just need
to tidy it up a little
bit Why didn't it
um trigger it should have triggered like
a Slowdown should it
restart there we
go okay I have to put a collider here
somewhere or like a trigger thing
because it's meant to trigger here you
can also see that there is a bit of
offsets between the different level
segments this one's up here
and this one is offset down a little bit
so this is all the level segments that
adds a little bit variation to the game
as well that they're like that woo dash
dash dash dash I'm I'm going to win I'm
going to win check this out next thing
I'm going to do is probably some more
back backdrop stuff I need the castles
and stuff in the in the distant
background there so like looking at this
the few twink tweaks that I'll probably
do before I put them in the game I need
to do something so the railing isn't
blocking my face I need to make that a
little bit smaller probably and the
blocks at the bottom here I'm not happy
with that I need some more
irregularities there so I'll probably
tweak those blocks other than that I
think um yeah so it probably needs maybe
about uh 20 minutes more attention to it
before uh these as well here in the
center are a little bit too like square
and stuff so I think there's room to
improve the bridge a little bit more but
as a start thing for 10 minutes plus
whatever Tinker Time we did I think it
works pretty good all right thanks for
tuning in this week for episode 134 I
hope uh you enjoyed it and give it a
thumbs up if you like the video and
don't forget to subscribe if you haven't
already and check out uh unfair Rampage
Nightfall on Steam and wish list it if
you want to have this game I want you to
have this game it's only going to be
five bucks $5 it's like the price of a
coffee so uh do you do yourself a favor
for me no I'm only joking I'll cut that
part out no I won't have a great one
I'll see you soon bye for now
[Music]