hey everyone it's steve here from cg
geek and i'm back again for the msi
creator awards 2022 contest i'm a judge
for the 3d creation category the theme
is create your own utopia and you have
till the end of may may 30th to get your
submissions in is a ton of fun and you
can win some incredible prizes so you'll
definitely want to enter so today i'll
be teaching you how to create your own
utopia low poly world using blender and
cycles and for this project msi sent
over their rtx 3090 supreme x really the
coolest 3090 available on the market
right now it's got the triple fan cooler
so it keeps the 3090 temps really low
while being really quiet and also just
looking super cool with the rgb lighting
so that's the gpu i'm using and as you
can imagine it's incredibly fast in
blender 3.0 now with optics without
further ado pull up a chair sit back and
relax and let's have some fun creating
some low poly worlds so go ahead and
fire up the latest version of blender
and let's go ahead and start creating
our world so we'll start by just scaling
our cube up about three times by hitting
s and three and then i'm going to scale
it down along these z axis by hitting s
and z so we have a platform for our low
poly world here this is just the base
ground so we'll go ahead and give it a
material right off the bat why not this
will just be a nice brownish color and
start rendering right off the bat by
jumping to the rendered view here and
we'll switch that over from ev to cycles
and then change the device to gpu
compute so i'm using that rtx 3090 for
all the rendering here also i'll go
ahead and open up my hdr lighting right
away for the scene so everything looks
nice and pretty in real time as we're
rendering it so i'm just opening up an
hdr here from poly haven i'm going to
take the strength down this a bit just
to a 0.5 and then i'm going to jump to
the render settings here and if you go
down to film you can check transparent
so you don't see that in the background
but it's adding some lighting to the
scene making it look prettier all right
so now with a nice sort of brownish
color here for our ground maybe make it
a little bit darker as well
we can go ahead and start working on the
ground so i'm going to tap into edit
mode i'm going to grab a vertice here
and then hit l on my keyboard to select
the whole cube i'll hit shift d and pull
it up along the z axis now i'm going to
scale it along the shift z by hitting
shift and z to make it wider but not
taller and then we'll scale it down
along this head a little bit as well as
well because it's a little tall there
that's looking pretty good now i'm going
to go ahead and go ctrl r to add in an
edge loop on both sides here and then
i'll grab the rest of the mesh here
right click and subdivide it perfect now
i'll hit l to select that top mesh and
i'll hit ctrl t on my keyboard to
triangulate the mesh this is gonna help
make it look nice and low poly now if i
hit o to enable proportional editing
here you can see that if i choose
connected only i can grab some of these
vertices and start pulling up sections
of the mesh here to make it look like we
have some sort of hills and valleys
going along on our mesh here just give
it a little bit of an organic sort of
look to make it look like up and down
giving us some of that variation so you
see some of those faces
sticking up
nicely not bad at all and on the ground
here i'm going to turn the roughness all
the way up to 1 so it's not shiny
perfect now we can make a new material
this one will be a nice green color
something along the lines of this
here and then if you tab in edit mode
hit l to select just the top mesh there
and assign it because we have our new
color
in the scene again we're going to take
the roughness down on the grass so just
give that a one play around the color a
little bit to get the right color that
you kind of go on for the scene maybe a
little darker
alright now we want to cut a river
through the center of this
and this actually isn't too hard to do
what i'm going to do is i'm going to
jump to top view i'm going to go shift a
and add in a cube this is going to be
the size of the river that we want to
cut through here so i'm going to hit g
pull it up along the z axis there and
i'll hit s and x to scale it along the
x-axis
and this is going to basically be where
the river is cut out of my scene so i
can tab in edit mode put a few cuts in
this cube
and then grab those verses and just give
them a little bit of side to side
movement so the creek here or the stream
or whatever you want to call it isn't
perfectly straight make it look a little
bit more organic and then we'll grab our
ground mesh here jump to the modifier
settings and go ahead and add in a
boolean modifier
we're gonna grab the object of that cube
as long as it's set to difference and
fast you can see that if i hide this
cube now we have a nice river cut out of
our creek and that looks really good you
can grab your cube object here and kind
of play around with it to choose where
you want that to be exactly how deep you
want the creek to be etc but it's really
easy to mess around with
and once you have something that you
think looks pretty good i'm just hiding
the mesh there i'll go ahead and click
the drop down there and click apply for
that boolean modifier now you might want
to hit three in the keyboard to switch
to face select and grab all those faces
in the middle and just make sure that
those are all assigned to the green
material as well i just thought that
looked a little bit better and we'll go
ahead and add in our creak now running
across the center of our scene so for
this it's just going to be a plane
scale it down a little bit
grab it along the z-axis and we'll scale
it along the x-axis
something like that looks pretty good
then i'll tab into edit mode grab the
two vertices on the end here and i'll
just extrude extrude them down along the
z axis something like so now we're going
to want to put a cut down the middle
cut there and then a few cuts in the
center by using our scroll wheel and
going ctrl r and clicking
and this just gives us some more
variation to make this look a little bit
more low poly a quick technique for
doing this is using proportional editing
but changing it to random and now if i
go g along the z and just kind of scroll
my wheel real big you can see we kind of
get a low poly wave effect going through
that creek i'm also going to go ahead
now and add in a solidify modifier on
our creek there we'll crank the
thickness up a little bit something like
so next up we can add a material to our
creek so i'm just going to go ahead to
our materials tab go new material then
i'm gonna go ahead and split our window
so we can bring up a shader editor to
work on this material a little bit more
switching this window to the shader
editor hitting end to close off the
properties tab i'm giving it just a
little bit of a blue color here and then
i'm going to pull this principle shader
out of the way a little bit i'll give it
more specular by cranking that all the
way up so it's nice and shiny a little
bit of sheen can kind of help as well by
adding some value there but then i'm
going to go shift it and add in a shader
mix shader where we have it right there
shader
right there then i'll go shift a and add
in a glass shader go ahead and plug this
into the bottom socket and you can see
that this just gives it a little bit
more of that shiny reflectiveness that
is looking pretty cool i'll go ahead and
duplicate that mix shader
and then go shift a and add in a new
shader glossy as well we'll change this
to sharp i'll go ahead and plug that
into the bottom socket and this you want
to go a less of a mix factor here but
putting a little bit of that in there
makes it look nice and kind of like
water as well not too bad maybe make the
color of the water here a little bit
more blue
that's looking good let's grab the lamp
that is sitting in the blender scene
here and change it to a sun lamp we'll
take the value down to a three actually
and give it a little bit of a warmer
color but this will just be adding some
more shadows to our scene and as you can
see that looks
pretty nice when we kind of have it to
the side there then i'm going to grab
our water and go ctrl t just like i did
before and add in a little bit of
variation then to that
and that just gives it more of that low
poly look that i was talking about and
that's looking pretty good you can go
ahead and play around with some of these
vertices to give your ground a little
bit of variation okay so next up let's
go ahead and add some low poly trees to
the scene so i'll start off with some
pine trees over on the side here and
these are super easy i'm just going to
shift right click to put my cursor over
there shift a add in a cube we'll scale
the cube way down i'll hit period on my
number pad to zoom in on that cube tab
in edit mode and then hit 3 to make sure
i'm using face select so i can just grab
the top face there i'm going to hit e to
extrude and scale it up a bit something
like that and then i'll hit e to extrude
again
pull it up nice and high and scale it
down to a very small point there then
i'll hit g and pull it up a little bit
higher there and as you can see that
right there is a pine tree in itself and
we can definitely go ahead and just ctrl
r put a cut in the middle hit g to kind
of move that to give it a little bit of
personality ctrl t to make it um
triangular and we'll add a little bit of
variation to that now using the
proportional editing with the randomized
node there and i'm just going to give it
a new material this material will be
sort of a nice
shade of green a little bit off color to
the ground though give it another
material this will be just sort of a
brown color for the uh for the bark on
the trunk of that tree so you can tab in
edit mode here
hit three to go to face select and
actually if you check the x-ray button
here we can see the faces on the other
side let's grab all those faces and
assign the bark to those so there's a
cute little tree if i ever did c1 now we
can go ahead and make some variations of
this pine tree so i'm just going to
rotate that pine tree so now let's make
another variation of our pine tree here
for this i'm just going to go ahead and
add in another cube very similar to
before scale it down nice and small for
the trunk tab in edit mode grab that top
face extrude scale it
and then extrude up and scale it to a
point again
now what i'm going to do is i'm going to
go ctrl r
i will go down about here and i'm going
to scale it in a bit then i'm going to
ctrl r and we'll pull this edge loop
down i'm going to scale this one up a
bit and as you can see right away this
is super easy to add that kind of pine
tree look to the scene control r again
and i'll actually grab the first one
there scale that down and we have sort
of a cute looking pine tree not bad at
all we can go ahead and slap on our own
sort of pine color for this one this
should be like a little bit more of a
bluish
bluish color pine tree i think that
looks kind of nice and then a bark
material for the trunk there we'll go
ahead and put plus so we can just grab
the same same brown material we already
created there and assign that
to that so now on top view you go ahead
and duplicate this pine tree rotating it
around and adding in you know just a few
variations of it
maybe make this one scaled down a little
bit but then shift s along with zed to
make it sort of short and fat
this one could be a little bit taller
just kind of forming our low poly utopia
now i think it's time we place our
camera so i'm going to grab our camera
and i'm going to jump to side view here
where i think a good angle is i'm going
to go alt control 0 to snap it to that
view just go ahead and place it there by
hitting g and moving over and i think it
looks best for a low poly scene like
this to have a very zoomed in view so
i'm gonna actually change our focal
length here under the camera settings to
200 millimeters and then i'm just gonna
have to hit g and pull out using the
middle mouse button to zoom that out a
bit so we have everything in the scene
as we can see there perfect
now you might be able to scale up some
of your pine trees if things are looking
a little bit small in scale for your
liking and that's looking pretty cute i
think on to the next part of our low
poly world here i'm going to go over to
the side here and we'll add in some
rocks these are going to be super easy
i'm just going to add in an icosphere
and make it one subdivision so nice and
small here scale it down a bit and
making sure proportional editing is
still enabled there i'm just going to go
ahead and pull up a shape here i'll grab
some of the faces along the bottom and
i'll scale those up
and as you can see it's really easy to
just quickly get some weird looking rock
shapes and i can shift d duplicate that
rotate along the z-axis here
scale it down and then using
proportional editing easily change the
shape of that
real quick for the material on these
it's just going to be a little bit of a
darker slightly blue color
i'm going to go shift a and add in
another aquasphere
scale this one down and just scale this
one up along the z there
for a little bit of variation
pull some of these faces out along the
bottom a bit
pull some of these down from the top and
there we just have a cool sort of little
bit of rock rocky formation and then we
can go ahead and add some cute little
pine trees around it by grabbing the
pine tree here and shifting it
kind of filling out our nature scene if
you uh
if you like
and any of these you can go ahead and
add a little bit of variation to maybe
grab this little pine tree and we'll
stick him over in this corner here with
a little bit of a different rotation
a little bit of an angle there maybe
scale
a little bit more narrow i think i'll go
ahead and add one more pine tree by
duplicating this one over here maybe
this will be a little bit bigger and
maybe we'll give it a different color so
we have a little bit of variation you
can just click the five button there to
make it a separate material and then you
can go ahead and tweak that material to
be a little bit different
this one will be kind of overhanging the
overhang in the creek here a little bit
that might look kind of cute
all right now we'll create one another
variation of trees for this side of the
scene here for this i'm just going to go
ahead and add in an icosphere
icosphere
this one will change to two subdivisions
pull it up scale it down
and we'll give this a random color
something like one of the trees that we
already have there and for these i'm
just going to grab it and shift d it
duplicate it and scale it for a
different size we'll give this one a new
material something like that
tap into edit mode and assign that new
material to it and now you can just kind
of duplicate these icon spheres around
to kind of make this little poly looking
sort of
tree sort of thing-ish
you can get creative with this make it
look uh kind of abstract
but they also kind of have their own
unique low-poly flare to them
kind of pull it up a little bit like
that and if you tap into edit mode you
can also do a little bit with
proportional editing to make them look a
little less perfectly round so just
giving them a little bit of that random
proportional editing shape adds a little
bit of that organic sort of unique look
to them which is kind of cool just
moving a verse face around a little bit
with proportional editing enabled there
all right i think i like the look of
that so i'll scale
all those down a little bit
place them over here and then you can
hit ctrl j to make them all one object
now we need a quick quick and dirty
trunk so what i'm going to do for this
is with face select enabled here i'm
just going to grab a few faces along the
bottom of these
there we go and i'll extrude
and scale them down but i want to turn
off the porcelain for this yeah scale
them down something like that
all to a central point where then i'll
just duplicate one of these faces by
hitting shift d
rotate it and scale this one up a little
bit
place it right in the middle there and
extrude this down
for the trunk of the tree now if i just
hit l i can select that
add in new material we'll give this one
the bark material there and assign it to
it i can also grab these little faces
here hit ctrl plus with the number pad
to increase that selection and assign
those as branches as well but now you
can see that's kind of a cute little
chunky
chunky little poly tree there
that will work uh just fine for our
scene here
i want to scale it down along with y a
little bit
that's rather cute though and you can go
ahead and duplicate this tree as well
for another one back here maybe a little
smaller
cool now a few final details because
those always look really cool in these
low poly scenes we'll just be adding in
a little ecosphere here and there that
is a dark green bush i'm just going to
give this material of our dark green
here maybe hit that button to make it
even darker green and scale it down for
a little chunky bush now if you tab in
edit mode again with proportional
editing enabled we can make this look a
little bit different
and then hit period to jump to that bush
right there and i'll just duplicate it
rotate it around scale it duplicate
again just kind of adding in some of
these cute little bushes
around the scene
i thought it added quite a bit
to the
to the character of the scene you know
making it look a little bit more filled
out
and super easy to add these details in
really fast
something like that just adds a good
amount to the scene
and you can add some of these bushes as
well
over to your trees here
a few little bushes around the base of
these trees can kind of go a long way to
add to the scene also a few cute little
rocks maybe in the creek here looks nice
so i'm going to go shift a add an
icosphere take this one down to just a
value of one scale it down tab to edit
mode give it a little bit of variation
scale it down a little bit more
and then just duplicate this around a
little bit
just rotating it scaling it
that looks pretty good we'll duplicate
both those pull them over here
grab them up along the zed because we're
stuck in the middle of the mesh here
jump in the top you might make this
easier there we go
scale them down just kind of stink them
in the water there a little bit
now i should mention that this scene is
sort of based off some artwork by an
artist that goes from the name of i
think it's pavel and he's got all kinds
of different low poly worlds that he
creates so if you guys need some
inspiration you can check out some of
his work if you want some more
inspiration it's always fun to see other
people's takes on it too so if you
create something cool post it on
instagram and tag cg geeks so i can see
what you created because i love seeing
the awesome stuff that you guys come up
with so the last bit was a little
campfire now on this side of the scene
just to kind of fill it out so what i
started off doing is going shift a
adding in a circle we'll take this down
to just like eight faces
i'll tab in edit mode and i'll extrude
it pull it up a little bit scale it down
again we're using the randomizing here
to give it some nice variation
then i'll extrude one more time and
scale it in
real nice and tight scale it all the way
down to zero
okay now we can kind of pull some of
these faces up and this is just sort of
the platform in the ground where our
campfire is going to be located for this
we'll give it its own material sort of a
sandy like material here looks kind of
good
something along those lines then we just
need some bricks for around the
fireplace now you may have noticed that
i actually kind of incorporated the msi
creator awards logo in this by doing the
twisting bricks in a variation of color
that fits the logo of the awards this
year which was just kind of a way to
incorporate the logo in a sneaky way
into my finished scene but for the
tutorial i'll just show you the basic
process for the way i did this i'm gonna
go shift a add in a plane scale it down
grab it along the zed so we can pull it
out of the mesh there a little bit tab
in edit mode and i'm just going to make
sort of a triangular shaped brick here a
little bit of variation to it and
extrude it up so we have a rock again
using proportional editing now we can
give it a little bit of variation
and give this its own material this will
just be a slightly bluish grayish rock
nothing too crazy
and i will rotate it
tap out edit mode i'll rotate it scale
it down so we have sort of cool looking
rock and then just place it down at
ground level there
right around there looks good
now for a fireplace what i can do is i
can just place my cursor where i want
the fire to be and then hit period on my
number pad and choose 3d cursor so now
when i rotate it's going to rotate
around the 3d cursor here so i can just
go shift d rotate
add a new brick there shift d rotate and
actually if you hit shift r now it will
just repeat that last step and rotate
those blocks all the way around now that
gives you a good layout to start working
with i do recommend at this point that
you grab them all
unselect everything else hit ctrl j so
they're all one object and then use
proportional editing just to kind of add
some variation to these rocks
you don't want something looking
too
similar because low poly is supposed to
be imperfect
and that's what kind of gives it that
charm and maybe make one variation of
the rock color here for something a
little bit different this can be a
little bit of a
off-colored rock and you can grab some
of this by just hovering over with your
cursor and hitting l and assign this
color to those that looks kind of nice
and from camera view you can see
we have some blocks showing up doesn't
look too bad
we just need to kind of place these
around so it does look a little better
from the camera view here now lastly we
can go ahead and add a little bit of a
flame actually to this um
fire fire pit here for this i'm going to
go shift a add in a plane
rotate it so it's kind of facing the
camera there scale it down
then i'm going to tab into edit mode and
give it a few loop cuts there and a few
loop cuts there then i'm going to grab
the vertices in the corner here turn off
proportional editing and just pull out
random flame shape
kind of pull these vertices around
giving ourselves sort of a random
looking bit of fire
it's really actually not that hard to
just kind of
pull these vertices around getting
something that kind of looks like
a cartoon
cartoon amount of fire kind of popping
out of the
ground here that looks actually just
fine you scale it down
and pull some of these out even brighter
and the material for this i'm just going
to hit new is actually going to be not a
principle but an emission shader then
you can go ahead and give this a nice
orangey color
something like that
crank the strength up a little bit
higher
and there you have your flame
that looks pretty cute for last little
bit of color you can go down now to your
color management and give it a higher
contrast look by giving it a medium high
contrast there maybe increase the
exposure just a little bit on the scene
if you think it's a little dark take the
brightness down a little bit on that
water
maybe make it just a little bit of a
deeper blue color water there and there
is your low poly world created in
blender i can't wait to see what you
guys might create with this tutorial or
it might be creating for the msi creator
awards 2020 too but that's going to do
it for me guys thanks so much for
watching if you have a question leave it
as a comment in the comment section
below if you like the video hit that
thumbs up button have fun creating your
own low poly utopia and i'll see you
guys in the next one peace