hello everyone and welcome to episode
136 of the 10-minute modeling challenge
this week we're going to be switching
from one game to another I'm going to go
from unfair Rampage we were doing a
windmill there last week and I'm going
to switch over to the RTS game line war
and create a new building there because
we're needing we we need we need an
academy there a lot of stuff has been
happening to the game not only did
single player come woo everyone can play
it now even the people without friends I
nearly said shouldn't say that but
people that can't find someone to play
against on internet they can actually
play against an AI now that's pretty
cool so uh we need um now we're working
on Technologies and we're be adding a
lot of the stuff for example let's have
a look at the screen here because uh if
I unpa this what I've been working on
today and yesterday is camouflage stuff
so we have something called Pioneer
units now or Pioneer troops Pioneer core
and if I spawn a few of them here I'm in
like a sandbox mode we can make it a
little bit bigger and we let's make sure
actually we'll go over here where
there's a bit of uh desert there's some
mountains some forest and some grass and
check out if I spawn a few units here
see that they've got like an orange
backpack on and that's because these are
the Pioneer core and they can entrench
faster and they can camouflage their uh
their little hideouts or their
entrenchments so they dig a lot faster
they create these entrenchments and when
they're done UPS slides a little
camouflage net and whether this will be
the final mesh version that's going to
be ending up in the game not sure yet
because I'm still working on these
things but there's here's the latest
installment of them and you can see as
well that it Shi shifts over to desert
camo here where there's desert and then
there's a mountain camo and then some
Plains and in the forest they'll have
that as well and it's a bit of a
challenge because you need to be able to
make sure that you can see the units
good enough so I've had to if I go into
like this little scene view here you can
see I've had to make a little hole in
the top and there's like a little mesh
and it sways quite a bit and that's on
intention at the as well because then
actually it reveals the unit below it a
little bit and it's only the foot
soldiers here that can dig these but if
I spawn like um let's see a couple of uh
artillery pieces here then they can
actually go into and let's say switch
off the entrenchments for these so the
uh once the Pioneer core here has been
digging some uh some secure and high
hidden entrenchments then other units
can go to those and it's a bit ironic
now that they actually decided to go to
slots where there wasn't any
entrenchments but if I spawn a few more
uh like here you can see that they'll be
able to and a tank why not as well H
they'll be able to dig dig down and they
don't need to dig down because they have
already being created the Pioneer core
here has already created these but
they'll how hide out here so with these
little dig outs that are entrenched and
hidden away with some camouflage it'll
be a lot more difficult for the enemy to
detect those so you'll do a landfall
somewhere and you go woo this looks nice
and empty but it's not it's full of
people there so let's switch over to
today's topic and I'm I'm going to be
creating an academy building so it needs
to be a little bit high-tech looking but
not too high-tech it's going to be low
poly and it has to fit the Aesthetics of
line War as well so it's going to be
very similar and uh I'm going to be
probably I've got um a scene here where
I've got all my buildings and I've
enabled uh here's the factory in the
game and here's the town and I also have
the here's actually I'm working on some
camouflage for the barracks here and uh
the so I'm going to be creating one new
building here today and with War we're
actually using we're not using the
infancia Pix pile palette because um
this game was starting to be designed
way before I created that more advanced
pix pile palette so I'm using a very
basic one here with just the basic
colors which is pretty good as well
because then I stick to a specific color
pattern for everything in the game and
uh the only thing that actually shifts a
little bit is these two colors here
they're uh these two blue colors here
they'll actually be redesigned for up to
eight different units they'll be like
red teal purple black it just rotates
with different colors so the only colors
I've got to play around with are these
at the moment and then I have to accent
it with these two colors so uh that will
shift in the game so when you come to
the building and it's a red building
then uh these two colors will be shifted
so that's why actually I think I've got
uh some sample materials here we can
probably
look all of them are copies of that one
okay never mind I didn't have any red
one never mind so let's get started I'm
going to put 10 minutes on the clock and
then I'm going to be be trying to create
uh this Academy building for line war
and again this will probably be a
prototype I'll probably have to do a lot
of testing and it's going to be a
modular building but at least I'll be
able to get a prototype together that's
the purpose of today's video tomorrow as
well I'm going to be driving up to uh a
college in uh on the Sunshine Coast
that's going to be a lot of fun cuz uh
I've got eight new students there that
are going to be learning some blender
skills so I'm going to be showing them
probably low poly character uh modeling
like I did last year so that's going to
be a lot of fun going to be head up
there and uh actually in fact if you're
watching the premiere now right when
this Premiere is done I'm going to jump
in the car and drive up there and give
him a bit of a a a lesson I'm going to
teach him a lesson sounds weird I not
going to tell them off but I'm not all
right let's put uh some time on the
clock here ready steady go and off yep
it's counting down so T ined mode select
this shave sh face hold the control key
snap it down to there shift e to
duplicate it scale it down let's make a
ilar style here I can probably keep it
to that style e to extrude and then
shift e to duplicate move it over here e
to extrude I'm going to do some
different floors so I'll probably do
like this and then Shifty to duplicate
that on scale it down move it here just
needs to be looking a little bit nice
like something and then Shifty to
duplicate and I think one here as well
there we go so that's the going to be
the foundation here I want to do it
inser and scale it down a bit more e to
extrude and let's create some staircase
here so shift e to duplicate this one
scale on the x-axis move it into here
and I don't know I need to find a better
way to do stairs but what I tend to do
is um like this I'll uh control R Loop
cut that on maybe to there and then here
is the unfortunately the fastest way
actually I'll hide that face shift
select oh oh it's no no no l select the
link e to extrude and there we go
and I need to find how much I'm actually
extruding e to extrude 0.1 no that's too
much
0.05 e to extrude 0.05 that's it and
then here we go e to extrude
0.05 shift select that one e
0.05 and shift select that on E 0.05 and
that's going to be enough actually I
don't need all of these other ones so I
just do alt select on that on delete
faces
and we'll cap this as well alt select
there F
to L select the link and move it into
there and then move it down so I just
needed some U stairs there and should
that be a little bit higher yeah I'll
actually do El select the link scale on
the Zed AIS bring it up to here and ALT
H I need to un unhide that face again
and then actually I'm going to scale
them I want them a little bit longer
instead then how about this that should
should do and uh here as well I'm going
to do these like multistory I think uh
so I can combine different modules I
think that should be good uh so what
I'll do here is I'll do I to inser and E
to extrude and then we'll do control R
and then create some windows here
control R here as
well and it inset and I'll do it twice
so I get individual e to extrude that on
and that should be all right we'll do
the like dark Windows there as well so I
need to put the accents on as well so
we'll be able to differentiate these
building and usually I do that on the
corners and stuff so I'm going to do
shift d to duplicate that on scale it
down bring it in there and then scale it
down again and bringing that down to
there and then let's just put the accent
here so e to extrude hold the control
key okay I need to actually switch this
one to vertex so I can hold the control
key slide it up on the blue axis hold
the control key snap it to there I'll
select the link and now we'll pick the
blue color there so we can I don't mind
that it's Z fighting there cuz I'm going
to be uh fixing those a little bit later
on and overlapping them so and here also
another thing that I like to do on these
buildings is uh just create a beveled
edge here think either once or twice
like that and then we'll do all El
select the link
and I think uh yeah Shifty to duplicate
that on and we'll put the same sort of
pillar here as well and move that one to
here bring it up to here and grab the
bottom one there there and pull it down
oh need to pull the whole face down
there you
go and El select the L and then I think
I'm going to be doing just Shifty to
duplicate that one and put one there as
well I should do so and uh here should
we do another platform I think so I'll
do e to extrude this one move it into
here and we need to do the multi story
now so maybe I'll do blue in here as
well
and here e to extrude I just need
accents because you be able you have to
be able to see who who this building
belongs to uh actually I'm going to be
duplicating this instead of shift e to
duplicate it scale on the Y AIS e to
extrude and then select these two edges
contrl B to Bevel them El select the
linked and grab that on
there and then now I'm going to do
another floor here so Shifty to
duplicate that on and maybe rotate Zed
90 okay I need to not be an individual
period medium Point rotate Zed at
90°
and that looks a bit uh funky but okay
let move it into there and slide it into
here as
well I think I'm going to scale this one
up a little bit it's going to be a
bigger floor here for some reason so
there we go and we need to do some how
am I doing 451 okay so it doesn't make
much sense yet but trust me it won't in
the end either probably I need to
probably have something more here as
well so I'll e to extrude this one and I
have to check make sure that I don't
have back faces as well later on so this
is going to be our Academy I I guess we
should put some so like solar panels on
and I think I want to make it okay it's
quite a bit taller than that one now
that's fine I don't think I'll be able
to do it modular enough to to have um uh
all different things for all the
different Tech I actually had the idea
first that it'd be kind of cool to do
that so every different Tech would have
its own floor in the building so you
could see but I'll probably have to
differentiate that in a different way so
I'll do control R here as well e to
extrude this one and uh here could be
another entrance maybe a different type
of or a ramp maybe on this one control R
it to
inset and move it up e to extrude it and
then here
shift e to duplicate this one scale I
don't really mind about overlapping
geometry either scale y e to extrude El
select the link down and it's just about
creating interesting shapes so there's
like a a ramp of some sort that's fine
and more accents I think so Shifty to
duplicate we'll put accents
here uh rotate Z 180 oh rotate Z 180 and
then move it it down and it's important
as well that the building goes down in
the ground because sometimes you build
it on a slope so this needs to actually
keep going down like a foundation like
that that's pretty good and uh here I
think I'm going to put uh I'm not going
to put another floor on it but I'll do I
to inser twice so I don't get individual
e to extrude this one down and then I'm
going to put like some sort of a solar
panels up here so scale scale Z zero
that's fine e to extrude and shift e to
duplicate
and here let's just bring these up these
are going to be some solar array type of
panels so let's make them black looks
high-tech and then we'll do e to extrude
that on and then we'll just put some
Foundation here shift e to duplicate
scale it down e to extrude so it goes
into there bring this one up to here as
well control r a few times make it a
little bit high-tech looking don't know
why this would make it high tech looking
but actually I'm going to control r a
little bit more control R how many five
six oh okay not 56 control R 6 how about
that and then it to
inser okay that didn't work either I
insert why is it oh I have to hold the
control key or something shift alt ah
okay period have I got different is my
scale off here or
something scale's fine no okay I'm not
sure why it's uh I set it's really wonky
finding those there okay I'll just do a
little bit and ALT the
scale okay never mind got of a funky
look no I'm not not going to have that
so let's just contrl Z out of
day and scale to select okay we'll do it
like that instead then and then we'll do
shift e to duplicate that on move it in
E to extrude scale it down and bring
that down that makes sense or something
l l l and
scale that one up a little bit and then
shift e to duplicate on the x-axis to
there and then shift R that's our little
academy thing going there and here I
think I want to create the platform as
well I only have one minute to go so
Shifty to duplicate that we're going to
test in in the game as well to see what
it looks like what needs changing think
I want to do e to extrude and I think
I'm going to put some pillars here make
a little bit more interesting looking e
to
extrude and El select the link move it
to there shift e duplicate on the X or
on the Y AIS maybe to
there
and this platform I want it to be
connected to here and this one looks a
bit empty so I'm actually going to
double this one move it in a little bit
Shifty duplicate that one scale Zed and
move that
in and then here we'll do let's see what
do I have on the other other buildings
I've got some Slants and chimneys and
stuff this one's not going to have Chim
e to
extrude and let's just accent this whole
thing we need more accents here and
shift select these darker in here I
usually do that like an ambient
occlusion thing fake one yeah there here
as well alt select on the edge darker
and then slant this one and 's
up okay so pretty plain looking and
just playing around a little bit with
shapes to see what it looks like so I'm
going to do Academy let's name it and
let's export it into the game just to
see what it looks like I'm going to go
file export fpx and selected objects
we'll do apply transform for this one
apply scalings unit scale go to the mesh
folder and then just call it Academy
then I also need to make fractured
version of these and when they're
broken that should be fine and what I'm
going to do is I'm going to put this
building I think
on a different object so cuz oh no we
actually have the academy so let's uh
let's try
that so in the game here
Academy I can type here we go cuz uh
bantos has already created a placeholder
for this which is kind of great uh so
instead of the town here I'm going to
switch this town building
to and we should already have this
Academy in here now yeah cuz I exported
it into the folder structure let's look
in here and we're going to going to take
away this giant cylinder here cuz this
was a bantos Academy hint can take this
one away now cuz he had to differentiate
that building just so we're going to try
that and now let's go in the game and
have a look at it it's already ready to
go but it's called town here but that's
okay and let us
play and it needs to be built close to a
town or a city so here's a town
spot take we'll take these
territories and build a town and then we
can build the
academy wrong there but that's fine okay
so we see a few issues here straight
away we have the Zed fighting cuz I've
got the platform right on the base here
so I'm probably going to take that
platform
away uh and also it's two planes to gray
so I need to add a few things maybe
we'll zoom in a little bit and we can
update this on the fight I'll just pause
the game now and move it in here and I
think what I'm going to do is I'm going
to El select the link or eight select
everything I'm going to move it down a
little bit so it's under the
ground instead and I'm going to keep the
foundation cuz if we're building in the
mountains it's important to be able to
have like a foundation for the building
so let's keep but I'll lower this down
slightly as well
but we can't have these things flying in
the
air let's move this one down to here I
think this will be it's just so we don't
have anything running exactly on the
same plane as the ground that's the
important thing and then another thing
we noticed was that it was too two
static looking so I'm going to alt
select on this Edge I to inser alt s to
scale and let's scale that one down and
create
okay that's fine I had something go in
there but let's just change this one to
scale
zero and then go black there as well see
okay we've got some broken stuff here
all right that's why so I just need to
do here then instead I'll go here and
click control to their I to inser alt e
to extrude long face normals hold the
ALT key so we can actually get the right
proportions it's a little bit difficult
to see but sometimes it doesn't
uniformly insert insert them move this
one
in and this one in here as well and then
select these and go pretty black there
as well and then move this one down move
this one
up okay what else this looks way too
plain so we need to create contrl R
to more interesting looking shapes maybe
we'll do like this it inser
and ald to extrude along face
normals these could be some research
like they need skylights or something
here so it to inset Al to EXT long face
normals it to inset alt e to extrude
long face normals these are all
different sizes now that's not so good
so let's do that shift e to duplicate it
e to extrude it let's do it once it to
ins set e to extrude hold the ALT key so
that make any difference
no and I'll select the link let's get
rid of those faces and
then let's select those color those in
the player color control R okay what do
we need to do El select the
link shift e to duplicate on the y- axis
and then to here we'll leave a gap in
between as well shift R like that that
looks already a lot more interesting and
maybe we can create a bay on this one
just this one in particular
I to inset e to extrude and then maybe
offset this one like this and then do I
to inset and then create like a hole
down Control Plus go dark
there and some pipes would never be
wrong I think this one is sticking up a
little bit too much so let's go and I
don't really like those foundations
they're a little bit offset so L select
the linked maybe we'll make it a little
bit more just to the side there I'll
select the link
El select link let's delete that one
faces control R and scale shift Zed
because we only want to scale them on
that axis El select the link maybe a
darker gray and and let's look on the
side view there control 3 shift d and
then Y and there we go two more
interesting pillars and also these look
two PL so I'm going to do move it down a
little bit e to extrude S to scale it
just to Bevel that edge a little bit
instead I to inser and then e to extrude
again and here this is also looking very
un beveled so contrl B on this one
instead scroll wheel
there and okay that's all right and make
the ceiling darker or the
roof that was also more interesting here
maybe we need a big pipe so shift e to
duplicate move it scale it down right
click subdivide
edit and go Circle it's my shortcut to
create pipes I know it's stupid should
have created a cylinder or something X
and limited this all it's just faster to
do that way cuz I've done it so many
times and then we'll do I need to see
from the side we have to hide this one
now hide and hide oh not that one
hide and then I like the bend the pipes
here it makes it look a little bit more
interesting e to extrude R to okay so
here's a good way to to do with pipes
actually um press one go into vertex s
shft shift select that vertex shift s
cursor to selected and then here I'm
going to be moving uh just um this uh
this is actually a shortcut I do to move
the it's just faster to move the 3D
cursor this way e to extrude snap it
with the middle Mouse button to here
select this vert shift s cursor to
selected and then delete that vert
that's the fastest way I've found to
move the 3D cursor to a specific place I
know you can go in here and like
manually drag the 3D location but when
you're in the flow that seems to be
working pretty good so and then I'm
going to use this one Spin and change it
to the x-axis and then hold the control
key so we snap it up to there 90° but we
only need that's too many so I'm going
to do like maybe just eight of them
that's
enough yeah I think so and then click
here and then I'm going to shade these
smooth so right click shade smooth on
that pipe El select the link e to ex
through this one
first I'll select the link shift space g
and I don't know in a Academy building
why they need because it's not like an
industry industry building so I don't
really know why they need the these but
I do think it'll look a little bit more
interesting if there are some pipes here
Shifty to and then repetition is always
good so let's put three there and then
make them
like a much darker color there as well
it's just they to research they need uh
this I guess and then why not this could
just go through that makes it more
interesting too and I think I'm going to
pull the other ones through as well so
we can see them from the side here I'll
select the link shift the snap it with
the middle Mouse button to there and
then shift R to repeat that
process and these look a little bit too
plain but let's have a look in the build
in the game to see what this looks like
now so just select it file export
fpx and then tab back into the game and
there's our building so it's looking a
little bit better I think it's too small
I think it needs to go a little bit
bigger so select everything and scale
everything
up and then make sure that it's uh let's
see it's too far in the ground now so we
can move it up to
here probably let's try to export this
one and I'm going to make the f
Foundation here darker as well like that
not that you see that one anyway but on
the slopes you will and let's export it
again so that's a bit better size I
think for that one and it looks a bit
boring when these arrays are or like the
solar ones are static like that so I'm
going to rotate these a little
bit rotate set okay we need the
foundations too I
think so as if if
they're but then again that like the
whole thing wouldn't rotate guess we'll
put them on a like a turntable thing
shift e to duplicate that on right click
subdivide and go edit Circle and scale
it it to
extrude there we go it makes sense if
this whole thing
instead turned X and then do limited
dissolve there Shifty to duplicate that
on E to extrude and now we'll just l l l
l l l select all the link
here there we go and this one and rotate
said there we go that probably will look
a little bit more interesting and this
one again this sticks out as if it
should be a different color this
platform should probably be darker as
well
and I think I wonder if um
for the for the game I actually shaded a
lot of stuff smooth nearly everything so
I think I should uh step up a lot of the
sh smooth shading here cuz if I if if I
select everything and could do shade
smooth it probably won't look so good
here will
it I'm expecting this to look stupid in
the game so let's try
it yeah looks like that's good then we
know
uh this is looking too plain it
inset alt e extrud long face normals
hold the ALT key see the difference here
it's a subtle different but if I do a
little bit more hold the ALT key see in
the center there it just uh otherwise
it'll
incorrectly like scale it so hold the
ALT key here just that'll make it
right dark to there and then here it set
alt e extreme long face normals hold the
ALT key
again like a dark window and this is
looking way too plain so time for
accents Shifty to duplicate this one
scale bring in actually I can scale this
whole thing
up and Shifty to duplicate x-axis and
then three of these that's good scale X
bring them down a little bit
more and here's probably space for
another platform e to
extrude cuz there's a lot of research
going on in here remember scale x e to
extrude I should probably have some
emissive uh surfaces on the inside here
later
on here we go Control Plus G move it to
there this is also looking way too
plain so maybe thinner accents here
should we try that yep we should Shifty
to duplicate scale bring in in E to
extrude bring this one in El select link
accent El select link and repetition
usually looks good too so Shifty to
duplicate Z axis Shifty to duplicate Z
axis and we'll put three of them there
but that turned out to be too
high so I'll have to move this one down
a bit and this one down a bit
too okay
here looking too plain on this side I
think but we can get away with it maybe
for
now um should we put some sort of a pole
here right click subdivide Circle scale
e to
extrude actually maybe we'll
do shift
Zed maybe we should have some
cylindrical building here that's like
integrated into this
one X and then do limited disolve we
don't need those extra lines up
there let's flip this one rotate Z
180 make this one a bit
wider
and up to here and then Shifty to
duplicate it e to extrude shift e to
duplicate and E to extrude e to extrude
S to
scale don't know why this is looking a
bit like a lighthouse but we'll figure
out what to do with
that and it inset e to extrude and
darker okay now we're starting to get to
like having a little bit of detail
everywhere I'd say it inset it to
extrude
we don't want the accent to go through
so move that one into
here Control Plus on the keypad there or
numpad and control minus there we
go two plane here as well maybe a bridge
over probably not because it would
interfere with this one but I I mean we
could control
B it's like a corridor that'll
work and then contrl r
okay before I bevel I'm going to do the
control R control r contrl r bevel and
then it doesn't really make sense that
those are but I'll I'll look maybe it
makes sense we'll find out this is
looking too plain as well but we can
sort that out probably control R control
r contrl b should we bevel just one
there these two contrl B
that should
work and these could be like as if it's
like glass or something as well so let's
go
darker maybe let's try
it a little bit more uh file export fpx
export and bring it into the game and on
pause let's have some units walking
around here as well
should we put
some war going on here as well probably
needs I mean I'm okay with it uh but it
probably needs a little bit
more interesting features maybe animate
it a little
bit why is he just shooting without
aiming he needs to aim at it that's a
little bug that'll get fixed
uh I'm going to rotate a little bit so
let's see
Academy here we
go and
rotate I need a
medic oh yeah some Shadows up
there is damage already work working
yeah I've got a material for damage so
it just distorts the polygons and puts a
like a dark darker texture on it so it
already works but the explosion of it is
not going to look correct but the damage
already works I should talk about that
it's basically just a material if I
pause there and then we'll do the
academy let's have a look
on press there cuz that might be
interesting to know about
mesh it's called town here but it's not
see here player
so this material if I double click on it
maybe I can find it opening Shader
editor I'm actually using they were on
the built-in render pipeline so this one
is using uh this type of a damage
texture and then it just uh projects it
onto three different faces like a cube
projection and then it uh uses those
Cloud textures and it distorts the uh
the vertex offset here as well so I'm
not going to go through too much but
it's basically just the slider that
offsets the vertices a little bit on the
building and then gradually increases
these noise textures onto the um just
like project them onto the building but
it works pretty simple that way so it's
basically just a slider from if I do
here damage
here maybe we'll zoom in a little bit
more okay not like
that so damage zero damage and distort
the vertices a little bit on the cloud
texture and then also just fade that
damage texture in so saves you having to
do like when we created the game first I
created three different models and
switched out the mesh but this is uh so
much
easier all right folks there we have it
we prototyped ourselves a little academy
building for the game line war and we'll
see I probably need to modify it quite a
bit before the final version ends up in
the game at least this is a like a rough
draft of what it could look like and
then um there's a lot of other stuff
that goes into creating this building
because I need to be able to I need to
animate it inside of unity so when it's
constructed it like slides up the
different accents and it adds the
different floors and it creates a
scaffolding on and it usually needs like
a robot that it looks like it's building
it so that's a lot of work and also need
to fracture it and have like a
destruction model so when the the units
shoot it and blow it up it needs to like
explode in the right place but just to
get the mesh like roughed out and
blocked out and then imported into the
game it's uh pretty simple and
straightforward
so but then the devil's in the details
then there's a little extra work added
onto that I hope you like the video give
it a thumbs up if you did and don't
forget to subscribe if you haven't
already and I'll see you in a video soon
again bye for now
[Music]