[Music]
I don't never slow up no I don't take
I got no love for the fness if you
want to play tough and want to hate this
I always show up I don't never slow up
no I don't take I got no love for
the fiess if you want to play tough and
want to hate this I'll always show up
and make a statement I don't have slow
up no I don't take I got no love
for the Fess if you want to play tough
and want to hate this I'll show up and
make a statement everything I do so
instinctive and so passionate every word
I move so descriptive like an adjective
I got a vetta against people who
patented it being negative when you
should be getting after it I got facts
over facts over tracks this a n spitting
slow spitting fast I could roast I could
gas think I'm okay Al last but I don't
know if that can a race saw the past in
the pettiness a reflection of The
Emptiness hilarious you think you're
with my time you're Delirious mysterious
because you are behind the fake exterior
inferior you know I'll always be a bit
Superior get off of me this ain't no
humble brag I want you to hear words you
can say them back I want you to feel
free from the chains at last and to
believe in what you got it was built to
last yeah now that I've been put through
hell I never got anyone's help I had to
do it all
myself I don't never slow up no I don't
take I've got no love for the
fakeess if you want to play tough and
want to hate this I'll always show up
and make a statement I don't never throw
up no I don't take sure I got no love
for the Fess if you want to play tough
and want to hate this I'll always show
up and make a statement going to learn
the consequence of being incompetent
mental health is confidence dreams into
hestness I'm not here to say the day
that's for you to take away I could play
a million mind games but instead of say
something not logical something that is
topical rub it on and watch it go make
yourself Unstoppable Dre your
irresponsible but they always possible
if you just believe you could be so
remarkable thoughts in my head a collage
spread I'll be great one day going off
of my meds no I'm not giving up no I'm
not giving in I will make it to the top
taking off in the wind I got to make it
I'm saving every day to taste it I'm
patient from my mind it can hardly take
it I'm chasing a dream that I've had for
several ages of B modern Kingdom for the
Tak now that I've been put through out I
never got anyone's help I had to do it
all
myself I don't never SC up no I don't
take I got no love for the fakeess
if you want
[Music]