today i'm going to teach you how to make
a low poly landscape inside blender
let's go okay so here we are over in
london basically what you want to do
first is you can have your basic
landscape usually what you do so i have
like two methods for making our
landscape so the first one is you'll
just grab like a plane we can scale it
like all the way up like this and then
go ctrl a also you see so i have our
scale right a random scale so you see 86
so it's ctrl a
scale and you see now system back to one
and the two ways that i can do is either
i can take this i can subdivide it so
i'm just going to tab to go to edit mode
and i go to w
subdivide and you can see it subdivided
open up this bottom middle tab and then
just make it like 20 or 220 uh or even
more let's go like 40. so we have it
like this now what we can do is we can
use the uh proportional editing let's
click on this little button let me turn
it on and what you can do with this is
you can just select part of the part of
it and you can see like drag it up and
then you just scroll down your mouse
wheel and you can see you can kind of
just make changes to the whole
kind of like landscape of it
so you can kind of usually just make
something that you want like this
so yeah so it doesn't work too well
you can also like sculpt it
until you get something not don't you
remove it too much
and yep and you can have it like that
and then usually you can just like
select the outside edge
and like extrude it out and i don't have
a proportionality and scale it up
and you could like add some air tubes
and like smooth it out like that so you
get some sort of land like this
and what you can do so you can have like
your main landscape be like around here
and then you'll usually have like some
sort of barriers around the edges and
what you can do also is you can make
like mountains and stuff so what i'd
usually do with this is i'll add a
decimate uh just to make it like look
more
nice
and then like depending on what you
specifically need so if you have like
small detailed spots you can have like a
high resolution and then like sculpt it
in
so you can have like some specific spots
maybe have like a river you can just go
sculpt mode and then just like carve
something out for like a river
maybe it like separates into like a pond
and carries on out the other side so you
can see so you can kind of just quickly
sculpt it and get something simple uh
yeah like this so you can leave the the
modifiers on as well if you want also
what you want to do is you want to maybe
exclusives there what you can do is you
can create like mountains so make sure
you go to edit preferences and then go
to add-ons a dot n so you see a dot n
dot t and you can see and landscape so
just enable arts and then you'll see you
have a create button or you can just go
shift a
mesh landscape and you can see it's all
the way down here in the middle so you
can see you can create monitors like
this so if you have something nice you
can just go decimate it and then just
shades flat and then just scale it all
the way up you can just like put it
underneath like this uh and then you can
just like mess around with it until it
like intersects properly or you can use
something like booleans billions so yeah
so you can create like map uh some stuff
like this uh or you could you can create
like custom mountain for each one this
river is probably a bit too big
especially around like a mountain here
but yeah so we have some like this so
you can carry on just like working on
something like this just to get
something pretty decent for your thing
uh make a custom
uh mountain for each part and then yeah
like this
and then you can also set up like some
materials let's say here we have our
camera here let's go at a camera i'm
going to use my custom keyboard you're
going to use control
uh control alt and 0 on the numpad
so i'll put it like here
you can just like sculpt the mountains
if you want to like have it a specific
way or like decimator more or less and
then you want to get lucky materials
like the mountains will be gray and then
you can have like your ground
be like a green
just go rendered i'll turn it to cycles
i'll just set it to like a low sample
count and then turn on render region i
think what i want is like a low f of e
so i'll do like 24
go 30 35
so it doesn't look the greatest
uh it doesn't look the greatest with
having this like little
like separation here
uh so usually
so they couldn't usually just like
figure out a way or we can add some like
bushes and stuff
so what you can do also we want to do
the water so you can just go add like a
plane
scale it up like this
and then just like extrude it out
and then you'll just want to drag it up
so you can actually see the parts
through and then maybe just go back and
skip parts and yeah
there
and then just screw it all the way along
and then if you want to get some better
looking like colors on the actual
um
also on the actual ground
what we can do is we can do a vertex
color uh paint
and
what that will do is if we go
there
i think i want to
fix this so we can see the water
so maybe we can just select everything
and kind of like
rotate it like this
and then we can just
bring this down
uh maybe wait
scope mode
it's like there okay cool
and then what you want to do
is we go to
materials give us a blue
you're going to select subdivide this
uh add a
displace
new
go to the texture tab changes to clouds
you want to make it small so it's kind
of just a random drag upstream slightly
maybe yes so the subdivisions and then
also decimate it again just to add a
nice look to the water um but let's just
actually just leave us an e for now you
can also like drag down the roughness
and maybe
transmission so with that you'll have to
add some alpha blend that's not great
just because of some internal preview
and yeah so you can just mess around
with everything and then what i'm saying
with them at the vertex page so
basically what we can do is we can go to
this little toolbox and black paints the
colors on
so
start this
we'll see wait what is the color let's
grab this color
and then paste it in
and we can paint our entire model with
it
because then what we can do is go
grab the color for the rocks
and then go away vertex paint go back to
the tool
and paint in the gray
vertical screen
so we're gonna make a color palette just
click new go plus
and then put in the gray color for the
rocks
click plus so we can make it there
and
you can like paint in the colors you can
drag it down the opacity if you want to
like blend it in so you can kind of just
start like blending everything in
so let's just get rid of the mountains
for now just to
make it easier to paint everything in
yeah like there so if we go unhard
if we go to shading and then we go
vertex color
and then choose the color
color to base color and you can see so
it actually works so you can do the same
thing with the mountains if you want to
paint a specific part onto them
and you can get it kind of working like
that if you want you can go at a
color ramp
uh
i don't know how well this is going to
work but we can do something like this
and then
this won't really work out well
uh
okay if you can come up with a way if
you just have like two colors whatever
your landscape
or you can if you have like black and
white whatever so we can set up a color
ramp like this and you can see we have
it like this and then we can actually
like clamp them together or just turn it
to constant actually
and then you can see we can kind of set
it up this and if we have multiple
colors um so we can have like a second
color maybe we have like a different
green like a darker green
or if we have like a yellow sandy color
kind of thing
um we can go
paint that in
like this around the sides yeah it's
like this then you can see we can kind
of bring it back in here
but then what we do
is if we bring three colors
it'll work the best but
you can just get it to like set up like
this
and then give it the colors so we have
our base color green
check the color palette we can put
around gray
or you can just have it like smooth over
and then just plug it in and then you
have the colors actually working
properly and you can change it on the
flower like this um and i guess if you
want you could i guess if we have a
darker green it might work so just grab
this color and then we can just kind of
give it like a variation of it and then
we can also start making some foliage