so i've been getting some tutorial
requests to make some more low poly
blender tutorials and so i decided to
make a tutorial on how to make low poly
nature in blender so in this tutorial
we're going to be making all of these
different nature assets and if you'd
just like to follow a certain part and
just model a certain nature asset i'm
gonna have time stamps in the video
description so you can just go down
there and click on a timestamp and it'll
jump you to the part in the video where
i make the asset so we're gonna be
making this low poly mountain with snow
on it we're also gonna be creating this
low poly tree stump and a low poly
wooden log we're also going to be making
these low poly flowers and i'm going to
show you how to make it so that when you
duplicate the flowers the flowers have a
random color and i'm going to show you
how to set up the colors to the colors
that you want we're also going to be
making some low poly rocks and we're
going to be making some low poly grass
this is something that you could use
like a particle system and make the
grass in a scene and we're going to
create some low poly bushes and some
different mushrooms so we're going to be
creating some brown mushrooms and also
some of these red mushrooms with the
little white dots on them and i'm going
to be using blender evie for this
tutorial but you could definitely use
cycles i'm just using evie because evie
is a real-time render engine and i think
it looks pretty nice for these low poly
nature assets alright so here i am in a
new scene in blender and i've turned the
render engine to eevee and then i've
turned on ambient occlusion screen space
reflections and motion blur and then
also over here on the world settings i
have this whipple creek hdri i just used
the 1k version i'll have the link in the
video description this is from
hdrihaven.com
if you'd like to download this hdri that
i'm using and i'm just using this to get
some really nice lighting for our nature
scene so let's first start off by making
the mountain so to make the mountain i'm
actually going to be using a landscape
blender add-on it's built into blender
so you can enable it by going edit and
going to preferences and then right over
here on the add-ons just start typing in
landscape and you can see there's the
add mesh ant landscape just turn this on
and then if you want it to be in all
your future blender files you can click
on save preferences and then you can
always use it in the future so with that
turned on i'm going to press shift a i'm
going to go to mesh and i'm going to go
all the way down here and click on
landscape you can see it adds a
landscape so this is basically a
landscape generator now there are a
bunch of settings here but there's also
some presets if you click on this you
could see it has a bunch of different
presets you can try these out and use
one that you like i'm going to use
mountains 2. so when i click on that it
does look pretty cool but it's not very
high up so to make it bigger i can
scroll down here and there's this height
if i hold down the shift key while
dragging this i can make more sensitive
movements and i can make this a lot
higher so now that we have this mountain
i'm just going to close these settings
right here
and i'm going to tab in edit mode and
you can see what the mountain is looking
like now right now it's smooth and it's
also way too high poly so we're going to
make it look low poly so i'm going to go
back into object mode so instead of this
being shaded smooth i want it to be
shaded flat so you can just shade that
flat and now it definitely looks more
low poly but it's just a bunch of
squares and there's not really any
triangles and it is too high detail so
what i'm going to do is go over here to
the modifiers tab i'm going to click on
add modifier and i'm going to add the
decimate modifier now this ratio here
you can turn this down and what it's
going to do is it's going to start
taking away more and more of the mesh
and you can see now it has a very low
poly look so just get it to how you like
i like something i like that you can see
it has all those little triangles and
stuff in there which i really like so
now that i like that i'm going to move
my mouse over the decimate modifier and
press ctrl a make sure you're in object
mode when you do this ctrl a and that'll
apply it now when i tab in edit mode you
can see it has a lot less vertices and
it has much more of a low poly look so
now i'm going to add some material so
i'm going to click over here on the
material tab click on new and i'm going
to call this mountain and for this i'm
just going to make the base color a dark
brown color i'm also going to press z
and move my mouse up to go into rendered
view and you can see what it's looking
like now right now it's a bit too shiny
so i'm going to turn the roughness up a
bit because mountains aren't really that
shiny and then i will also make this
darker and maybe turn the roughness up
just a bit more okay something like that
so now i want to add the snow on the top
of the mountains so what i'm going to do
is tap into edit mode and i just need to
select the top parts where i want the
snow to be so to do that i'm going to
press 3 and that'll go to this face
select you can also just click right
here press a to deselect everything and
then i'm going to press 1 to go to front
view actually in this case i'm going to
press 3 to go to side view because i can
see the mountains a little bit better
then i'll press z and move my mouse over
to go into wireframe and now i can press
c and that's going to open up the circle
select and i can just select the little
peaks where i want the snow to be so
there i want a lot of snow to be right
there okay a little bit more here and
now i can just go around here press z
move out to go back into solid view and
i could just box select a few areas by
pressing b for the box select just
selecting a few areas that i want to be
snow maybe in here i want there to be
more snow so i'm gonna just go around
here pressing b for box select just
selecting all the areas that you want
the snow to be on okay let's just go
around here i don't want there to be too
much snow but also not too little snow
all right so once you've selected all
the places that you want the snow to be
i'm going to scroll up here i'm going to
click on the plus and then click on new
and i'm going to call it snow and i'm
just going to leave it at the default
maybe just make it a little bit more
shiny so turn the roughness down a
little bit because snow is somewhat
reflective and then with that selected
i'm going to click assign so now if i go
into rendered mode you can see what it's
looking like so now if you want to go
ahead and change some stuff like maybe
there's a little bit too much snow or
too little you can have an edit mode
just keep on selecting some areas like i
think i might have some snow there um i
think i might connect these so if i just
like box select this maybe go to the
circle select with c
just select some more areas and then
with the snow selected click on a sign
now you can see there's more snow and
then also if you're going to have these
mountains as a backdrop behind your low
poly scene you could just like scale it
down on the x axis scale it down like
that and then when you're looking at it
from side view it does look a little bit
cooler but when you're looking at it
from the top it does look kind of weird
stretched out so you may not want to do
that it really depends on your scene so
i'm just going to scale it down a little
bit by going s and x scan it down just a
little bit more so it's a little bit
more flatter kind of like a mountain
range just like that and then one last
thing i am going to go into edit mode
press one to go to the vertex select and
just hold down the shift key and select
these four vertices out here and then
press x and delete vertices and that way
there's just a circle around the
mountains and i think it makes it look a
little bit nicer so that's going to be
it for my low poly mountains all right
so let's go ahead and do the trees next
now before we do the trees i'm just
going to press shift a add a plane i
will scale this plane down and then
press s and y scale it out a little bit
and then i'm going to hit new and call
this grass just add a grass material and
then on the base color i'm just going to
make it a basic grass material
and go down here turn the roughness up a
bit and that's just going to be our
plane that we're going to have the
nature assets on all right so let's make
the four trees now the first one i'm
going to make is the apple tree or the
fruit tree so i'm going to press shift a
and i'm going to start with a plane just
scale the plane down and just bring it
up by pressing g and z bring it up a
little bit i'm actually going to go out
of rendered mode just so that i can see
it a little bit better okay i'm going to
tab into edit mode and with all of these
selected i'm going to press s
0 and enter so that way we only have one
little vertice right in the middle now
i'm going to press m and that'll merge
it and i'm going to merge by distance
and now it's gotten rid of the extra
vertices and there's just one vertice in
the middle so now i can press 1 to go to
front view and it does look like i
actually modeled this sideways so i'm
just going to press a to select
everything r and z and type in 90
enter now when i press 1 the mountain is
going to be behind us and i think i will
press g and then click with my middle
mouse wheel just move this over a little
bit so just select the tree again i'm
going to press 1 for front view and i
will tab into edit mode and then i can
just extrude that up by pressing e and
i'm basically just going to make the
shape of the tree trunk just going all
the way up here and then i'm going to
have two branches coming out and
connecting up to the tree so i'm going
to select this extrude that out with e
extrude that up just click and place
that and just have it come up we're
going to be having all the leaves up
here and then i think i will press ctrl
r add a loop cut right in there click
and then press g and bring this down and
then i can extrude this up with e and
then e again and just bring that up now
the tree is kind of flat right now so
i'm gonna hold down the shift key select
this branch press seven to go to top
view and just press r to rotate that and
just bring it out a little bit and then
i could also do that for this branch so
i will click on this and then shift
select this and this one
7 for top view and just press r to
rotate it a little bit press g and move
it over
and now the tree is a little bit more 3d
okay let's tab back into object mode and
now i need to add some modifiers to
thicken it up so i'm going to go to the
modifiers panel right here and i'm going
to click on add modifier and we're going
to add the skin modifier so when we add
it now it has a lot of thickness but
it's a little bit too thick so i'm going
to tab into edit mode double tap a make
sure everything is selected you can go
into wireframe view just to see if
everything's selected and then i'm going
to press ctrl a
and ctrl a is going to scale how thick
that skin is so just scale it down ctrl
a make it smaller and then i do want the
trunk to be thicker and then i want the
limbs to be thinner so i will deselect
everything
press z move my mouse over we'll go into
wireframe press b i'm just going to box
select some of the trunk and then i can
press ctrl a make it a bit thicker
and then just box select the bottom here
press ctrl a make it even thicker and
then i think i'll just select this last
one press ctrl a and make it even
thicker so now the tree starts out
really thick and then it gets thinner
and thinner and then right up here i'm
going to select this one and this one
press ctrl a make it even smaller
because these are just some branches
coming out and then i think i want the
trunk overall to be a little bit thicker
so i'll just box select the trunk here
press ctrl a make it a little bit
thicker overall
all right there we go so now we have
our low poly trunk and branches so now
i'm going to press ctrl a with my mouse
over this and this is going to apply the
modifier so now if i tap into edit mode
you can see that it's actual vertices
now it adds a lot of extra vertices in
here and that's a little bit annoying so
i'm just going to get rid of these you
don't really have to it's not really
going to affect the look but it will
make it a little bit lower poly so to
get rid of these pretty quickly i'm
going to go up here and click on this
merge auto merge vertices what that'll
do is when the vertices get really close
to each other they're going to merge
together so now what i can do is alt
select one of these loops and then
double tap g move it down or actually
i'll move it up and then when i let go
it automatically merges it together so i
can double tap g
pull it up let go it's going to merge
that i can alt select this double tap g
edge slide and then place that double
tap g again double tap g again and i can
very quickly just get rid of all those
extra vertices if you'd like to okay i'm
going to do that up here so click on
this one you can alt select a loop and
then double tap g click double tap g
double tap g
okay double tap g just keep on doing
that bringing it around all right there
we go so now the tree is a lot lower
poly let's tap back into object mode now
and now let's make the rest of the tree
so i'm just going to click to place my
3d cursor right about there i'll press
shift and i'm going to add an icosphere
now it's really big right now let's just
zoom out on the icosphere settings right
here i want to turn this up don't turn
it up too high because if you turned up
really high it could make it really
laggy and possibly crash blender but i'm
just going to turn this up to 5 and then
i can just click on this and scale it
down so we're just going to scale it
down
and then i can also tab and edit mode
scale it on the z and then just scale
that up a little bit more and i need to
make it a little bit bigger so that the
branches go into it all right so now i
need to make the shape of the tree what
i'm going to do is press the o key and
that's going to turn on this
proportional editing right here now if i
just click on a point and press g to
grab you can see that it's pulling along
vertices with it now if i scroll wheel i
need to scroll my wheel down you can see
that there is this circle here and this
circle is telling it how much is going
to be pulled along with it so i can just
pull it around and i can make smooth
adjustments so i can just click on some
points press g and just move them around
and that way i can very quickly and
easily make the shape of my tree so just
make it kind of lumpy and random and
maybe pull it out a little bit more
where the branches are so there's some
more leaves where the branches are and
then maybe click on the top press g move
it up a bit more
alright so i like that so i'm going to
tab back into object mode now to give it
that low poly look again i'm going to
click on add modifier and just like the
mountain i'm going to add the decimate
modifier so this ratio here i can turn
this down and you can see that now it
starts to have that low poly look so
just turn it way down you can also hold
the shift key as you're pulling this
ratio down so that the movements are a
lot more sensitive and then once you're
happy with it you can hold your mouse
over this and press ctrl a so now it
looks very low poly so now let's add the
material onto the tree and then we'll
add the apples or the fruit or whatever
is on the tree so i'm going to press z
move my mouse up to go into a rendered
view and then i'm going to go to the
material panel right here i'll click on
new and i'm going to call this green now
i'm calling this green because i'm
actually going to use this in a bunch of
the assets almost all the assets are
going to be using the same material so
what i'm going to do is turn the base
color to a green color
make it a little bit darker a bit more
saturated of a green color and then
right down here the roughness turn that
up just a little bit more and then i'm
going to select the tree trunk click on
new and i can call this wood and then
this one for the base color i'm just
going to make this a brown color
a bit darker than that
maybe a little less saturated and then
i'm going to turn the roughness up a bit
just like that and then i think i'll
select the leaves and just scale the
whole thing up a little bit more alright
so now let's go ahead and make the
apples so i'm going to place my 3d
cursor right here and then i'll press
shift a and i'm going to add another
icosphere i'll zoom way out here now
don't move the icosphere because if you
do these settings will disappear on the
subdivisions i'm going to turn this all
the way down to one so the minimum
close this and now i can just scale this
down and this is going to be our apple
so just put it in there i'm going to
click on new and call this material
apple and then i'm going to make this a
red color i don't want to make it too
saturated because if it's super red then
it could look a little bit unrealistic
if it's super super deep red i'm going
to make it a little less saturated and
slightly more orange i think that just
looks a little bit nicer and i forgot to
mention this but if you haven't saved
your file yet it's probably a pretty
good idea to save this just in case
blender crashes you won't lose anything
so just go file and save and save your
project so now i just need to select
this apple and i'm just going to press
shift d shift d will duplicate the
object and i'm just going to manually
place them around i was thinking about
using a particle system and if you had a
lot of apples you could do that but
because we don't have that many apples
i'm just going to manually place them
around and usually the fruit is going to
be kind of hanging down so i think it
looks better if the fruit or the apples
is down here if you have the apples up
here i think that kind of seems a little
weird so i'm just going to have some
apples kind of hanging down more at the
bottom of the tree so just go around
here and make however many apples you
want and if you wanted to you could
model some low poly fruit like maybe
some pears or some other fruit like some
plums or some other fruit like that that
grows on trees you could also just
slightly vary the size of them because
apples are just randomly different sizes
some of them are a little bit bigger and
some of them are a little bit smaller so
you can just give the fruit some random
scale here and then one more thing
really quick i think this might be just
slightly too high poly i'm just going to
add another decimate modifier just turn
this down slightly
or something like that and then press
control a to apply that i think that
looks just a little bit nicer so now i
want to join all these objects together
so that when we grab the tree and move
it they're all going to be moved along
so i'm going to press z go into
wireframe just press b and box select
this area and then i'm going to press
ctrl j and now they're all joined
together so if i press z and move my
mouse up into render mode and just move
around you can see that now they're all
one object i'm just going to place this
tree into the ground just slightly and
then we'll go on to the next tree all
right the next tree is pretty simple
we're just going to be making a long
tree kind of coming up so i'm going to
center my 3d cursor right here i'm going
to press shift a and i'm going to go to
mesh and i'm going to add a cube and i
guess i modeled everything pretty small
because whenever i add in the objects
they're really big so i'm just going to
scale this way down and this is going to
be the trunk for our tree so i want it
to be the same materials so i'm going to
click on the tree right here and then
i'm going to click on wood and then i
can drag this color and drop color it on
there now it's going to add the material
to that object so i can tab in edit mode
now i'm going to press 3 to go to face
select and select this face
press 1 to go to the front view and then
i'll press g and z bring this up and you
can see that the proportional editing is
still on so i can just click this to
turn it off or press the o key so then
just select this top face again i'll
press 1 for front view g and z bring it
up and then s and scale it down now this
tree trick is pretty square right now
and i want to give it a little bit more
faces on some of the sides so so i'm
going to press 2 and that'll go to the
edge select and then i'll just select
this edge and then i'll press ctrl b and
that's going to add a bevel just make it
a random size like that and then click
on this one ctrl b add another bevel
and i want the size to be different so
maybe i'll make this one really small
and then select this edge ctrl b maybe
make this one a pretty big one and then
select this one ctrl b so now the tree
trunk just has a bit more of a random
shape so now i'm going to press shift a
and i'm going to add another icosphere
and i need to zoom out and go to the
icosphere settings right here this one
i'm gonna set back up to like five or
six and then i'll scale this way down
and then press g and z bring it up i'll
press one for front view so i can see
kind of how high this is
scale it up a little bit more okay now
i'm gonna tab into edit mode and just go
up to the top here i'll press o and
that'll turn on the proportional editing
again and just click on an area on the
top here and then i'll press g and z
bring it up and you can scroll your
scroll wheel to change how big that
circle is just make it something like
that and then also just select a few
more points i think i'll go back into
the vertex select just select some
points kind of pull them around to give
it a little bit more of a random shape
maybe just make it a little bit flatter
on the bottom here and just pull in some
of the areas just make it a little bit
more random all right so now that we
have the basic shape of this i'm going
to go to add modifier and once again add
this really great decimate modifier turn
this down and it's going to give that
really awesome low poly look now you can
see that the faces are pretty stretched
right here and they're not very
stretched down here so if you don't like
this i'll show you what i'm gonna do to
get rid of that so there we go i like
how that is i think i'll just actually
pull this out just make it a tad bit
smaller okay there we go so now with my
mouse over this i'm going to press ctrl
a and that will apply that modifier now
down here on the bottom of the tree if i
want to make this the same amount of
detail as the top here i can tab into
edit mode select one of these vertices
just pick one and this is still turned
on we turned this on earlier the auto
merge vertices so if i double tap g
and just push this in it's going to
merge with it and now there's going to
be less vertices now we still have this
thing on here so i'm going to press o to
turn it off and now i can just select
some points and double tap g and that's
going to do the edge slide and i can
just drag them around and get rid of
some of the vertices so i'm just going
to go around here and do that a little
bit on some of these areas so that the
vertices count is more even across the
entire object so now i'm going to press
z move my mouse up we'll go into
rendered mode i'm going to select this
and click over here to
the materials click on the green color
and then i can just drag and drop this
on and now it has the green color i
think i'll just scale this up and bring
it down just slightly now you can see
that these green colors are exactly the
same and this is okay if you're fine
with it but what i want to do is just
add a little bit of varying color in all
of the different green objects so what
i'm going to do is click on the shading
tab and then i'm going to press period
on the number pad to jump over here and
you can see that here is the shader
nodes so what i'm going to do is right
here press shift a and i'm going to
search for the object info node just
drop it right in here and what i'm going
to use is this random value and i'm
going to plug this random value into the
base color and then when i give it
different random colors it's going to
just slightly make the different objects
slightly different varying colors of
green so now what i can do is press
shift a here search for a color ramp and
drop the color amp right in here so now
what it's going to do is the different
objects if i just like duplicate this
you can see that the colors are going to
be randomly different through the black
to the white so now i can just change
these colors so this black one here i'm
going to make a dark green and then this
white one here i'm going to make a light
green so i don't want it to be too light
because i don't want it to look crazy
bright and then this one maybe just a
little bit darker and then in between
this i can make a couple more colors so
i'm going to click on the plus here to
make a new color
drag the tab over and this one i think i
want to be a little less saturated a
little more gray something like that
maybe just make it a little bit darker
and then i can click on the plus again
to add another one this one i'm going to
drag over here and then this one i can
make just a little bit more saturated
and a little bit brighter i'm going to
make that one fully saturated just up
like that
maybe make that just a little bit
brighter so now you can see if i just
select these and duplicate them just to
show you whenever i duplicate them
they're just going to randomly be
different colors and that just adds a
lot and just makes it a little bit
cooler so i'm just going to delete these
now oop delete these ones let's go back
into the layout here so there is the
second tree so i'm going to select this
and shift select this and then press
ctrl j all right let's go ahead and make
the third tree now so i'm going to click
and place my 3d cursor right there and
then i'll press shift a and once again
i'm going to add a plane i'm going to
tab into edit mode and press s to scale
0 and then enter and then because we
have that auto merge turned on there
already is one vertice because they
already got joined together so now i can
press 1 to go to front view and i can
just extrude this up so press e to
extrude bring that up and i'm going to
make this tree have a bunch of different
branches so i'm going to extrude it kind
of make it kind of wobbly and then
extrude this up and over and this one's
just going to have a bunch of different
branches
and then we'll have some different uh
green blobs for
the leaves on the tree and i want these
to be somewhat 3d as well so i'm going
to box select a branch rotate it over
just so that's a little more three
dimensional i think i'll press ctrl r
right in here click to add a vertice and
then i can extrude this out and make
another branch bring that branch up i'm
going to press ctrl r here click to add
a vertice
and then extrude that out all right and
then once you like how that looks i'm
going to go to over here to the
modifiers click on add modifier and we
are going to add the skin modifier just
like before now for some reason it's
really big i'm going to tab into edit
mode uh press a to select everything and
press ctrl a and make it really small
pressing ctrl a with that whole thing
selected i don't know why it was really
big all right there we go so now i'm
just going to press z go into wireframe
a to deselect everything and just b and
box select the middle part of the trunk
scale that up because i want the trunk
to be a bit thicker so i'm pressing ctrl
a and that'll scale up the skin modifier
and then i want the bottom to be even
thicker so i will just box select just
the bottom ctrl a make that even thicker
and then just select this bottom one
here ctrl a and make it really thick and
maybe move it down a little bit all
right now you can see that there's some
weird glitches here and this is because
of the angle of the vertices so if i
just tap into edit mode press z go into
wireframe just select this if i just
play around with this you can see that
now let me just play around with this if
you make the angle wider then it'll fix
itself so there we go that looks a lot
better and then the branches here i want
them to slowly get thinner and thinner
so i can just hold down the shift key
and select these vertices here
and then press ctrl a and make them even
thinner
and then i'm just going to
box select some of these parts right
here kind of more at the starting of the
branches ctrl a just make them a little
bit thicker so once you're happy with
your tree again ctrl a with your mouse
over the skin modifier to apply that and
then if you want to again you can hold
down the alt key and select a loop and
just keep on double tapping g and moving
it over and that way you can get rid of
some of those extra loops because the
skin modifier adds in some extra loops
right in there so just alt select a loop
double tap g and bring it up and with
that auto merge turn on it's going to
automatically merge them together so i'm
just going to keep doing that for a few
areas here all right there we go now
this may have happened for you or it may
not but basically there's some glitches
here and this is because i applied the
skin modifier while it still was acting
a little bit weird so i just need to
manually fix this so i'm going to press
3 to go to face select just select some
of the extra faces in there press x and
delete faces and then i need to press 1
for vertex select just hold down the
shift key and select the points and then
fill them with f
hopefully this didn't happen for you but
if it did it's a pretty easy fix and
there's another face in there so i'll
delete that face
and then just select the vertices and
fill that with f so once again just like
the other trees i'm going to press shift
a search for an icosphere
and then just scale this down and we're
going to make the little blobs of the
tree where the leaves are so i'm going
to tab into edit mode press o or turn on
this proportional editing and just give
it a random shape something that looks
good for you now since this is the main
trunk coming up i'm gonna have this blob
be the biggest so just make this blog
really big and then the other blobs that
are coming off of the uh branches
they're gonna be a lot smaller all right
there we go so i will click on add
modifier add the decimate modifier make
it way down about there okay and then i
will press shift d to duplicate this
scale it down and just stick it right in
there so the branches are going into it
i can tab into edit mode now and adjust
this so i can make it different than the
other one and i definitely want it to be
smaller
so i will scale it down okay like that
and then i actually want this branch to
be a little bit farther away because
it's a bit too close to this main piece
right here so i'm going to select the
branch tab and edit mode
z and move my mouse over to go into
wireframe i'll press a to deselect
everything and then i'm just going to
press b
box select this area right here
i'll press r and rotate that just bring
it over so that there's a little bit
more space there all right now i can
select this one press shift d and move
it over once you kind of get it into
place i can tab and edit mode and then
just select some points and continue to
change it make it a little bit more
unique okay so let's just do that for
the last one shift d move this over
make this one maybe even smaller change
it up a bit okay and now let's add
materials to this tree so press z move
your mouse up you can select this tree
and click over here to the materials and
then the wood here drop it onto the wood
and then select the green and just drop
it onto all of the leaves there just
like that all right so now i'm just
going to select the leaves go to the
modifiers and then with your mouse over
the modifier press ctrl a
just apply all of these and then once
they're all applied you can shift select
all of them and then press ctrl j all
right let's make that tree that kind of
is like a pine tree or kind of like a
christmas tree so i'm going to actually
use this one so i'm going to select this
press shift d click with my middle mouse
move it over here and then i'll just tab
into edit mode and then i can hover my
mouse over this and press l and that's
going to select all the linked vertices
and then i can press x and delete
vertices so now we're just going to be
working with the trunk so now i'm going
to press shift a and i'm going to add a
cylinder i'm going to scale this
cylinder down and just put it kind of
right there
on the tree trunk press three for face
select and just select this top face
right here and then using s just scale
that down and just make it really small
and then i'm going to add some loop cuts
in here because i want to add a lot more
geometry to work with so i'll press ctrl
r and i can actually scroll up and
scroll way up and just add a bunch of
vertices and then you can double click
to place that so now i'm going to press
l with my mouse hovered over this to
select all the linked vertices i'll
press p and separate this by selection
because i actually want it to be its own
object so i can tab into object mode
select this and then i'm going to click
down here and then just remove the wood
here so i'm just going to remove that
and now it's just the green material so
now what i can do is tab into edit mode
press 1 to go to the vertex select and
just select some vertices and once again
press o to turn on proportional editing
and just move this around and make it
kind of random just give it a little bit
of randomness some lumpy parts just that
it's not perfect this will make it look
more organic then once you're happy with
that you can go over to the modifiers
and once again add the decimate modifier
turn this way down
and you can see what it's doing so just
turn it down to something that you like
i like that and then with my mouse over
this i can press ctrl a to apply that
i'll press g and z and bring this up and
then one last thing before we start
duplicating these i'm going to go up
here tab into edit mode i'm going to
press 3 to go to the face select and
just select this face and then i need to
turn off the proportional editing again
and then i'll press s and 0 and enter
and that way it's just going to merge
these together because the merge is on
and now it's really pointy at the top so
now i can press one to go to side view
just bring this over and scale it down
and then i can press shift d click with
my middle mouse
scale it up and then also press r and z
and rotate it around so that it has a
random rotation
also you could rotate that so that this
bottom part here is a little bit
straighter okay let's do that again i
want to add four of them so i'll press
shift d again r and z give it a random
rotation and then just scale it up even
more
make sure that it's straight you can see
that this is way off because i rotated
it so i need to straighten that all out
okay
select this last one shift d
z
and then r and z and rotate it give it a
random rotation let me just scale this
up a bit as well because i want them to
slowly scale up bigger and bigger and
then as they get higher up they're going
to be smaller and smaller and then also
you can tab in edit mode and just select
some points press o to turn on
proportional editing and you can just
play around with this and just change
the shape of it a little bit and then
once you're happy with your pine tree
i'm going to shift select the entire
tree and press ctrl j so there we go
there's our four different trees alright
so next let's do the wooden log so i'm
going to place my 3d cursor right here
i'll press shift a and i'm going to
search for a circle now the circle here
if i open up the circle settings it's 32
which is pretty high i'm gonna change
this down to like an eight and that way
it'll be a lot less geometry i'll scale
this down and then i can press r to
rotate and y on the y-axis and then just
type in 9-0 and enter and that way it's
rotated sideways so i can just scale
this down kind of bring it down onto the
grass now what i'm going to do is press
7 for top view bring this over so i can
see it a little bit better i'll tab into
edit mode and just start to extrude this
out so extrude it out and then i will
turn off proportional editing because i
don't want to use that
and then i'll press e and extrude kind
of bring it down a little bit something
like this and scale it down a little bit
more and then e to extrude bring it out
even more and scale it a little bit more
so it slowly gets smaller and smaller as
it goes over and then i think i'll just
hold down alt select this loop and scale
that up a little bit alright so there's
our log we need to give it some
thickness though so i'm going to go to
add modifier and add the solidify
modifier and then on the thickness here
just turn this up i'm going to hold down
the shift key as i turn up this value
and then i'm going to press ctrl a with
my mouse over this modifier to apply it
so now it's actual geometry now i want
to put a hole in our log so what i'm
going to do is press ctrl r add a loop
cut right there
click to place it ctrl r add another one
place it about there and then ctrl r add
another one click to place it right in
the center so basically what i'm going
to do is i'm going to cut out a hole
right in the log now because this log
has thickness i do need to add loop cuts
inside it as well so i'm going to press
z move my mouse over to go into
wireframe and then it's a little bit
hard to see but if you kind of go at an
angle it's a little bit easier press
ctrl r i'm going to add one loop guy
here ctrl r another loop kind of in the
center and then ctrl r and one more out
here so if i just go up here i can
double tap g and just kind of place
these and just align them up with the
other ones so alt select that one you
can see it's in the middle there if i
press 7 for top view you can probably
see it a little bit better and then i
can double tap g and just get it about
the same as the other one so alt select
this double tap g all right now before
we cut this out i do want to make this a
circular shape and to do that i'm going
to actually use a blender add-on it's
built into blender though so to turn it
on you can go edit
go to preferences and then right over
here you can start typing in loop tools
just turn on the loop tools just check
mark that and then close this now when
you check mark it when you press n to
open up this panel you can go over to
edit and you can see here is the loop
tools add-on so when i click on it you
can see it has all these different
things what i can do is i can select the
vertices and then i can click on circle
and it's going to turn them into a
circle so i'm going to press 3 to go to
the face select click on this and then
shift click on this and then if i click
on the circle you can see now it is a
circle so i want to rotate it over so
it's a bit straighter with the log so i
will press r just rotate that over maybe
scale it down a little bit more alright
now i need to do the same thing for the
one inside so i will click on this shift
click on this
click on circle
and then
go back up here if i just go into
wireframe by pressing z and moving my
mouse over i can just align this up
and scale it down
okay now i want to delete these so i'll
press x and delete faces
and then go out of wireframe select this
one x and delete faces select this one
and x and delete faces so now we have a
hole coming out of our log but you can
see that you can see inside the
thickness of the log so i need to add
faces right along here so to do this i'm
going to press 1 to go to the vertex
select
just alt and click on this loop and then
hold down the shift key and alt key and
select this loop so now i have both of
those selected now you could manually
fill those with the f key and make faces
but what i'm going to do is press f3 to
go to the search and start typing in
bridge edge loops and if you click on
this
it automatically merges those together
as long as both sides have the same
amount of vertices it just fills all the
faces
and it works great just like that and
then i think i might hold down the shift
key select these two
press g and move them down a bit so that
they're a little bit more round with the
log
select these two press g and move those
down a little bit and then i think i'll
select this entire loop again just by
holding down the shift key and selecting
these loops and then just press control
b
and add a bevel there and that way it
just looks a little bit nicer okay let's
move over here and i want to give this a
little bit more detail so what i'll do
is tab into edit mode here alt select
this loop and then i'll just scale it
down just to make it a little bit
thicker and then i'll press three to go
to the face select and just select a few
different faces here
and then i'll press e and extrude them
out kind of like this is the bark of the
tree and the bark of the tree is just
going up a little bit like there's kind
of a lip you could also press one to go
to vertex select just select a few
vertices and just move them around to
just give a little bit more random shape
and then let's move around over to the
other side here and i want to make this
a little bit thicker as well so i'll tab
into edit mode hold down the alt key and
select this loop and scale it in a
little bit and then you can see that the
ground is coming through here so i just
need to press g and z
and bring this object up you can also
double tap r and rotate that a little
bit to make it a little bit flatter and
then g and z just bring that up because
i don't want the ground to be coming
through there all right so i'm going to
tab into edit mode press 3 to go to face
select and i'm just going to select a
few different parts right here and do
the same thing so e to extrude and then
i think i'll s and just scale that out
just a little bit and then i want to add
a little crack here in the log so i'm
going to press ctrl r
click and bring this down and then i
want to add another one so ctrl r just
add another loop cut in there so we have
two loop cuts really close to each other
and then i need to set a point for the
crack to end so i'll press ctrl r
click and bring this over just like that
and then i'll press one for vertex
select and just select this loop double
tap g and bring it over and if i click
there it's automatically going to merge
using the merge and then click on this
double tap g and again using that auto
merge it'll automatically merge together
so now we have a little crack in our log
and if we want to make it a little bit
bigger i can just shift and select these
two vertices
bring it up a little bit to make that
cut look a little bit bigger so now
let's add a couple of branches in our
log so i'm going to tab in edit mode
just alt select this loop press shift d
to duplicate it we can scale it down
rotate it with r and then press g
bring it over and just stick it inside
our log and i just want to stick it in
between that thickness there so it
doesn't come out on the other side so
once that's in place there i can press e
to extrude extrude it out and then r to
rotate s to scale and we're just going
to keep on extruding that out and make a
little limb or a branch coming out of
the tree trunk and then once that's as
far as you want you can press f to fill
that face now i want to have just a tiny
little branch coming out of this branch
so to do that i'll press ctrl r add a
loop cut right there and then i'm going
to press ctrl r add a loop cut in there
and then press 3 to go to face select
and i'm just going to select these two
vertices i can press n to open up that
panel again and there is our loop tools
click on circle and it will make it a
circle and then you can scale this up a
little bit and extrude it out scale it
down and that way you can just add a
little tiny branch coming off of the
bigger branch okay that looks pretty
good so i want to add something like
that to the other side so i'm just going
to duplicate it and then modify it a
little bit so i'm going to click
somewhere on here and then press l with
my mouse over this to select the entire
branch i'm just going to press 7 for top
view and then i'll press shift d to
duplicate this over
press r to rotate and scale it down a
little bit because this is higher up on
the tree so the branches would probably
be a little bit smaller and just put it
into place but make sure you can't see
it inside the tree trunk and then to
rotate this around it just make it a
little bit different i'll just rotate
this maybe bring it kind of down here
and then i can press one to go to vertex
select a to deselect everything z and
move my mouse over we can go into
wireframe
b and box select this area just kind of
rotate it and change
the shape of it a little bit and then
one last thing before we finish the
modeling for this log i do feel like
it's a little bit too long so if you
want to you can just box select an area
in edit mode bring the whole thing back
box select this area and bring it back
just to make the log a little bit less
long alright so now let's do the
materials for our log so i'm going to
click right over here and i'm going to
click on this and i'm going to add the
wood material i'll press z and move my
mouse up to go into rendered mode and
what i want to do is i want to make the
wood that's inside a little bit lighter
because this is kind of the bark of the
wood so it's going to be darker and then
inside i want it to be lighter so to do
this i'm going to tab into edit mode
press 3 to go to the face select and
just alt select some of these so shift
and alt and select these different loops
going all the way around here and then
i'm going to hold down the shift key and
just click on some of these bits right
here because these won't select properly
with the alt key because they have some
things getting in the way so i'm just
going to need to manually shift and
click on these and i'm basically just
selecting all the wood that's darker and
then i will invert the selection and add
the lighter wood and then the branches
here i'll press l and l with my mouse
hovered over them to select them so now
i just have all the outside of the log
so now i can press ctrl i that'll invert
the selection and that's all the stuff
that i want to be the lighter color and
i'll click on the plus here click on new
call it wood
light and then just make it a light wood
color something kind of like that and
then click on a sign now this looks
pretty good but i do actually want this
log to be a bit darker so i'm going to
select this wood right here click on the
plus to duplicate it and i'm going to
call it
log just so that's a separate material
and i can make it a little bit darker so
on the base color i'll just bring this
down
make that a little bit darker that looks
a bit nicer all right so let's go ahead
and model the low poly tree stump now so
i'll press shift a we're going to start
with a circle and then make sure on the
circle settings make sure the vertices
is set to 8. i'm going to scale this
down
bring it over into the center here so
that we can see it a little bit better
tap into edit mode and just make sure
you're in the vertex select by pressing
one and then i'll press f to fill that
now i'm going to press e and z and
extrude this up and then i'll press e
and s scale that out make the thickness
of it and then i'll press e and z
bring it down okay now i need to bring
this object up because
it's a little bit too far down okay
there we go tab in edit mode i'm going
to scale this up a little bit because as
it comes down it's going to get bigger
so e and z
and then s scale that up and then i'm
going to press three to go to the face
select and just select a few points here
just select maybe about five of those
faces and then i'll press e and z
bring them up a little bit and i'll just
slightly scale them up and then i want
to add one of those cracks in there
again because i think that looked pretty
cool on the log so i'm going to press
ctrl r bring a loop cut in there press
ctrl r add another loop cut right there
then i can press one to go to vertex
select just select this and double tap g
push it in click on this one double tap
g push it in and again because we have
that auto merge it's going to merge the
vertices together i think i'll just
select these bring them down a little
bit and then select these vertices bring
them out and these out a little bit i
think i'll bring this one down a little
bit as well
and just pop this one up a little bit so
i'm going to scale this down a bit and
bring it down right onto the plane just
like that and then i'll go to the
material tab and then click on the drop
down menu and start typing in log and
just add in that log material and then
we need to add the roots for the log so
tab and edit mode just find a spot where
i want the roots to come out i want the
root to come out right here so i'll
press three to go to the face select
just select this face and press e to
extrude
and then scale it down a little bit and
rotate it and then e to extrude again
bring it down and just extrude that down
just like that so let's add another root
right here and i want this root to be a
little bit more round so to make it more
round i'm going to press ctrl r just
double click to add that loop cut and
then i can just select this double tap g
move it down a little bit select this
one double tap g move it down a little
bit and then i can just press three to
go to the face select just select these
faces and extrude that out and that way
you can see that the root is going to be
a little bit more round so i'll just
rotate it making sure it's still in the
ground
extrude it down and then extrude it in
just like that okay let's add one more
right here now this one i want to be a
smaller one so i'll press ctrl r just
drop that in there i'll select these two
bring them down to make that a little
bit smaller and then i can press three
to go to the face select select this and
then extrude that out with e and this
one i want to actually come up a little
bit so there's a little bit of an area
underneath the root so i'll extrude that
rotate it and then extrude it down
and into the ground and scale it down a
bit and then if you wanted to make this
root a little bit more round you could
tab into edit mode just alt select one
of these loop cuts and press ctrl b
just add a bevel there and that way
there's going to be a little bit more
geometry and it'll be a bit more smooth
all right so i'm going to call the
modeling good for that now just like the
log i want to make the wood later in
inside so i will tab into edit mode
press 3 to go to the face select and
then select this face and then i'm going
to click plus to add a new material
click on this and start typing in wood
and we want to select the wood light and
then with that selected and the wood
light selected you can press assign and
now it's going to have the lighter wood
now i want to show those wood grains
kind of these circles inside the tree so
i'm going to tab into edit mode and i'm
just going to start by pressing i and
i'll press i and that'll inset the face
you can see that these vertices here are
really close to each other because we
added that cut in there so i'll press 1
to go to the vertex select just select a
vertices and then double tap g and just
move them away from each other double
tap g just give those a little bit more
space and just make sure all the rest
have a bit more space so now that they
have more space i'll press 3 to go to
face select just select this face i can
scale it up a little bit more and then i
can press i and just keep on pressing i
so just keep on doing this and what
we're going to do is we're going to make
every other loop a little bit brighter
now you can see that i have the same
problem here so i'm just going to press
1 to go to vertex select double tap g
double tap g just give that a little bit
more space i can press three again to go
the face select and just keep on
pressing i to inset that and i'm going
to call that good so now what i can do
is press three for face select just hold
down the alt key and select one of these
loops and then just hold down the shift
and alt key and select every other loop
and then just hold down the shift key
and you can select the middle one now
what i want to do is i want to make all
those a little bit brighter so i'll
click on this plus here
click on this type in wood and i'm going
to select the wood light and then i'm
going to click on this kind of file icon
it looks like two pieces of paper click
on that it's going to duplicate it i'm
going to call this wood light 2
and then with that selected i can click
on a sign and nothing will change that's
because it's the same color right now
but this color if i make it brighter you
can now see that it stands out and then
if you wanted to you could also press
three to go to face select and just
select some of these faces in here and
also make them the lighter material
so i'm just gonna select all the
interfaces
just like that click on the wood light
and then click on assign and there we go
there is our finished tree stump so i'll
press 7 for top view move this over
scale it down a little bit and just
place it
right over here just make sure it's
going down into the ground
all right let's go ahead and make the
flowers now so to make the flowers i'm
actually going to start off with adding
a cube so press shift a add a cube
we'll scale this cube down i'm just
going to bring it over here so we can
work with it a little bit better period
on the number pad to zoom into it i'm
going to tab into edit mode and scale it
on the z-axis so s and z
bring that down so what i'm making right
now is one of the flower petals and then
once i've made the petal i'm going to
duplicate it and rotate it around so
that we have petals all around our
flower so i'm going to press 3 to go to
face select select this face and i'll
press g and click with my middle mouse
bring it out and then just scale it up a
little bit more just bring it out a
little bit farther something like that
maybe even a little bit farther and
scale it up a little bit okay i'll press
7 for top view now i'm going to press a
to select everything
g and move it over a bit and then now
that i've made one pedal i want to
duplicate the pedals and make them going
in a circle so i'll press shift d to
duplicate click right there r to rotate
just put it in place like that shift d
again r to rotate make this one right
there shift d again r to rotate bring
this one over here and then shift d
r to rotate
and then we'll add one more just give it
a little bit more space shift d
r and bring it in now you can see that
they're overlapping a little bit i don't
really mind that too much but if you
want to just press l and select some of
these
and just rotate them and kind of give it
a little bit more space there all right
now i want the center to be a little bit
smaller so i'm going to press 1 to go to
vertex z to move my mouse over and then
i'll just deselect everything i'll press
c for the circle select and just select
all of these and then just press s and
scale them down a little bit more all
right and then i want to bring this down
so i'll press g and z
bring it down i'm going to place my 3d
cursor right here and then i'll press
shift a and i'm going to search for
another circle i'll scale this circle
down just make it the size just make it
a little bit bigger so the petals are
kind of coming out of it and then i'll
press g and z bring it down
f to fill a face in there and then i'll
press e and z
just bring that up and then e and s and
then e and s again and then i think the
normals need to be recalculated so i'm
going to double tap a press shift n and
there we go now the normals are
recalculated now on the bottom here i
want to press e and then s
scale that down a little bit and then
i'm going to start to model these stem
so i'll press e and s
make that really small
and then e
and s
so it's going to be thin and then i'm
going to keep on extruding and making it
a little bit thicker as it goes more
towards the ground and then i want to
add some leaves so i'll press shift a
search for a cube
scale this cube down we're just going to
bring it over here
let's scale it down on the z axes
scale it up a little bit on the x
just put it into place i'm going to
press ctrl r right here and add a loop
cut in there and that way we can have if
this will actually go there we go click
right there i can press g and z bring
this down and that way we can have a
curve in the leaf so i want to add a
couple more vertices here so that we can
make the leaf thinner on the edges so
i'll press ctrl r i'm going to scroll up
with my mouse wheel to add two and then
just double tap to place those so now
what i can do is go into wireframe press
b and box select the front here press s
and scale it down and i'm actually going
to squish it all together so s and 0 and
then hit enter and again that auto merge
is going to merge that together alright
so i want to select the other side of
the leaf and scale that down as well but
it's kind of coming through here so i'm
going to press l
to select the entire leaf with my mouse
hovered over it g to move this over and
then z to go into wireframe i'm just
going to
box select this and then e and then s
and then type in 0 and enter just bring
that out a little bit more all right so
the leaf is pretty straight right here
so i'm going to alt select this loop g
and z bring it down and then shift and
alt and select this loop and this loop
and g and z
bring it down so now the leaf is nice
and curved so if i tab into edit mode
now press l with my mouse over the leaf
it'll select the whole thing i can press
s and scale it up and then r to rotate
and just put it into place right there
and i think i'll also bring it up a
little bit
and maybe scale it a little bit bigger
and then i think i'll make another one
so i'll press shift d duplicate it bring
it over
r to rotate you can also double tap r
and that will kind of do the trackball
rotation
and just stick it into place and there
we go we have our first flower modeled
so let's add some materials so i'm going
to click right here and first add the
green material let's go into rendered
mode so we can see what that's looking
like now i want it to be yellow in here
and then out here i want to be random
colors depending on what flower it is
and real quick it looks like something's
wrong with the modeling here you can see
that there is a little bit of space in
there there's a little gap so i can
press three to go to the face select and
then shift select these faces and then i
can press g
and push them in so i need to just
select the area that i want to be yellow
so i'm going to hold down the alt key
select this loop and then hold down the
shift and alt key and select this loop
and then just hold down the shift key
and select this one now i can click on
the plus right here click on new i'm
going to call this material yellow
and then on the base color i'm just
going to make this yellow and then click
on a sign so i want it to be kind of a
yellowy orangey color pretty saturated
okay so now i need to
click on one of the petals press l and
just go around pressing l with my mouse
over the petals to select all of them
i'm going to click on the plus
click on new and i'm going to call this
flowers or petals or whatever you want
to call it and then i'm going to press
on assign and now it's the white flowers
now when i duplicate the flowers i want
them to randomly be different colors so
to do this i'm going to go to the
shading tab
zoom out here and you can see here's our
shader nodes and i need to pan over here
so i can see the flower
okay i'm going to press shift a and i'm
going to add the object info node click
on this drop it over here the random
value i'm going to plug into the base
color so now i need to tell it what
colors are going to be randomly
generated so i'm going to press shift a
search for a color ramp just drop the
color ramp right in here and then you
can see this fades in between the
different colors i don't want to fade in
between the colors i just want there to
be specific colors so instead of linear
i'm going to click right here and turn
it to constant and now there's no fading
in between the colors it's just constant
colors from black to white or whatever
colors we're going to add so now we can
do is just bring this over i want some
of the flowers to be white so i'll just
leave that at white the black here i'm
going to turn this to a red color so
bring it up make it nice and red not
super saturated but pretty saturated and
then i'm just going to actually
duplicate a bunch of flowers just so
that we can see what this is looking
like so press shift d
duplicate a bunch of flowers and you can
see that however much of the color there
is it's more likely that it's going to
be generated as that color so i can just
change this if i want most of them to be
white i could do that i'm just going to
bring this down though okay i'll click
on the plus button add a new one this
one i'm going to make a purpley color
and then again change the size because
the size is going to determine how often
it's going to be that color i'll click
on plus again
move this one over here and then this
one i'm going to have a really bright
yellow color
like that i'll bring these in a little
bit more and then i want to add one more
in here so i'll click on the plus button
and this one i'm going to change to a
pink color and then to make that purple
look a little bit different kind of more
contrasty i'm going to make that purple
a bit darker and a bit more blue so
there we go now if i just duplicate
these you can see they're just randomly
being generated with different colors so
i'm just going to select all these
except one press x and delete them so
this one i need to scale down and let's
just go back into the layout so we have
some more space so i'll scale this down
to the size that i want just place it
down there and then i don't want the
flower to be pointed straight up i kind
of want it to be sagging a little bit so
i'll just have an edit mode
z for wireframe one for vertex select
just box select an area and just rotate
it give it a random rotation just like
that okay let's duplicate this and we
can make some more flowers so this one
here i'm just going to press l and just
select that leaf and press x and delete
vertices and now that just has one leaf
and then i think i'll just give it a
random
rotation so maybe this one's going to be
rotating over like this okay there we go
and then i'll make one more so i'll
click on this shift d bring it over here
that's a purple one and then this one
again just rotate it give it a random
rotation and then this one i want there
to be two leaves but i think i'll change
the position of the leaf so i'll press l
to select all the linked vertices
are to rotate
just rotate it
where you want about like that maybe
rotate it over a bit more scale it down
a little bit and there we go so there is
the finished flowers all right let's
make the low poly rocks now so i'm going
to press shift a
and i'm going to start with an ico
sphere and then on the ecosphere
settings right down here i'm going to
set these to 5 so it's a little bit
higher and that way we can shape the
rocks how we want so i'm just going to
scale it down just press period on the
number pad to zoom into it i'll tap into
edit mode and then i need to press o to
turn on proportional editing and then
i'll press g
and just make the shape of the rock so
just make it however you want rocks are
usually pretty random although i do find
that rocks are usually kind of flat on
the bottom of them so i'm going to make
the bottom of the rock pretty flat where
it's going into the ground and then once
you've made a rock i'll click on the
modifiers right here click on add
modifier and i'm going to add the
decimate modifier just bring the ratio
down until it's at a value that you like
and then i'm going to make four
different rocks so i will bring this one
down a little bit into the ground and
then i'll press shift d click with my
middle mouse wheel bring this over tab
in edit mode i'm just going to
select some points now this rock i think
i want to be a little bit longer or
higher up so i'm going to bring that up
there we go looks very cool
shifty click with my middle mouse wheel
maybe give it a random rotation
this one maybe i'll make a super flat
rock there we go maybe just change the
shape of it a little bit and then i'll
press shift d
bring this over make one more rock just
like that alright so then once you're
happy with the shape of the rock you can
press ctrl a with your mouse over the
modifier and just apply all of the
decimate modifiers let's add a material
to these rocks so i will click on the
materials panel click on new let's go
into rendered view i'm going to call
this material rock and then on the base
color i'll make this a bit gray
and then on the roughness you could turn
it down a little bit if you like that if
you like the look of that you could also
turn it up just a little bit and then to
drop this onto the other rocks i can
just click and drag and drop that on to
the other rocks
and then i'm going to select these rocks
scale them down a little bit and bring
them over to the side now let's model
the grass so to model the grass i'm
going to press shift a and i'm going to
start off with a cube
scale the cube down
bring it over here
just bring it into place i'll tap into
edit mode and scale it down you can see
that it the proportional editing is on
again so i'll turn that off i'll scale
the whole thing down on the x-axis
so that it's a lot thinner and then also
scale it down on the y-axis a bit i'll
press three to go to the face select and
then e to extrude and just start to
extrude out those grass blades now that
grass blade is way too big so i'm going
to scale it a lot more down and then
let's tab back into edit mode scale it
way down now at the very tip here i want
to scale this down to zero so i'll press
s
0 and enter and there we go now the
point is very sharp so that's one grass
blade let's press shifty and duplicate
this bring it over and let's make a few
more so i'm gonna make four different
grass blades and then i'll use those
grass blades to make some bunches of
grass so this next one i think i will
box select it and make it really long
and straight just like that okay
duplicate this again bring it over and
this one i'm going to make it so it's
rotating over a lot and a bit smaller
i'll also add a loop cut in here by
pressing ctrl r double tap to place that
and then just bring that up maybe bring
that down a little bit more and then i'm
going to select this one press shift d
bring it over and i'll just make one
more grass blade this one's going to be
just kind of a basic one just going
straight up maybe it's going to be
waving a little bit so down here it'll
kind of go up and then over to the side
and then back all right so now that we
have these four grass blades i'm going
to click on this
add the green material but grass is
usually a little bit more reflective a
little bit more shiny so i'm going to
click on this to duplicate the material
call it grass and then i'm going to
click and drag just drop the color on to
the other grass blades so now what i can
do is go down to the roughness turn the
roughness down a little bit and now if i
go into rendered mode and look around
the grass will just be a little bit more
reflective so now i want to make some
bunches of grass i'm going to just kind
of rotate these bunch them all up
together put this one in here i'm going
to make four different bunches of grass
and then i can select some pieces of
grass press shift d to duplicate it give
them a random rotation
just have them sticking out just like
that all right so that's going to be my
first clump of grass so what i'm going
to do now is hold down the shift key
just select all the different pieces of
grass and press ctrl j and that'll join
them together and now we have one clump
of grass so i want to make four so this
is going to kind of be a medium sized
one i'll press shift d click with my
middle mouse move over i want to make a
bigger clump of grass so i'll tap into
edit mode just select everything with a
and press shift d
bring this over and then press r and z
and give it a random rotation kind of
have it sticking out
kind of rotate that and then i will
press shift d again rotate that give it
a random rotation and i want a little
bit more of the grass to be curved over
so i can just manually
go into edit mode here just rotate some
of the grass pieces
because i think some of the grass pieces
should be rotated over a bit more all
right and there is my second clump of
grass so now i want to make two more i
want to make one that's really small and
then one's just just a little bit
smaller so i'll press shift d bring this
over duplicate that tab and edit mode
i'm just going to select some random
pieces of grass press l
and just select some of them and then
i'll press x and delete vertices so now
we have a smaller lump of grass and
again i'm just going to play with the
shape a little bit just to make it look
a little bit nicer all right there's my
third piece of grass i'll just make one
more so i'll select this one shift d
click with my middle mouse wheel bring
this over and then this one i just want
to be three pieces of grass so i'll just
press l
and select a couple and press x and
delete them and now i just have a very
small clump of grass and i think i'll
press l to select this one and bring it
in a little bit more there's our grass
looking pretty good now i do want to
play around with the colors a little bit
so i'm going to go back to the shading
tab so i just want to play around with
some of the colors i think i'll make
this a little bit darker this one i
think i'll make a little bit more
saturated and if you wanted to you could
also add some more colors like i'm going
to add a color in here and make this one
a little bit more yellow and generally i
think it would look a little bit better
if the grass were a little bit darker so
i'm just selecting some of these points
and then clicking on the color and
making them a little bit darker so there
we go there is our finished grass clumps
so now let's go ahead and make the
bushes so i'm just going to place my 3d
cursor right here i'll press shift a and
i'm going to add another icosphere now
this psychosphere on the ecosphere
settings i want to turn these
subdivisions all the way down to one so
it's very low poly and then i'll just
scale this down now on the bottom here i
don't want this to be pointed way down i
want it to be kind of flat because it's
just going in the ground so i'll just
select this vertice and make it nice and
flat and then i can just bring the
entire bush up i'll add a new material
and add that green color and then i'll
tab into edit mode select everything
with a and press shift d and just scale
this down and what i'm going gonna do is
make little clumps of bushes around the
big bush so just move these around press
shift d scale them up a little bit just
give them some random scale and just
place them around the main bush all
right there we go now i want to do the
same thing but this time i only want to
have two clumps so i'll press shift d
click with my middle mouse wheel bring
this over
and then i'll tab into edit mode press l
and l to select these and then press x
and delete vertices and then this one i
think i want this one to be a little bit
bigger and then this one maybe just a
little bit smaller maybe give that a
random rotation but there we go there is
our finished low poly bushes and our low
poly acids are really coming together i
do want to make some mushrooms though
and i'm going to make two different
types of mushrooms so i'm going to make
a brown mushroom and a red mushroom so
let's do the brown mushroom first so
i'll press shift a and once again i'm
going to add a circle just make sure the
circle settings is set to 8 and then
we'll scale it way down tap into edit
mode and i'm going to press f to fill
that i'll press 1 to go to side view so
that we can see that a little bit better
and i'll press z and go into wireframe
so now what i can do is just extrude
this with e and s and scale that down
and basically just make the shape of the
stem for the mushroom and i don't want
it to be too thick so maybe make it a
little bit thinner okay i'm going to
press e and s make that a lot bigger and
then just bring that down a little bit
okay i'll press e and s scale that up g
and z bring it up a little bit and then
i'll press e bring that up scale it down
just a little bit and then e
bring that up scale it down we're
basically just making the shape of the
mushroom
and then e and s
and then the face is already filled
right up there so there we go that's
looking pretty good but the stem is
really big so i'm going to press c go
into wireframe just box select the top
here and scale it up and make it a lot
bigger
because right now the stem is way too
big compared to the top of our mushroom
i'm also going to alt select this loop
down here scale it down and then press g
and z and bring it up a bit let's make
the materials for our mushrooms now so
i'll click on new i'm going to call this
stem because this is going to be the
stem of the mushroom and i'm going to
make this
a lighter brown color
and i'm going to turn up the roughness
because i don't want it to be very rough
just something like that and now i'll
tap into edit mode press 3 for the face
select and just alt select some of these
vertices just that we have the top of
the mushroom selected now i'm going to
click on the plus here click on new i'm
going to call this one mushroom and then
click on a sign now this one i want to
be a much darker color not super dark
but definitely darker and then i want to
turn the roughness up quite a bit and
then i want to add a little bit more
vertices in here so i'll tab into edit
mode press 1 for the vertex select and
just alt select this face and i can
press ctrl b add a bevel in there that
way there's just a little bit more
vertices i could also
select these and double tap g and edge
slide them up a bit and then right here
i think i want to add a bevel right here
so i'll alt select this control b just
make a little bevel just like that all
right let's make this mushroom bend over
a little bit so i'll tab in edit mode z
move my mouse over just box select this
and rotate it a little bit g to grab and
then press b for the box select but i'm
going to click with my middle mouse
wheel to deselect that area and then
just rotate that over a little bit okay
looking pretty good i want to duplicate
this and make just a couple more
mushrooms so this mushroom i want it to
be rotated maybe the other way so i can
just rotate that over maybe scale this
one up a bit so that it's a little bit
bigger and then also just rotate it down
a little bit just like that and then one
more mushroom i'm gonna select this one
press shift d click with my middle mouse
bring it over and this one i want the
stem to be a bit thinner and make it a
little bit smaller so i'll scale this
one down tab into edit mode just box
select the stem here and then hold down
alt and shift and select this loop and
i'll scale that down and just make that
really thin and then i can just select
the stem bring it down just make it a
lot longer and then scale this way down
and bring it up a bit and there we go
now we have a small thin mushroom all
right just one more type of mushroom now
i'm gonna make the red mushroom so i'm
going to press shift a and once again
add another circle make sure it has
eight vertices and then scale it down so
we're basically going to be modeling
this the same way but a little bit
different so i'll tab in edit mode here
fill that face we'll go one for front
view go into wireframe and this one i
want to be a bit fatter the stem a bit
fatter so i'll extrude this up scale it
down and i want the stem to again get
smaller as it goes in and then i'm going
to press e to extrude scale that up and
then bring it down a little bit e to
extrude again scale this up and this
mushroom instead of it being a shape
like this i want to be a little bit more
pointy and a little bit more out on the
sides so i'll extrude that up
and then extrude this scale it down
extrude it make it a bit more pointy and
a bit higher up and then extrude that
scale it down and then the face is
already filled okay i'm going to add a
loop cut right in here so ctrl r add a
loop cut and then i'm just going to box
select these vertices right here and
scale them up a little bit box select
these and scale them down a little bit
and i want the tip to be a bit more
pointy so i'll just box like this scale
it down and up a little bit more and
then right down here at the bottom of
the stem i want it to come out a little
bit and then quickly go back in so i'll
tab into edit mode add a loop right here
by pressing ctrl r and then click and
then we'll scale it up and then go into
wireframe box select this area and scale
it down and then this here we need a box
like this and scale it up a little bit
and that way it kind of comes out and
then goes back in right at the end there
let's add the material now so i'm going
to click on this start typing in stem
because we want the stem to be the same
material then i'll tab into edit mode
just box select the top area right here
and i'll click the plus icon click on
new call this red mushroom
and then right here i'll make it pretty
red but a little bit orange not super
saturated but pretty saturated and then
just click on a sign and you can see now
we have a red mushroom now to make those
little white circles on the mushroom i'm
going to go over to the shading tab
we're going to be using a procedural
texture to make those little white dots
on the mushroom so i'll press shift a
i'm going to search for the veroni if i
can spell it right veroni texture and
then i'm going to use a feature from the
node wrangler add-on if you don't have
that enabled you can go edit and
preferences
and then right here on the add-ons start
typing in node and you can see there's
the node wrangler just check mark that
and then with the add-on enabled now i
can press ctrl t with the veroni texture
selected and that's going to add this
texture coordinate and mapping now the
object i just want to plug that up to
the vector and that way this froni
texture will be placed on the mushroom a
little bit better so i can now plug this
distance into the base color and you can
see what it's doing now right now the
dots are way too small so i'm going to
bring the scale down and then the dots
are faded way too much so i'll press
shift a search for a color ramp drop the
color ramp right in there and then this
black value and this white value if i
start to push these together you can see
that there's going to be a lot more
contrast and then the white i'm going to
make that red color so just change it
back to that red color right there and
then this black color i'm going to make
the white so just bring that up and
there we go now i think i want the scale
to be
a bit bigger just like that and then if
you want there to be less dots you can
bring these both back and you can see
there's a lot less dots now sometimes
instead of having circles these
mushrooms have some sort of square type
shapes and if you want to look like that
you can change this bottom value here to
manhattan and now you can see it has
these little kind of square rectangle
type things and if you like that better
then you can leave that setting on i'm
just going to change it back to the top
one here and then for some reason the
dots aren't really where you want
right over here on the location z you
can turn this and that's going to just
change the dots and you can just change
it to something that looks nice to you
alright we're almost done here i'm just
going to duplicate these and again just
like the other mushrooms tab into edit
mode and just box select the top of the
mushrooms and give it a random rotation
i'll just maybe make this one a little
bit smaller as well and then i'll make
one more mushroom by pressing shift d
let me go back into the layout so i have
a bit more space and then this one i
think i want to be a bit fatter so i'll
tab into edit mode select the whole
thing and press s and z
and bring that mushroom down and then
scale it out so it's a bit more of a
fatter mushroom and then this last one
here i will beat a box like this and
just give it a random rotation and there
we go look at that our nature assets are
finally done now just a couple things
that i want to do before we end one
thing that i want to do is press shift a
and i'm going to add a sunlight i'm just
going to bring this sunlight up rotate
it over a bit and then i can make the
strength a little bit brighter and then
the color here i'm just going to make it
slightly yellow so that it looks like
sunlight and then one last thing that
i'm going to do because i'm using ev i
want to make it look a little bit more
realistic so i want to bake some of the
lighting and that way it will look more
realistic so i'm going to press shift a
and i'm going to go down here to light
probe and i'm going to click on the
irradiance volume and what i can do is i
can use this to bake the lighting and
make it look a bit more realistic so i'm
just going to scale this and just make
it so these little dots here are where
the nature assets are just about like
this maybe scale it down a little bit
and then what i'm going to do is click
over here
to this rendering tab go down here and
there's this indirect lighting if i turn
this on and then click on bake indirect
lighting you can see that it just makes
the lighting look a bit more realistic
i'll save this project again and then if
i click on this it'll hide everything
else from the view and i'll press ctrl
spacebar to look at the finished assets
so there we go there is the low poly
nature asset tutorial if you make
something cool with these nature assets
you can definitely leave me a link in
the video description to your artwork
i'd love to see what you guys create
with your nature assets but with that
said thank you so much for watching and
i will see you in a future video