welcome my name is esther from passion
also known as infensia you might have
seen my 10 minutes build before for
example where i made 10 cars in 10
minutes or
maybe a rigged dragon or a rigged pirate
or a star destroyer i've had quite a few
comments from my 10 minute modeling
challenge where people say well this is
too fast for me to learn from this is
not a good tutorial
and i wanted to make this video to
really cover everything that i know at a
slow enough pace
so for those of you who thinks that 10
minute modeling is too fast and you
don't
have a clue what i'm going on about
hopefully this video will give you a lot
of insight and details
in a step-by-step fashion so we could
help you out in your modeling skills
you could even start using this tutorial
if you're brand new to blender because
i'm going to go through everything in
detail
if you're experienced in blender maybe
this first few minutes won't be so
necessary for you to watch but you
should be able to pick up a few tips
because i've found
a lot even though i've done this for
quite a few years i find out stuff all
the time about new nifty ways to do
things so maybe you'll find something
out of this video too
you navigate just press the middle mouse
button to rotate
you hold the shift key and the middle
mouse button to pan around in a scene
and you use the scroll wheel to zoom in
and out there's also a few shortcuts
that you should know in the viewport and
on the keypad you can press 1
to see the front view press 3 to get a
side view
and 7 to get a top view you can also
toggle between
orthographic and perspective mode using
5 on the keypad basically that removes
the perspective and that's useful
sometimes to do as well up here you've
got something called the outliner and
this will show you which object you've
got in your scene
and down here is a properties area and
we'll only be using this
spanner looking thing here which is
modifier properties the rest we can
ignore for now
i also like to use the n key to bring
this numbers panel up
in where we can type in details
sometimes in blender we use the left
click to select nowadays it used to be
right click but nowadays it's left
clicking
thank god for that if you use the right
mouse button you get a context menu
up i don't really use that one so much
maybe you'll find use of it but there
are a few things i do if you want to
delete things you press the delete key
and we can get rid of this light here
for example and this
camera we don't need those when we do
modeling if you accidentally delete
something
then you can press ctrl z like in most
programs to bring it back
one of the most common questions that i
get asked is how i colorize my low poly
objects colorizing your objects is
essential to get those low poly
objects look just right i go to the
shading tab and if you go to the
description
you can download this file as well i've
created a palette for you and you can
just drag this png file right into this
section of your shading view material
editor window here you can also download
the
palettes from lowspec.com for example
they've got loads of palettes or you
could create your own ones in
any drawing program like photoshop i use
for example but you can use free ones as
well
and be aware that my textures i do them
in extremely low resolution this one is
only eight by eight pixels because it
saves a lot of
texture space when you do import it into
a game engine
but we need to collect this color node
here to the base color and you can see
that it's really blurry here now and
it's because it's so low resolution so
we also need to change from linear here
to closest and that'll bring make it
crisp and nice i actually use the
uv editing tab to do most of my modeling
because if i zoom in here with the mouse
wheel on the left you can see i've got
quick access now to these colors that
are in that texture if i resize this as
well
now the cube here as you can see is
unfolded onto this texture
and it's basically representing the 3d
cube in 2d texture space
if i use this little drop down here we
can switch the texture and that shows
you exactly how these
uvs are laid out so this front side for
example is
represented right here we've got quick
access now to colorize this object
if i select all of these faces with a
key
and then on the left side here now i
press a and then i scale it down
to zero and then i can press g on the
left side here to move it
g for grab or move g as in move and if i
place it over green here now
the cube becomes green and if i wanted
to change this face color here
i select the face and i press g on the
left side here and i can change that
face
to orange and this is a really fast way
to colorize your low poly objects and
make them look really crisp and clean
don't worry i'll cover the hotkeys as
well about moving and scaling and things
like that in detail this was just to
demonstrate the coloring process
there are a few things that you need to
be aware of when you do this when i
scale down this uv here down to
basically zero as you can see it's just
a little dot when you import these
objects into a game engine like
unity or unreal they might require a uv
layout
to render for example shadows correctly
in unity you can
enable unity to generate a second set of
uvs or you can create a second set of
uvs in blender here we don't need to do
that at this point because
i'm just going to show you the coloring
process but be aware that there might be
some tweaks that you need to do
when you're going to start using these
assets in a game engine
the second most common question i get in
all my comments is
i change my viewport settings a little
bit and people are asking how i get
about to do that so if you use this drop
down here
i often model with shadows enabled and
especially this cavity feature here
and if i change type here to both world
and screen
or as a world in screen i select both
here and i ramp these
up then you get glowing edges onto your
objects
and when you make low poly art for
example like a car or a tree or
something whatever a
character even then having this cavity
enabled can make the
low poly objects really stand out nicely
so i usually do this when i model
you can also use the workbench render to
render objects using the cavity settings
if you want there's one final setting
that i like to recommend and if you use
this drop down again you should enable
this backface
culling feature and that will tell you
if you have faces that are facing the
wrong direction
sometimes you can have a face that's
facing inwards like this one for example
if i go into the cube now you can see
that this face here is facing inwards
and most game engines don't
render the back side of a face you can
enable that but most of the time they
don't render
and in blender if you don't have back
face culling then you won't really be
aware that you have some holes like this
in your mesh so i recommend that you
enable back face calling
that way you can see when something is
broken and you can fix it there's
something called for example
if you press f3 and type in flip normals
then you can flip that back but there
are other ways as well i'll tell you
about that
there's something called object mode in
edit mode in blender
and by default when you come in it's in
object mode and
basically you can click click on an
object and it'll select it here in the
outliner but to edit an object we need
to press
tab on it because that will give us
access to the geometry
and up here you can switch between
vertex
edge and face select you should learn
these hotkeys it's one
two and three to select between those
you could also hold the shift key and
select multiple
i often don't do that because i think
it's a little bit confusing but just be
aware that you can do that if you want
and you can press
a on your keyboard to select everything
and double click a
to deselect everything you can also
press alt a to deselect everything
and you can hold the shift key to select
multiple
and if it works as a toggle so if you
click again on them with shift pressed
it toggles between the selection okay
finally we're going to start editing
this mesh a little bit
so if we're in edit mode here i press 3
to go into
face select mode and i click on a face
and i can press
g now to move it in 3d space it's quite
difficult to play something if you just
press g and move it so you can press
shift space and g to enable this little
gizmo here
and this way you can basically just drag
it like this instead
to place it and then if you drag on one
of these axis it'll really make it easy
to move something up or down or
left or right back and forth pressing
shift space and g all the time is a bit
tedious so you can also use this drop
down up here and enable the
object gizmo move by default so now when
we select something
you'll always have the option to be able
to drag it out like this drag it up
and drag it out one more thing about
movement
is if we press one on the keyboard to
get into vertex select here and i pick
this vertex here if i press
g it'll move it anywhere but if i press
g again
it'll actually slide it it's a sliding
method that's really handy
to do if you want to just slide this
vertex along here or this one
you want to slide it you press g again
and that makes it easy to slide it along
one edge
the next one is scaling so if i select
three on the keyboard and i press this
face here i can press s to scale it
and you can press this one scale it up
and down and when you scale it
if it really moves like this quick it's
because you press scale when you're
right near the center of it so i
recommend that you move your mouse out a
little bit
press scale because then you'll have
more control when you scale it up and
down
also when you scale something if i
select these two faces i hold the shift
key and select both of these and i press
scale you can see that it scales pretty
much the whole cube maybe that's not
always what you want
you can then press period on your
keyboard and by default it's using
medium point which is in the center here
but we'll switch this one to individual
origins
and now when you scale it it just scales
it along
its own individual phase origin here so
maybe that's what you're after sometimes
if it doesn't work the way you want
but let's go back to medium point which
is also common to use
the next hotkey is e to extrude and if i
select this face and i press e to
extrude
basically it just takes that whole face
and it extrudes it up
this is really useful when it comes to
low poly modelling
you can click on any face and press e to
extrude it e to extrude it again
e to extrude e to extrude e to extrude
you can go crazy with this e to extrude
e to extrude
and when you combine this with s to
scale you can quickly start shaping out
objects
so you e to extrude s to scale e to
extrude e to extrude
s to scale and the more you become
comfortable with this method
of just scaling and extruding you'll be
able to create something let's go all
the way back down here
to a small object let's colorize the
whole object i'll press a here
s to scale it to 0 here on the left
the mouse has to be over the uv here to
scale this uv
2d space here to zero i press g to move
it let's move it back to a gray color
here
so recolor the whole object now to gray
and let's say i just wanted to create
something like
a skyscraper or something then basically
if i just
what we've learned so far let's move
these out a little bit
and then here let's select this one drag
it up a little bit
and now press e to extrude s to scale it
down
e to extrude again e to extrude s to
scale e to extrude
e to extrude s to scale and then we
could just narrow it off here
e to extrude s to scale e to extrude s
to scale e to extrude
let's make a little ball here e to
extrude s to scale e to extrude
that's the scale you can also type in
values if you wanted to scale this
infinitely down
you can type zero now and that basically
scales this phase now
that we learned before down to zero and
now we've created something that could
be turned into a skyscraper by just
extruding and scaling and moving a
little bit let's say we selected a few
of these faces now like this
there's also some tricks with extrusion
here and if i were to press e to extrude
now you can see that it just
doesn't really know what to do it just
slides it up and
basically nothing really happened there
so let's press ctrl z and try that again
and this time we press
alt e instead and then we do extrude
faces along normals and now magically it
just expands
outwards the normal of a face is a line
that faces
perpendicular to the surface of the
object and by using extrude along
normals it takes each face and goes oh
my normal is this way well my normal is
this way mineral is this way and mine
and then it extrudes it that way instead
there was another thing we spotted and
that's if you do alt
e again and then you do extrude
individual
faces and now suddenly it takes all four
of those faces and extrudes them
individually
also really good now if we scale it
remember now we've got the medium point
which is why it scales it down
so if you wanted to get rid of that
remember we press period and switch to
individual origins
and now when i press scale it scales
those down this would be a really
strange skyscraper
so we're not going to make a skyscraper
out of this one there is one more method
that you can use to extrude
and if you select any face here i press
three on the keyboard into face select
and i
get this face here i can hold the ctrl
key down and right click
and that'll extrude it automatically to
that location just hold the ctrl key
and right click and that'll follow along
one good thing to keep in mind here is
if i
select this face here and i press one on
the keypad to go into front view
now if i hold the ctrl key and right
click i know that everything will be
aligned
perfectly let's rotate with the middle
mouse button you can see that
and we can even go to the side view here
you can see that it's perfectly straight
this one behind
be aware though that when you do this
method you can
so you don't go too sharp if i were to
go too sharp here
then you can see we have this back face
problem that we described before
let's cancel out of this one controls
that a whole bunch of times so we go
back to here
there's another hotkey that's really
useful and that's to rotate things and r
is the hotkey for that so if you just
press
r on a face here you can see that you
can twist it
here i'll select this one r to rotate it
and
if i have multiple ones selected here
and press r
it'll rotate it you can combine r to
rotate so if if we select this one and
you do e to extrude
and you press r to rotate e to extrude r
to rotate e to extrude
or to rotate this is also quite useful
you can also rotate around a fixed axis
so if i select this face i press e to
extrude it
and then i press r to rotate it this
also works for moving and scaling things
but if i press the keyboard now to
represent one of the axes like
y for example to represent the green y
axis you can see that it created a
guideline here
and now it forces rotation around that
axis if i were to
switch to x it'll rotate around the
x-axis and if i press
z it'll rotate around the z axis and
this is a really useful way
to force rotations if you want to do it
around one axis
also when you rotate you can type in the
amount that you want to rotate if i
press r to rotate
i press y to rotate it around the y axis
and then i just
let go of the mouse now and i type 90.
then it twists that face but be aware
you don't want to rotate that much
because it breaks the geometry so if we
redo that one
r to rotate y on the y axis and then
type in
45 degrees okay another useful hotkey
for hard surface modeling is
eye to inset so if i select this face
and i press i to inset you can see that
it just creates an
inset face here and if i wanted to
now we could extrude that one for
example and you can also after you do i
to inset
you can also extrude downwards to sync
into the object
i to inset b to extrude s to scale
e to extrude i to inset e to extrude
and you could create like a sci-fi
skyscraper or a building
really fast doing this method so
remember we've got
g to move s to scale
e to extrude i to inset and these keys
are
lethal when it comes to low poly
modeling so you should really get the
hang of those
do it as much as possible when it comes
to in setting as well
let's say you select multiple faces like
these i hold the shift key to select
multiple one
if i press i to inset now you can see
that it creates
one single insert for all of these faces
quite often this is the way you want it
like let's say we wanted to extrude that
could be quite common maybe you have a
building complex or a
pentagon or something like that then you
want to do that
but sometimes when you do i to inset you
can press i
again and that makes individual
insetting
and if you extrude those then suddenly
you've created individual faces
delete this one now i'll do shift a and
create a new cube so we're back to where
we started
let's say we wanted to make a skyscraper
out of this one now i do go tab into
edit mode
maybe slide this one up let's press
these two
with the shift key scale and then i
press x to scale it on the x axis
here let's move this one up a little bit
e to extrude s to scale e to extrude e
to extrude
s to scale e to extrude e to extrude s
to scale e to extrude
e to extrude s to scale let's say we
just have it like this now instead
now you could create for example if you
wanted to expand here e to extrude
b to extrude e to extrude
e to extrude and remember with inset now
as well
if i select a few of these faces i to
inset
and i've already got individual you can
see at the top there individual is on
so you toggle with the i again if you
wanted to just inset it like this
and you can inset it again and s to
scale it you can start creating a lot of
details on your objects by doing it this
way
and here let's say we wanted to create
an indentation for
something that could look like a roof i
hold the shift key and select these two
faces
press i to inset e to extrude it down
select these two with the shift key i to
inset and e to extrude it down
so now we're starting to be able to
model maybe a sci-fi city really fast
this way i also want to show if you've
got
the mirror modifier on this is another
question i get a lot a lot
and you press i to inset sometimes you
want
this center face here not to appear and
there's a hotkey for that
and if you press i to inset and then you
press b on your keyboard
it'll magically remove that one if
you're using the mirror modifier we're
going to cover the mirror modifier later
on
just so you know now though that b is
the hotkey for boundary
and that way you'll get rid of that
center face if
b doesn't work for you like this it
could be because you've selected
individual faces
so if i have these two selected i do i
to inset
i to inset again now suddenly i do it in
set and then i want to do
b it doesn't work and no matter how hard
you press b
it won't work and that's because you've
got individual on so toggle off
individual first
and now b works so just a little side
note
one more thing that's useful is
proportional editing and that's a little
thing up here
you can press o which is a hotkey for
proportional editing
you should really learn these hotkeys by
the way they'll save you a lot of time
but you can also press up here
and now when i press g you can see i've
got a little circle around here and you
can use the scroll wheel now to change
the circle
and this way we can proportionally edit
the whole object here which is really
useful maybe not for a skyscraper but
there will be many times
especially if i want to make some let's
say you had a little building and you
wanted to make some more character on it
or you were creating an
island and you want to drag up the
surface or you're creating stones or
something like that
you can switch up here from different uh
the default one here is smooth you could
also do random for example
and now when you move it'll start moving
things randomly so that's also very
useful
let's put this a little bit to the test
now if i hide that one i
do shift a to add a new cube here and
let's start fresh
i'd like to go in fresh let's say you
want to make a crate now let's make an
actual object
that we could be proud of when i create
a new object
often you have to go back into the
shading tab by the way and then
when the object is selected you switch
back to material if it disappears you
know why
it's because when you create a new
object it won't have that material by
default
now let's see what we've learned we
press tab into edit mode
a just make sure a to select everything
here on the left side here i press a
scale 0 and enter
and i press g here to move these uvs
it's called
to here to make a brown box like a wood
box
i press three on the keyboard now and
now i've got
face select that's what we switched to
with three here now we press i to inset
and we had individual on from before
normally you'd probably get to this
where nothing is happening
but when you press i again to switch on
individual
you get this magic here and then
remember what we learned something else
we did
alt e to extrude along face normals
and i drag it in a little bit and now
we've already created something that
looks a little bit like a crate
a box that brings us to another
technique that we could do and
if i select i press two on the keyboard
and i hold the shift
key to multiple select these edges here
now here's another thing
ctrl b is bevel and if i press that and
drag a little bit
it bevels the edges that i selected
there is also a way to do if i select
these at the bottom here i hold the
shift key
ctrl b to bevel if you expand this
little one at the bottom here
you could actually increase the number
of segments
if you wanted it to be rounder when
doing low poly i rarely use that but
it's good to know that you could
actually have more
levels to this if you wanted to there's
also something called shrink and flatten
if i press three to get into uh face
selector i select these faces
and then i do alt s to shrink and
flatten
that's another method that you could do
we've got actually proportional editing
on random here now which is why it
turned out a little bit weird so let's
deselect and do alt
s and this basically shrinks and
flattens these faces that i do it's
different from scale because if i press
s to scale it'll scale those faces only
but if i do alt
s it'll take and shrink and flatten the
whole mesh if i do it inwards it'll
shrink it i've already mentioned it a
few times but
you can also create additional geometry
so i've got this cube here
selected and then if i do shift a when
i've
when i'm in edit mode remember i do
shift a then i can add a cube
and i'm still in the same object here
but we've got
additional geometry this is why it's
already colored because we're in the
same object now
but we've got more geometry more mesh
data in here if i do shift a
again i could add an icosphere for
example and let's move that one to the
side
often when i model even if i do an
entire island or a car or
with loads of different parts i often
model it in the same object
but i have these different meshes and
when you press shift a
it'll create the geometry wherever this
3d cursor is i haven't really mentioned
this 3d cursor it's just been sitting
there in the center all the time you can
place that one by
holding shift and right clicking
somewhere and that'll move this cursor
if you click on an object it'll actually
figure out that you wanted it on that
surface
so when you add something let's shift
right click there
and then i do shift a and i add another
cube it'll place the center of that cube
right there sometimes you want to have
really specific control of where you
place this cursor so if i want it to be
right in the center of this face here i
have face select on here which is three
on the keyboard then you can press
shift s and do cursor to selected
and that'll place that cursor right
there and i often use that to place it
exactly where i want it
before i do a shift a and maybe i wanted
to add a cone there
also when you add stuff like this like
the icosphere for example let's create a
new icosphere
shift right click over here shift a
let's create
an ico sphere then you have often when
you create something you have the for
example subdivisions here you can
step this up if you want more or less
detail and if you don't see this one
it's probably because it's collapsed
down here so you have to click on this
expansion thing
now we can use what we've learned let's
delete everything that we've done so far
this building gone if you want to
re-center this 3d cursor to the center
you can press
shift c to re-center it down here in
this scene let's
shift a add a cube we're going to make a
tree now
so i tab into edit mode or first we need
to go into the shading tab because this
time we created a whole new object so we
lost this material setting so i
switch back to the material go back into
this uv editing here
let's do a on the left side scale 0
press enter g to move this little dot
here as well
onto brown and now let's create a tree
how we learned we scale this down a
little bit
maybe i view a little bit from the side
i press control and i right click
s to scale ctrl to right click s to
scale control to right click
s to scale g to move it if you want
purposely i made a small step here
because now when i select a side face
here i can press
either e to extrude it or i can look
from the side here and control
right click and then s to scale it to
extrude that one
you can even do two branches at the same
time with what we've learned if i select
a shift select these two and i do alt e
and extrude individual faces and s to
scale them
and remember if you don't want it to
scale down towards the medium point here
in the center
you press period and you go to
individual origins and then you try
scaling again
and when you have these two phases
selected you can actually move them up
at the same time you could press r to
rotate them together
and you could press alt e to extrude
this time we'll do along face normals
and g to move it up so now we've created
a basic stem of a tree
and then i wanted to create some leaves
here as well and we've learned
most of that as well so if i shift and
right click at the tip here of that face
it placed my 3d cursor up here and then
we do
shift a because we want to we're still
in this object remember now
but i do shift a and let's add that ico
sphere again
and we can play around with how many
subdivisions we want but let's keep it
low poly looking so we'll keep it at two
and then i can press
s to scale this whole thing up now and
here's the beauty thing that we learned
before about
quick colorization now if i go to the
left side here hover with the mouse
press a to select everything here s to
scale it
and 0 press enter and then
still over here g to move it and move it
to green
now we're coming to a really important
method when we want to select something
since we're in this same
cube object here but we've got two sets
of geometries we've got the tree trunk
and we've got this ball of leaves here
instead of selecting all of this
individually with shift now
there's an extremely extremely extremely
useful thing you should definitely learn
this one
and that's the l hotkey if i hover the
mouse
over this ball of leaves and then i
press l
it'll magically select all of those and
that that's
select linked since all of these
vertices are connected to each other
if i press one on the keyboard you can
see all of these have
lines connecting to each other but none
of them have any lines that connect or
vertices that connect to this tree trunk
and that's how blender will know that if
you press l while hovering over one of
these
it'll select all of these and as i said
i often model in
the same object here but with multiple
features like on the tree here for
example
and this is by far the most effective
way i've
found to uh to quickly model things in
the same object
that'll bring us to another hotkey and
that's shift d to duplicate things
because
we want to have a ball of leaves here
and here as well and now if i press
shift d i can duplicate this and it'll
follow my mouse now and we can try to
place it a little bit here
but sometimes we have to tweak a little
bit but let's place it there
and we can use this gizmo remember we
enabled that one up here so it's
permanent
we up here we've got the move object
gizmo
so we can move it just along these
axises here to make sure that it's
pretty good and then again shift d we
move it to here
okay we need to align it a little bit so
let's move it into place
like that and now we could press l
to select these and if i press l over
that one it'll add that one
and l over that one and now you can also
you can actually press shift
l to deselect that works the opposite
way
and if i press l here now and s to scale
it
r to rotate here i press l to select it
s to scale it r to rotate just randomize
it a little bit l to select it
s to scale it and r to rotate remember
we also learned this
proportional thing that was quite useful
so we press o
or click up here o toggles the
proportional editing
and if i select this vertex now and
press g
you can see that i can move this and it
proportionally edits the tree trino so
remember
you can use the scroll wheel now to
scroll this in and out
and see how much it should affect and
here we see something that when i scale
this one up it starts dragging the tree
branches or the tree trunk as well
sometimes you don't want that and with
proportional there's something called
connected if we click on this one again
you can select connected only here and
that's pretty similar to how
l uses to select things now when we do g
to move it and you see that there's a
hollow point here in the center and that
means that it will only affect
the vertices that are linked together so
that are not connected
so if you just wanted to change this
ball of leaves and nothing else
then you can use that method so let's
use this one to g to move it
g to move it and now remember you could
also toggle here to random
and that's becoming quite useful because
now when we drag it it'll do a little
bit random
be careful so you don't move it too far
so you start breaking the geometry you
see you have some overlapping
lines here so ctrl z you'll have to
avoid that at all times you don't ever
want
intersecting lines like that you can
also do proportional editing with
r to rotate and then remember you could
press z
to lock it on the z scale here and then
scroll down with the scroll wheel
you can add some twists to the trees
here as well
archer rotates
or to rotate and set sometimes you still
want to have if you do alt o is the
hotkey for this connected thing if you
still wanted it to affect the tree trunk
again
then g to move it and you could totally
reshape this tree
all together
now we're going to deep dive into some
more selection methods because
we've learned some of the basic modeling
techniques now so i'd say
most important of all in addition to the
modeling techniques
is the different selection methods
because you're going to be spending a
lot of time selecting and deselecting
things
in order to do some operations on them
in fact you'll save immense
insane incredible amounts of time by
learning these different selection
methods
when you do low poly modeling everything
is about to finding a quick selection
method to select what you want and
figuring out the right operation to
modify those selections
either to extrude or scale or modify
them flatten them or something like that
so a few things we already did l to
select the linked
very useful we know how to already click
on things like this
and holding shift to click on them to
select and toggle multiple selections
the next thing i want to show you is
loop select and if i go into
face select here which is three on the
keyboard i can hold the alt key now
which is a loop select
and i click on this edge here and now
it's selected everything around here so
instead of having to click here
and holding the shift key and rotating
around instead of doing that
hold the alt key and just click on one
of these edges in between
and that loops selects around and that
also works in this direction
it selects the whole loop around the
tree here another method
is to press c for circle select
and that brings this little circle up
that you can change the size of with the
scroll wheel
and then basically just paint over which
ones you want to select
and then you press the middle mouse
button if you want to deselect things so
you could just paint a little bit there
paint a little bit there
paint a little bit there oop maybe not
that so you press the middle mouse
button
and then you have to remember that when
you're finished with this you press
enter
and then that selection is remembered
for you so if you wanted to do
something like extrude that for example
e to extrude it or s to scale it now
we've got proportional that's why it's
do not let's disable that
scale it so circle select is very useful
as well
in edge mode you can also do something
called ring select
and if i go here i have two pressed or
go into edge select
and then i do alt control and i click on
one of these
it selects the ring around these you can
also do
loop select which is alt and click on
that one
and that selects the loop round you can
also use the control key
to select the shortest path to something
if i have
edge select here i press two to make
sure i'm in edge select and i select
that edge
and then i select an edge over here and
i press ctrl it'll select the shortest
path
to that one here i select this one
control
and select so shortest path also very
useful another one i use a lot is box
select
so if i go into one here to see the
vertex mode
double click a to deselect everything
press b on the keyboard to box select
things
really fast way to get and see that it
doesn't pick the back faces here
if you wanted to include all the back
purchases i do that quite often
i'll double click a maybe i'll go into
front view
with one on the keypad and then i press
alt z to enable x-ray
and now when i press b to box select and
i slice
something like that for example then you
can toggle back from alt set
and now it's selected all of those
vertices around there so maybe you
wanted to just select those to do
maybe you wanted to g to move them up or
e to extrude them and has to scale them
down
for whatever reason b to box select is
very useful that's very useful
especially from an orthographic
side view like this where you really
want to select if you had a
like an island for example with loads of
vertices across the ground
then it's useful to use that method
another one useful is
lasso select again if i do alt z
to see through here the x-ray double
click a to make sure everything is
deselected
now i hold the control key and i use the
right mouse button to draw around here
this is lasso select if you want it to
really be precise like this
well i do it often and quite fast like
this as well even if you wanted to just
select a few regions if i double click a
here
alt z you can use ctrl right click
to just lasso select a few of these
vertices if you wanted to
just select a few of them another useful
one is to grow and shrink your selection
if i press 3 on the keypad i select
maybe i select that face alone if i
press
ctrl plus on the keypad now it'll grow
that selection by
everything that's enabling that
selection if i press ctrl plus again
it'll expand it again
this is a quick method let's say i
wanted to select i hold the shift key
select a few of these top ones
ctrl plus a few times and now we've
magically selected all the top
parts here if i wanted to e to extrude
it or maybe s to scale it
e to extrude it maybe i wanted to create
snow cap here
like this yeah that's very useful to
grow and shrink
the selection oh wait i said shrink
selection now because you can equally do
control minus here to shrink it so
control plus expands it and control
minus shrinks it
since we're on the topic of selection
here's another tip you can select the
random stuff as well
so if we double click a nothing is
selected i go to select here
and then select random it selects a
random number of faces
and here you can increase and decrease
the number of percent of randomness that
you want maybe you only wanted a quarter
of them selected or maybe you wanted
75 selected another thing we can do is
select similar ones
so if i select this one and do shift g
we can select similar faces let's do for
example polygon sites now it's selected
everything that had
three three edges to the polygon so it
didn't select anything on the tree trunk
because that's
got more four it's uh four edges
we could also do shift g we have to have
one selected by the way
at least before you press shift g for
the similar one
maybe we wanted to do normal okay
nothing was selected
so maybe we increased this threshold and
now we can see that it's selected faces
that were facing this one
so again if we wanted to do the snow cap
i could just select one face here
press shift g normal and then use the
slider here for the threshold to say
okay that's how much we want to be snow
covered now it also picked some of this
tree trunk here as well but maybe we
wanted
something there i do alt e extrude along
phase normals
and let's say we also see that didn't
actually when we extruded now we didn't
have this edge selected but we want this
to be snow as well
then remember here's where control plus
is really useful now it added that
it expanded the selection to include all
the neighboring ones
and then here on the left now you can
see that it's combined we've got some
faces that are brown
and some that are green so to fix that
one we can do a quick operation on the
left here
so while the mouse is over here on the
left press
s to scale it while they're selected and
then zero
and now it shrunk it down to yellow
because that was the medium point here
but i can press
g to move it to white and now we've snow
covered everything
that was similar facing to what we
selected before
so play around with shift g and you can
select different things here try to find
methods that work there's also something
called checker deselect which is useful
if i press l here to select all of these
linked ones and then i do f3
and i type in checker deselect then you
can see that it
deselected pretty much every other one
so maybe if you're doing like a castle
wall or something with
all these little firing holes or if
you're doing a kitchen floor or
something like that
check your deselect will be able to uh
to do that really quickly
one more thing when it comes to
selecting and deselecting things it
sometimes is a bit tricky to see
so i want to show you how to hide and
show things so if i press l to select
all of these
leaves here and then i press h on the
keyboard then it hides those
but they're still here if i tap out of
edit mode you can see that it's still in
the object
but while we're in edit mode here with
tab they're gone and now you could do
stuff like
here you could fix and maybe you wanted
to tweak this one maybe you wanted to
rotate this one a little bit or
say maybe it was a bit too wonky there
so we fixed that one maybe we wanted to
extrude it a little bit more there
do some final tweaks and now to bring
the geometry back that's hidden you do
alt
h and that brings it back you can also
do this for
certain faces let's say you only wanted
to hide these faces here so i hold the
shift key
and then i press h to hide that because
sometimes you want to be able to see
stuff especially if you in old z with
x-ray here sometimes you want to hide
some geometry and then you can always
bring it back with alt
h when you're done i do this very much
if i model cars for example and i want
to
hide a bunch of cars that are in the
same object i just hide them
h key out of sight out of mind and then
i bring it back with alt h again
okay now we're going to go into some
more mesh editing details here this is
fun stuff so
don't snooze off on me now let's hide
this tree i press h to hide the whole
object this time
let's add a new one we want to bring
this 3d cursor back so shift
c to bring it back into the center here
let's revisit that crate that we did
before
so we do shift a we add a cube and
remember
we added a new object now let's double
click on it and name it
create this time since it's a new object
here i could have to go back to the
shading tab while it's selected
click this little drop down here and
select the material again and here's our
colors back
remember we do on the left side here a
scale
0 and then g to move the colors
back here and we're going to repeat what
we did before now i'm going to do
i to inset and remember we still have
individual on
if it looks like this for you just press
i again and then alt e
to bring these faces in here let's say
we wanted to create some planks now here
we can do control r to do a loop cut and
we can use the scroll wheel
to scroll up and down the number of loop
cuts we should have
and when i press the left mouse button
now it also offers us to place it
somewhere
but i want it to be in the center now so
i just right click and it'll snap it
back into center
and just like that we've created a bunch
of loop cuts and it's extremely useful
to do loop cuts
i do it all the time if you wanted to
not have these to be wonky like this
you could hold the alt key and remember
we learned how to select all the way
around like this like a loop
and then we learned how to press s to
scale
but we don't want to shrink it like this
but we also learned that we can press
z on the keyboard to only scale it in
one direction and we also
know that we can type in zero and so
just like that we've actually flattened
this whole thing if we wanted to do that
for all of them
just hold the alt key select scale zero
we can probably do it for these at the
same time if i do alt here and then i
have to hold the shift key and alt to
select this one as well
but now if i press scale z and now
because we have individual origin here
on on period selected
now when we do scale z 0 we flattened
those as well
if i'll just control that out of that
one and i'll do period
if you're on medium point and you press
s to scale z and then zero
it actually brings it into the center
like this so
what you want to do these if you want to
flatten them is that you want to be in
individual origins here on period scale
set
zero and now we've flattened those okay
what more did we learn we learned that
we can select uh
we can press three on the keyboard to
get this face select and we can hold the
shift key and select multiple faces and
we can extrude these in
and i can select two more here e to
extrude those in
and we'll select two more here as well
and we can actually do this at the same
time so select those and do alt t
extrude long phase normals got a few
more planks there so now we've started
to create some
low poly planks in our objects let's add
some loop cuffs here as well ctrl r
scroll it up with a wheel maybe to same
amount of planks
right click to snap them back i've got
individual origins here on period
set so i can do scale but this time
we're going to scale it on the x-axis
the red one and then zero and that
flattened all of those as well
and i press three on the keyboard to go
into face select and i select a whole
bunch of these planks here on the top
and the bottom
like this alt e extrude long face
normals
and now we've created some more planks
that brings us to another one that's
quite useful
and that's k which is the knife tool it
doesn't matter if it's like this as well
see that this one i didn't extrude that
one you can extrude that one manually a
little bit like this if you wanted to
you don't have to be so uniform with
everything but let's select a few of
these as well hold the shift key
e to extrude that one in so let's bring
out the knife tool we press
k on the keyboard get this little green
dot and a knife and then we can start
slicing stuff
so let's just click here on the edges
and let's create something that is
shaped a little bit like
the texture of wood so k here we can
even begin in the center here
go here there let's make some
interesting shape here
maybe like this we can do like another
loop down there to there
to there and then k let's do one here as
well we can even begin in the center of
the face here and just slice it like
this
and see that it added two lines here
because it can't exist a phase within a
phase without connecting edges
so it actually added these little lines
here for me as well automatically
okay let's do another one here okay
here as well
and now if i go three to get make sure
i'm in face select i hold the shift key
and i select these ones that i created
now on the left side here we're still on
the same brown but if press g
now i can move the color of this to
maybe a darker brown
and if i tap out of edit mode we've
started to create some colors for this
and here's where i mentioned before that
doing this method could add a lot of
geometry or it will add a lot of
geometry to your meshes so you have to
be aware if it becomes too many polygons
maybe it'll affect your performance in
that case it could be better to
to do a texture map but again i like to
keep this crisp look
and for my purposes often it doesn't add
so many polygons that becomes a problem
because
pcs especially they're used to handling
millions of polygons
so these extra few aren't going to be a
problem if we reselect these now
you can even do an extrusion here to get
this even more detailed
so let's select those again and press
just b to extrude them in a little bit
and that added some texture and tab out
and this is what it suddenly looks like
you can also do someone that are
brighter so if i press k here
slice a little bit there maybe something
here as well
three to select the faces here and then
g
and let's move it to a brighter one and
let's move those out so e to extrude out
a little bit
tab out of object mode there so we can
see it there's something called the
topology
of meshes as well and this is breaking a
few of the rules
and i'll probably get some a few
comments about this because
when you're modeling characters and
things like that you should really avoid
to do what i just did here
with creating basically meshes that are
have vertices that are in the middle of
a face here
because especially if you animate
objects like a body or something like
that where you're bending limbs
it'll look really weird if i were to
move this vertex out now you can see
that it looks totally broken
so that's something you have to be aware
of but i don't want to rule out this
method to do stuff because it's really
useful if you have
static objects like a crate for example
or like a stone or whatever it is
then it's not really a problem i'd say
you could use it i use it all the time
so if i wanted to add some character to
this box now we could
select the face here and then press g to
move it
or o to enable proportional editing g to
scroll the scroll wheel down and then we
can start making some
some shapes to this object we haven't
colorized this part here but let's move
that one down
just be aware though that when you've
used this method to colorize object or
make some details then you have to be
really careful with the proportional
editing because it could really easily
break here if i press
if i have proportional editing enabled
there i press g to move it
you can see that we run into problems so
that's something you that you need to be
aware of the knife tool as i mentioned
as well it's got a few more tricks up
its sleeve
and if i tab into edit mode again i
press k to go to the knife tool
sometimes you want to make sure that
you're in the center here and you can
just hold the ctrl key and it'll snap
you to the center so then you know that
you snap from one edge to the other
there
and then press enter so that's a good
thing about the knife tool
another one is the the angle constraint
so if i press k on the knife tool
i press there and then i press c then i
can angle constraint it to
an axis here which could also be useful
okay that was our crate let's hide that
one for a second and
let's do shift a now to create a new
mesh a cube
and let's bring the shading here we need
to switch the material back here as we
did before
go back here a on the left side scale
zero
enter g to move it to gray let's make a
stone this time
now we're going to do something called
subdivision surface if i have this
object selected now i have to be out of
not in this edit mode but out here in
the object mode
and then i can press ctrl between 1 and
5.
if i press ctrl 2 here it applies a
modifier called the subdivision modifier
and basically that just takes an object
and adds geometry and smooths out the
edges so this cube nearly became a
perfect sphere now suddenly if i were to
press ctrl
1 instead it would have been the same as
having one level here
and if i were to press ctrl 3 it would
have or 4 it would have added a lot more
detail here
if i wanted to make a stone here let's
go back here and press ctrl
2. i have to enable my screencast keys
again so you can see and now let's apply
this modifier it's in this
wrench tool thing here we apply this
modifier because otherwise
this is actually still a cube here but
this modifier when it's enabled shows it
the way the result should be but we want
to actually apply this one all together
now and now it's
applied this modifier and transform this
so this is actually a
instead of a cube now it's a subdivided
cube that rounded it off like this
subdivision is really useful you can use
it when you make characters you can make
them
from blocky to really round and smooth
and if i
uh let's say we wanted to model a stone
here now in fact let's control z
and even apply more of a modifier here
let's go back all the way to the cube
here
control four let's make it really
detailed like this and then apply this
one
tab into edit mode one into vertex mode
and then we have proportional editing
very important here
remember the o key and then g to move it
and now we can start squashing the stone
so g to move let's just take some
different maybe we want it flat at the
bottom so i pick a
vertex down here g to move it up scroll
wheel to round it off
and this is not so low poly anymore as
you can see but that's okay we're going
to make it back into low poly
so let's just use the scroll wheel and
proportional editing to get some
interesting shapes to the stone here
like this maybe
there and maybe some more shapes like
that
now we've got something but we still
want to bring it down now again so that
brings us
in another modifier and that's we can
apply this one called
decimate that we just did for the box
before as well so we
click on decimate and we have to be in
object mode now so not in edit mode
and then i bring this ratio down on the
slider you could also type in something
but now we've decimated geometry down
back into low poly so the combination of
subdividing objects adding details so
you can reshape them and then using
decimate
to decimate them again can really get
some interesting low poly results for
you so keep that in mind
subdivide modify and then decimate
working on this rock now as well we can
turn it into more of a stylistic rock
here as well with something called
flatten if i tab into edit mode i press
three to go into face
select we could use anything here but
let's do c to circle select a few faces
here
like that press enter now i can press
f3 here and type in flatten
and suddenly it's turned this into a
flat surface let's do that a few times
so i do
seat circle select maybe those ones
enter f3 and we've already typed flat in
there so i press enter
c to circle select or first we want to
actually press escape and double click a
to deselect
c to circle select a few of these
f3 flatten and here becomes a bit of a
problem maybe so we could think about
ways to fix that but let's do a few more
things first let's do flatten this part
as well
f3 flatten and maybe here
enter f3 flatten we learned before that
we could
use scaling on on a certain axis
so for example if i do c to select here
enter if i were to scale this now it
just scales it up and down
and if i were to scale it on an axis
like z it would flatten it and widen it
but here we can actually go into press
comma and here we have a whole new
selection of
something called orientation that we
haven't covered yet and by default it's
set to global so when i scale on the
z-axis
it's the vertical blue z-axis here
but if we do scale or if i do comma
and then select normal here remember the
normal is the
face the perpendicular angle to a face
so if you have a flat face like this
it's 90 degrees
in the center going up that's the normal
and when we have multiple faces selected
it'll be the averaged normal so now when
i you can see this blue arrow is
pointing
away from an average of these normals
here
so now when i press s to scale i can do
z
to flatten it like this and we've got
proportional editing on now as well
which is why
it's moving the surrounding one if we
then want that we can deselect that one
with o
press s to scale again and then force it
on the z axis
and then you can type zero as well and
that's basically the same as flattening
but if you don't want to fully flatten
it you can press s to scale and then
do z to like bring those faces a little
bit more
into the shape that you want sometimes
you have little squiggly bits like this
that you want to get rid of
and let's say we wanted to fix this one
let's say this face is annoying us
a lot like this face is annoying most
people probably
but here i can switch this little thing
we haven't talked about this one but but
snap two i can change to vertex if i
wanted to move this vertex now onto
exactly the location of that vertex
i can press g to move it and since we
had switched to vertex at the top now if
i hold the ctrl key
i can actually magically snap it onto
any other vertex here
but we have to be careful because when i
did that now it looked like we fixed
everything
but if i press g to move it you can see
that it's actually two vertices there
and that's a problem you don't really
want to have overlapping vertices
because you have faces there now that
are basically non-existent but it'll
cause problems there's two ways to fix
that
first one you can do instead i press
ctrl z and we can enable this little
thing up here called
auto merge vertices so if i click on
that one
i press g to move it and now if i hold
the ctrl key
and i snap it onto there since auto
merge vertices is on now it'll detect
that oh these vertices are in the exact
same location so i'll merge those into
one
so now when i press g to move it it's
already magically fixed that for us
the other way to do it is if you don't
have auto merge vertices
you press g to move it hold the ctrl key
snap it onto that vertex then now
i can do a to select everything and
there's a hotkey it's changed now so in
2.83 it's just the
m key it used to be different one it
used to be alt m but now it's
m and then you do merge by distance and
you can see down there it says removed
one vertices or one vertex it's because
it goes through the whole mesh and
detects if there are duplicates one so
that's pretty good to do every now and
then if you've got a complex mesh
just select all the vertices do m and
then merge by distance and remove all
those doubles so you don't run into
problems with them i don't know if i've
covered this but i'll give you this one
as well
let's say we wanted to create a bit of a
worn edge to this stone and i press two
to make sure i'm in the edge select and
let's hold the shift key now and
select a few of these edges here and
then now you can press ctrl
b to do the bevel again and we've
actually done this before because i've
got loads of lines here we don't really
want that many so let's bring segments
down to
one and now when we tab out of object
mode we can see that it's created quite
a nice
little beveled edge to this and then if
we go one
into vertex edit here we can select a
few of these vertices and press
s to scale them and then here maybe we
want it smaller as to scale it down
here maybe we want to scale it up again
you can control
through scaling here how much you want
those beveled edges to be on the rock so
that's quite good
for stones low polystones okay let's
double click and
name this one stone
sometimes you want to start getting
nitty gritty with your editing so
sometimes you want to delete faces let's
say we wanted to shift select a few of
these
and then we wanted to press delete for
whatever reason
then it's a big hole here that could be
a bit scary in the first time that
happens
but don't be too worried about it you
can actually fix holes like this
by if you have a hole in your mesh in
edit mode
click a for everything and press f on
the keyboard
that fills this hole automatically but
it creates one big mesh like this
so sometimes you can get into some
alignment issues let's say we had these
gone
over the edge here like that let's
select those press delete
faces select everything and press f you
can see that it fixes the hole
but it's got some weird stuff going on
here with the shading
and that's because it's created one face
so it's really finding it difficult here
but there's a way to fix it
either we can do it manually by
selecting we know that we want the line
between that vertex and that vertex and
then we can press
j and that fixes pretty much everything
there because then you tell
the mesh that i want a distinct edge
here so that's fixed
another thing you could do is if we
control z out of that one
you could select that face and press
ctrl t
to triangulate it that's another way to
fix that one also if you want to say
exactly how faces should be created
actually let's
do ctrl t to triangulate that one as
well let's say we had this one deleted
again like this
delete faces if you want to have control
while you create this instead of marking
everything you can press
2 to select the edges here and let's say
i want to select this
edge that edge and that edge and now
when i press f
it'll create a face between those lines
that i set
here same thing here if i wanted to
control i could select
exactly which lines and f to create them
sometimes you'll run into a problem here
where the face is created maybe
inwards i'll just flip it manually now
so you can see what i mean
flip normals so this face actually
exists here if we do old said
you can see that there's like a center
point here you can see it
that one an old set again to
disable x-ray so there is a face here
but remember that we have the back face
culling on
so if if we can see the back face it
looks like there's a face there
but if we enable backface culling this
is what most game edges would see
a big gaping hole here sounded weird
okay but we can fix that in a few ways
one of them is manually by selecting
this face that we know exists there
pressing f3 and typing flip normals so
that was one way to do it
the other way to do it is that you can
actually recalculate the normals for the
whole mesh so let's say we flipped
we let's say we have a few of them let's
flip like this i'll select a few bunch
flip normals if you don't want to select
all these manually and flip them you can
do a to select everything
and then press alt n and then
recalculate outside and now blender will
sort of detect which ones are facing
outside and try to fix it for you so
that
works quite often not all the time but
quite often and equally
there's this thing called alt n and you
could do recalculate inside
so if you made a cave for example then
you can certainly be inside of it but
let's flip them back
alt n recalculate outside
and back to our stone here you can also
remove individual edges here
so if i press two to edge select and
let's say we wanted to
it's called dissolve so if i wanted to
remove these edges here but not
delete them i can press x or delete and
then dissolve edges
and sometimes you want to do this as
well because sometimes you don't
let's say you have a bit of a
triangulation going on like this
which might be just this like this
sometimes you want to select all of
these
like that press x and dissolve edges
and that will dissolve those and just
create one face but be aware that when
you subdivide and things like that okay
another thing we can do is
something called bridge edge loops which
could be quite useful
let's hide this one the stone and let's
bring a new one
shift a create a new cube
tab into edit mode first we'll switch
the shading again back to
the material here a
scale 0 on the uvs you know this by now
g to move it onto gray l to select this
one
actually let's just create something
here um let's
do the old school stuff what we learned
a long time ago now e takes true d to
extrude s to scale e to extrude to
extrude s to scale
maybe i to inset let's say we had
something like this now
and inset that one and then let's
duplicate this whole object now shift d
these are facing in the wrong direction
now because before remember we pressed
comma
to go into normal but we're going to go
back into global now so everything makes
sense i'll slide it on this red axis
and let's do something here item set
this one e to extrude
let's say we wanted to connect these two
now so we're in the same
object here now the cube here but we've
got two sets of geometries and sometimes
you want to connect this one here let's
slide this one out instead
so how do i go about connecting these
into one single mesh here you could just
select this face select that face type
press
f3 and type in bridge and then select
bridge edge loops here
and that links those together and we can
do alt z to make sure
it actually took away the center phase
that was in here as well so there's
no more center phase in there we can
actually double check here as well i'll
select
the loop around there and press h to
hide it and you can see that there are
no faces here as well
and then alt h on hide so if you wanted
to link these together
just select those two f3 bridge edge
loops
if you wanted to select these two up
here you can link those together as well
f3 bridge edge loops like that let's say
i wanted to model
top of a table with a computer a monitor
and a
keyboard on it let's do shift a as we've
done before we'll add a cube
and we'll go here bring shading make
sure we have the material selected
go back to uv editing i'll select
everything i'm in edit mode now so i've
pressed tab
very important scale z and then we
flatten it down maybe like this
scale on the x axis make it wider so
we'll just make the
i'll skip the legs for now i'll just
make a table top here a
on the left side on the uv here scale 0
enter
and make a brown table top again so now
we're going to put a computer here and
this is something i do quite often to
save a lot of time
i select this table top just this face
here i'm three
in phase select here shift d to
duplicate it
and you can see that it's loose here but
if i press right mouse button now it'll
snap it back to where it was
but now we've got a separate face here
so i can press s to scale that face
and s again and press x and scale it on
the x axis
and then move it to here and then now
when i press e to extrude it
we've got a computer here and remember
that i can press l on this one to select
it we're still in the same object here
but since these vertices are only linked
to this face and the extruded part of it
it's not linked to the tabletop anymore
so we can control this separate
and then i'll press on the left here g
and move it to black so we make a black
computer always cool to have a black
computer let's make a monitor
so in the same way i'll take the
tabletop here again shift d duplicate it
right click scale it down e to extrude
e to extrude again s to scale e to
extrude
let's actually press l here and move it
all the way to the side so we get some
space
e to extrude s to scale s to scale again
on the x axis
e to extrude and press l
to select all the links g here on the
left side move it to black
let's do i to inset and e to extrude
and let's change g here and change this
to a blue screen of that
and let's make a keyboard so same i'll
pick this one shift d
to duplicate it scale it maybe move it
to here
scale e to extrude it l to select the
length
and g to move it maybe it's a great
keyboard say we wanted to make a chord
here as well
we could do the same here thing with lu
we can do the same thing i'll do shift d
to duplicate it
scale it down maybe scale it on the z
axis
let's look from the top now and then
just remember we could hold the ctrl key
and then just right click
like this and then connect it to the
monitor
there maybe move it into the monitor
and it's hanging in the air now so maybe
we want to fix that i'll go into
two to edge select select any edge here
let's
press o to enable proportional editing
and g to move it down
scroll it up a bit see that we're
distorting the computer now we don't
really want to do that so let's right
click
to cancel that and do alt o to make sure
we only have the connected here
this one remember that it's connected
only now g to move it now we're only
affecting the chord no matter how big we
go
so we can hang the chord down to maybe
there select that one
scroll it down that one scroll it down
so now we've created a low poly cord
that's hanging maybe we wanted to even
hang off the table a little bit
have to be careful maybe we want to
rotate it bring it down
move that one there just make sure you
don't
twist the the stuff too much i probably
went a little bit overboard here
so be careful with that so this is still
again the same object but let's say we
wanted to detach this now into a
separate let's say we wanted to detach
the monitor
we can actually double click a to make
sure nothing is selected
press l over the monitor here and now
there's a hotkey called
p and then separate selection
and now we've created a separate one
here and that's our monitor and this one
first here is the
other combined if i control z that you
could actually do this as well
you can select everything p and separate
by loose parts and now it's created all
of these for us so i can go to this one
name this one monitor here is our
computer
here's our very basic keyboard
and here's our tabletop
maybe we wanted some legs on this table
as well after all
so we can do the same thing here i do
shift d to duplicate it
scale it down scale it on the x axis
move it into move it into the place of a
leg here maybe
so we slide it on these axis and then e
to extrude it down
maybe we do ctrl 7 to go to the bottom
view because
i didn't mention that before but 7 is
the top view but control 7 is the bottom
view
press l to select the link here shift d
to duplicate it right click to snap it
back
move it on this axis and let's press l
over this one so we select both legs
shift d to duplicate it and then move it
roughly today
and then now we've got some legs on that
table as well equally like we did with
separate before you can actually bring
them back into the same object again if
you want to we could
select this one hold the shift key to
all of these for example
and that one and then do control j
and that merges it into it'll pick the
latest name
here that you had computer
stuff and i think the chord is still a
separate one here so we can
click that one click that one and do
control
j to join that one as well and now
suddenly it's in one object again so
remember that you can separate it with p
into separate objects if you want to
export it for the game and have
everything separate that's fine and you
can join stuff together again with the
control j also very useful
now we're going to get into some
modifiers are you still with me are you
still awake
i'm barely what time is it 3 15 in the
morning i love this stuff
can't get enough of it that's why i'm
going to keep going so we're going to do
a modifier here
and it's going to be the mirror modifier
very useful if you want to model a
spaceship for example and so you go
on the right side here with the object
selected in object mode you go to this
wrench
icon and then add modifier and mirror
and it'll look a bit weird here because
it doesn't really know how to mirror it
it's mirroring it on the x-axis here by
default you can control which axis you
do i always
use the x-axis for mirroring but it
doesn't look mirrored now so we don't
know what's going on and that's because
this geometry is going past the center
here
if i take this face and move it you can
see that it's still there
which is really strange but it's because
it's mirroring this part of the green
side
of the y-axis here on the x-axis it's
mirroring that part
so in order to to get into a cube that's
mirrored
you'd have to if you do it manually
you'd have to delete that face
and then press two maybe and alt select
this ring and then bring it back and
it's difficult to know exactly how far
but you can enable this clipping feature
here because
then it'll detect that when you hit the
center here it won't allow you to go
past it
but we've got proportional editing on
still so disable that
so when i move it now it'll detect that
oh i'm going to glue you together now
because we've hit the center so now if i
try to move this one it doesn't work
because clipping
is preventing us from doing that so most
of the time that's what you want to do
saying all of this there's actually a
great way that you should do this
instead
so instead of applying this mirror
modifier here you go to
edit preferences and then here you go to
add-ons
and then type here you can type in auto
mirror i have this one enabled by
default because i love this one
so make sure you have that one enabled
and now when you click on the object
you can press n on your keyboard to get
this little menu here and go to edit
and now you have this magic one called
auto mirror so click on that one
and that just did everything that i did
manually if i tab into now it's already
got the perfect slit here it's got
clipping enabled
everything is ready to go so save
yourself a lot of time and hassle by
doing that
use auto mirror another useful modifier
is the displays modifier if i do
shift a here this time let's add a plane
tab into edit mode
scale it up a lot tab out of edit mode
and ctrl 5
and now we can actually go into simple
now because we just want to subdivide
this one it doesn't look any different
now
but if i apply this one and tab into
edit mode you can see that it subdivided
it
a lot of times here to create this grid
instead let's actually subdivide this
one one more time so
i select the object press control two
simple
and apply it and now we've got even more
geometry here so if you wanted to create
a low poly island or
you could uh enable this proportional
editing and then select the vertex
press g to move it and then use the
mouse wheel to start
changing this you could also what we
learned before ctrl right click to lasso
select something
and press g and then use proportional
editing here to start creating
different shapes to your island that's
one way to do it but i wanted to show
this
displays modifier so if i go to add
modifier here displace
and i have to tab out of edit mode to
see it now i can click new here on
texture
and on this little icon here and let's
switch the type here
to clouds for example and change the
scale
to this maybe two and then we can go
back into
this modifier tab here and change the
strength maybe we wanted to
tweak this one even more maybe we wanted
this one to scale
4 or 10. increase the scale even more
so here's a useful thing and if you
wanted to make it
maybe you wanted to add something like a
water thing there you could go into this
color one
and do color ramp
and then you slide this bottom one
it takes away details from the lower
part of the of the randomness so it
creates like
the surface of a c here and if you're
happy with this you could
go back to this modifier here and just
click apply and now we've created
something that looks a little bit like a
low poly landscape we could decimate
this one again because it still doesn't
look very low poly so we can go add
modifier
decimate it like we did before and slide
this one down
and that brings it into like a low poly
landscape and then apply that one we
have some issues here as well
if we wanted to fix that we could do
that we can select those two vertices
press x and dissolve vertices so if you
have some problem areas like that
x this is all vertices we could do one
to get
the side view alt z
to see all of this trickiness b to box
select
and then just select the very bottom
here as slow down as we can
and now we've selected all the bottom
faces more or less
alt said to snap out of that on and we
haven't actually changed the
material here so let's change the
material go back into uv editing
a to select everything on the left that
we selected scale
0 and now we can select that one to blue
if we wanted
but what about the rest well we can
press ctrl i to flip the selection
and then a on the left side scale 0
g to move it maybe to green so that's
one way to create something that looks a
little bit like a low poly landscape
if it's too steep for example you can
select everything
scale z to flatten it again let's say we
wanted some
uh white snow capped tops here make sure
we're in edit mode here maybe press
uh one to vertex select double click a
to deselect everything
b to box select and let's go like this
switch into face selector mode with
three again maybe we still want
let's say we wanted some uh gray
mountains first we could do control plus
a few times
maybe to there on the left side here
we've also got some water selected now
if we didn't want that to be selected we
could see it's these we could maybe
deselect these manually like this
if it's tricky to see where the water is
selected and stuff you can actually
click on this little thing here called
uv sync selection
because now if i do be shift select that
one it'll deselect edit anything that
had
that blue color and then we can switch
this back on again so now we
we've ensured that we don't have any
water selected and then i can do
g here and go to gray maybe and then
ctrl minus
maybe three times and then g and move
that to byte
and tab out of edit mode and now we've
created something that looks a little
bit like a
low poly landscape one more modifier
that's quite useful and that is the skin
modifier
if you wanted to create a tree again for
example you could do here we can
there's actually another useful thing
here you can go to preferences
and then here we type extra objects
enable that one
because now when we press shift a we can
actually add a mesh but we can add
a single vert it'll bring us into vertex
edit mode here
and now zoom out a little bit and i hold
the ctrl key and i
just right click a bit like this
and then i select this vertex right
click select that vertex
right click a few times with the control
key by the way
so control key right click right click
right click i'll hold the ctrl key
right click right click and i rotate the
viewport a little bit now when we've got
this
that looks a bit like a tree trunk we
can add the modifier here
and add the skin modifier see that it's
a little bit too thick now
tab into make sure you're in edit mode
so you see these vertices
press a to select all of them and then
ctrl a and that's the hotkey to scale
vertices for skinning for the skinning
modifier here shift deselect that one
let's enable proportional with o we
can't do scale remember we have to do
ctrl a
for the skinning one and then scale it
down and we don't want symmetry on
either
and then this one ctrl a
to scale and then roll up proportional
so this is how you could create
three branches
if you remember before we enable this
thing called vertex snapping and we used
it to snap one of these vertices
onto another one like this pow but one
thing that's really really useful let's
say you had
another line there and let's say that
one was a bit wonky that one was a bit
wonky
you can actually use the vertex snap on
an axis as well click
on this axis here that we have before
again if that's not enabled
you can go up here drop down and have
this one enabled or you can press
shift space and g to enable it as well
that's the same as clicking on this move
tool here and now if i move
on this axis and then i hold the ctrl
key
and then snap it to there it'll only
snap it on the x axis to that one
and this is really really good if you
want to align to make sure that they're
on the same
on the same distance on the on one axis
similarly
if i wanted to bring this one up and
make sure it's the same height as this
one
move it on this one hold the ctrl key
and move it
and move it so you get that little
circle and then we can see here that
that one's poking out we wanted to bring
that one into the same as there move it
on the green axis
on the y axis hold the ctrl key and snap
it to that one so if you want to do
aligning
vertex snapping on an axis is really
useful
we've already enabled automator here but
there are a couple of more ones i'd like
to mention
so in preferences under add-ons one good
is
loop tools so make sure you enable that
one
and another one while i'm here is f2
we'll enable that one too and one more
is bool tools let's enable that one
and i'll show you what these two as well
so if i do shift
a mesh cube here we've got a normal cube
again
let's subdivide this one ctrl 3 maybe
and apply that one and let's say you
wanted to make
these if you wanted to extrude these but
you wanted them to be
circle shape so if i shift select these
and extrude it's like a square thing
that i'm doing
so ctrl z on that one and then we've got
loop tools here
you've got a few things i won't go
through all of them now you can
experiment with these
but one for example is circle here and
that just basically takes that square
and
makes it a circle and now when i extrude
it's more like a round thing so that's
very useful but there are some other
good
things here as well like flatten that we
did before we've got uh
bridge and all sorts of stuff the other
thing which is really good is the bull
tools one
and again if i edit here it's a bool
tool here
if i do shift d to duplicate this and
then i select this one
shift select that one and then i'll do
control shift
minus on the keypad then it basically
cuts that first mesh
out of this one again very useful maybe
you wanted to create a moon or something
like that
so maybe we scale this one
off with proportional scale it down
do a few of these i'll select this one
shift to like this one ctrl shift minus
on the keypad
i'll select this one this one
ctrl minus select this one remember
shift select that one ctrl shift minus
on the keypad
so bool tool very useful especially to
do subtractive
boolean operations and then the next one
is the f2 that i did
and for example if you have let's say we
have a bunch of these cutaway
press delete faces f2 will do this for
you
remember that we created faces before uh
we could do
everything and press f to create one big
weird face
but f2 add-on will do this for you
select this one
press f ffff it'll automatically fill
that together for you into
usually a quite a good sequence
all right i want to finish off this uh
lengthy video with a few tips as well if
you run into issues
there could be a few tips maybe that you
can look into so one thing that you
might run into is parallel faces
and if you select this one and then if
you
extrude now up then you've actually got
this face here is sliding down between
and that's not really good
you don't want that so there's a few
things that you could do to fix this
one way to do it is if we've got this
auto merge vertices here i could do
control r add a loop cut here and slide
it down roughly to that place
and if i made it close enough which i
didn't because they're still separate
there then it's uh
it would have fixed it i'll select this
vertex press g to move it
ctrl and snap it onto that one since
i've got this
vertex snapping on here same thing for
this one select that
and that vertex is actually dug into
here so i do alt z to see through
select that one alt set g to move it and
snap it on to there
and now and then if i move this vertex
now you can see that we don't have any
double faces there anymore and if i do
old set i can also see
on three here we've got an issue still
we've got an
internal face here that was created due
to this you can only see that with old
said here and i've got that selected
there
and then you can just press delete and
delete that face and now we see that
there is no dot
here anymore in the center alt z so
everything's fixed we've now fixed that
double
alignment the other thing that we had is
if we don't have this enabled we could
have some duplicate vertices
sometimes so if i do control r loop cut
that one
move that one up to there roughly let's
actually snap it
let's do this all together
and snap all of these up with uh here
now it looks like this is just a normal
mesh here
but if i try to tab here and move this
one you can see that it goes all weird
and the best way to fix this one is just
do
a for everything m and then
merge by distance and suddenly six
vertices were removed and now
everything's back to normal the other
thing that we had is that faces are
facing the wrong direction
so remember if you have something that
looks like a gap but there's actually a
face here
you could either do alt n to flip it
or you can do it for the whole mesh and
do everything
alt n and recalculate outside that will
usually fix that one then you have the
misaligned vertices like this
you wanted to have those aligned
remember make sure that vertex snapping
is on
move it on this axis hold the control
key and snap these
into edge same for the height and the
width you could do
control snap it ctrl snap it height wise
to that one
and height wise to that one so that's
one way to really align everything back
into shape
if in setting is behaving really strange
for you let's say we wanted to inset
this one
like this eye to inset if for some
reason you have
accidentally scaled your objects outside
of edit mode let's say you're in object
mode
you scale your object along the x-axis
or let's do the y-axis like this now
if you look here on the item you can see
that the scale here is
string it's not 1 1 1. so now if i try
to inset this one
it's not scaling it uniformly it's
scaling a lot more on the y
axis and that's because this y axis
scale is more
and to fix that you have to just select
the object in object mode
click control a and apply scale and that
brings it back the scale to 1 1
1 and then i to insert now you can see
that the insetting is working correctly
let's say you wanted to work on this
vertex here
but when you rotate you're not really
rotating around that vertex
just press delete on the keypad or the
period or the comma key
and that'll recenter everything you
scroll out again and now when you rotate
you'll work nicely around that object so
it frames it to that object
another thing that you might run into is
if you add the subdivision modifier by
pressing ctrl
3 for example and everything looks too
round let's say you wanted the base not
to be rounded
ctrl z out of that one then you could
press ctrl
r in edit mode here add a loop cut quite
close to the base
so it's doubled up here and now if i tap
out of it into object mode and press
ctrl 2 again then you can see that
it kept a nice solid edge around the
bottom here so that's one way to get
around if you want to keep some edges
when
you subdivide it the other thing that we
had remember when we did the center line
when we subdivided for example for a car
window
or something like that if you have
mirror modifier on and the inset
produces a face in the center that you
don't want
make sure you press b for boundary and
that'll remove that little
center face for you and if b doesn't
work it's because you have individual
faces on so press
i again first to disable individual
faces and then
b for boundary should work again all
right guys so that sums up
it was a long video and a lot of
information but it's pretty much
everything that i do when i low poly
model stuff this is what i've learned
over the course of the last four to five
years that i've been using blender
i used a bit of 3ds max before that but
not really at a serious level
but i think it's mostly the two most
recent years that i've done on a lot of
low poly stuff and especially this year
with my 10 minute modeling challenge i'm
really trying to find the most efficient
workflows
and good fast techniques to do low poly
modelling come back to the video
re-watch certain parts
break it down practice practice practice
make a lot of low poly stuff i do that
all the time i basically jump into
blender and i just
model anything i can think of houses
islands
cars dragons i haven't even covered in
this video i haven't covered so much
about character modelling
same technique applies but when it comes
to rigging it'll be
a few more things and animating those i
should make some videos about that
so thanks a lot guys for sticking with
me give it a thumbs up if you like this
video and subscribe if you haven't
already and i've also got a patreon so
if you want to give that a little bit of
extra support
head over to patreon.com infensia until
next time have a good one
take care bye for now
[Music]
you