hello everyone and welcome to episode 71
of the 10 minute modeling challenge
this time around i'm going to be doing a
spider bot and it was suggested by mia
pc
and i think she meant it like a spider
bot so i'm going to do a spider robot if
that's not what you meant
then i got it wrong but i'm going to do
it anyway so a little robotic
hard to surface the spider it's going to
be low poly of course no surprise i'm
going to fit it in 10 minutes i'm going
to rig it as well
last weekend got a little bit busy as
well first it was my wife's birthday
actually on
the friday so we had a good time there
spent time with the family and
celebrated that
and then on the weekend we did a lot of
housework so we started to tear down a
balcony
and of course there was ludum there 48
and i sort of a little bit forgot about
it so i
just had to do what i could i didn't
want to miss out on my 13th
consecutive participation of ludum there
but i had to scale it down so i did a
little diving game and
uh very unimaginable very little
innovation when it comes to this one and
originality it just flushed down the
toilet
and when i told my wife what i did she's
just going god couldn't you come up with
anything better than that
but the game's called deep blue wow
surprising original yeah i know
and it's a deep diving like a free
diving game so i modeled a little
character
and it had some new challenges actually
but it was good to learn
first of all i'm not used to modeling
characters being upside down
and with the leg movements i'm so used
to inverse kinematics and the walk
cycles
so when i'm going to do the flippers and
when he was swimming down it was a
little bit trickier than i thought
so that was a bit of a good practice and
there was a few other things i did an
inverted
ragdoll which was quite fun that's
another new one for me because
usually i just do a ragdoll apply
physics and let them drop but this one
i had to do a ragdoll basically like
before
but i inverted gravity and i had to do
the angular drag and the drag of all the
joints a little bit so it looks like
he's floating up
and for the depth of the water just to
make that blue shades i didn't really go
all in with volumetrics and stuff like
that i did it uh the cheating way that's
what
that's me uh i was gonna say that was me
that's not me but the uh
uh oh yeah i just put a lot of
transparent sheets between uh
like different layers of the background
so it gradually shaded it towards
like a blue color for the depth so you
can download that unity project and if
you want to have a look at it it looks a
total mess
it's like hack and slash just make it
work within the
uh within the time and i guess you have
48 hours for ludum there
leave them there 48 48 hours that was a
bit of a coincidence
but i managed to put 15 hours into the
game and uh considering that little
amount of time i was happy with the
result and i also wanted to make
my first one-click game so there's only
one button that you need to do in the
whole game and that's
press spacebar but if you time the swim
downs then you can go a little bit
faster so you can reach that depth
and the theme of course was deeper and
deeper so i thought every time you go
you're
going to go a little bit deeper it's
time to model a spiderbot and
i'm going to go for the old cool palette
again the solid link is
might be in the description let's go
ready steady go
we're off tap into the mode a select
everything
g oh no first of all of course bottom
mirror
a g move it up scale it down bring it in
and here i'm going to copy this for the
legs shift d
and copy this for like a little gun
turret at the top here
l scale y control r
maybe six loop cuts on this one because
then you get a nice even number to
do this little effect with that we're
gonna use so we're gonna do i to inset
b to get the root of the boundary in the
center alt s to scale it down
and here let's do like a head so ctrl r
scale it out there maybe bring that down
and here we go i'm just gonna do some
sort of a
like spider-like body or something
i don't know g okay hey select
everything let's make it a little bit
darker this time
dark spider like in minecraft g orange
bit robotic no minecraft anymore g
to move that on i think that should do
and make a little bit point here
and we can do an i here so i to inset oh
i to inset the eye hilarious not really
g
red spin cycle on the washing machine is
going up again bear with it
stay with me let's see g okay
i haven't started the legs yet so let's
that's the eye let's do it like
scale it down archer rotate scale it
down i'm going to do
period and do uh no i'm not comma and do
normal so we get
the normal directions there e to extrude
e took shoot s to scale e to extrude
e to extrude that's the scale i'll just
do like a robotic leg of course
so that's it simple as that and
here let's copy this one shift d
scale it down e to extrude that's the
scale do it like internally like that
don't have to worry about the hydraulics
and stuff like that we should be getting
away with it low poly
we'll get away with it it's extrude sd
scale e2 extrude
sd scale e to extrude no i'm not going
to say
scale that one shift d scale it down e
to extrude
s to scale e takes true that's the scale
e to extrude
e texture s this game and i'm going to
do like spiky legs here so i don't have
to worry about feet 7 47 on the clock
here
i'm gonna do l to select the linked hair
though and rotate this
so the legs don't get too long
so g okay e to extrude i'll just
all the way down to the tip you know
scale pointy
feet there ctrl r but i'll chunk them up
a little bit here
put some features here now i'm gonna do
some shields of some sort here
so let's just do uh let's select that
one each extruder i'm going to attach it
to the actual leg so it's a little bit
easier to weight paint because we have
to do manual weight painting for this
need to extrude so let's do the shield
here
the leg shield e to extrude for the
spider bot
e to extrude r to rotate and then
let's shift select a few of these
and alt t extrude long face normals
g to move it down scale z no
x no y okay no apparently no axis
so let's leave it then and
g to move that on spiky i think the
washing machines don't know
to move that on okay this should do and
then uh i'll do features here as well so
maybe i'll
gg something wrong
oh yeah that's because that one so ctrl
r let's do
four here i'll select these
item set alt test to scale them down and
make them orange
and then here 621 we'll do the same type
of feature here
so b to extrude e to extrude but here
i'll just do one i think like this e to
explode like a shield here on the leg as
well
all d to extrude long face normals is
that even what i'm doing i hope so
g move that one and should we do
move that one up ctrl r we'll just do
one loop here
height inset all test is scaled down
orange
and here it felt like it was a bit too
thick so
let's do shift select these and spike
this up as well don't need to protect
the leg that much that should do and
should we do some something weird
no i think that should be all right
dude e to extrude that's the scale
little details here okay never mind
and now i'll do the torrent turret so
g to move that one back to there e to
extrude i'll just do something super
simple e to extrude s to scale e to
extrude
and then h extrude s to scale and then
here i'm just going to do like a cannon
or a gun let's just call it a gun shift
d duplicate that on the scale
bring it down to there and bring it in
because it's going to have like a recoil
effector e to extrude you to extrude
again
s to scale a little bit taller y
okay comma and do global again
and then e to extrude e to extrude
that's the scale
e to extrude here's just like the tip of
the
gun or something e to extrude
s to scale item set b for boundary and e
to extrude in
that's a big cannon big cannon hole ctrl
r six loop cuts
maybe that was too many i don't know
let's do those
like indentations here as well i'll test
to scale that on
let me bring those up and here should we
do like a shield in the back here as
well
all the extra long oh all the
extruded face normals scale z
rotate g e took screwed as the scale
and we'll do those i'll just do one here
as well
alt s scale it down g okay
four minutes to go let's try to rig this
and i have to figure out how to do this
now
because let's do some maybe dark parts
here too
okay okay uh
so to do this i need to do more legs
here
g to move uh i have to first of all do
the armature shift a
armature and here
let's go into this tab and do viewport
in front
tab in credit mode i've got three
minutes to to
awesome i was trying to call rotate
minus
90. ah can't answer now maybe that's the
fiber
uh i'll just have to decline for now and
pick up after
shift space g uh shift d that's for the
turret that's for the gun
and name this one root
name this one turret name this one
gun and then we'll do this one needs to
be connected
so control p keep offset and this one
needs to become vectors one
keep opposite and i have to do the legs
so e to extrude
g to move it g to move that one down oh
i have to do inverse kinematics with
this two two forty eight
this is not gonna work i'm panicking now
fail duck might be coming up
uh let's see so
i have to compare that one control p
keep offset
leg a dot l zero zero one
weird name and g to move that on down
e texture down up to no
g there i need to extrude it down to the
tip
and this needs to be segment b but leg
one and this one needs to be ligament
legacy let's see one still
i feel panic now two minutes to go each
extrude uh
p now alt p clear apparent
g to move down high up because this is
going to be the pole target
for some flippy legs i need to find the
d4 needs to go off and then e to extrude
on
alt p clear parent deform off
ik target dot l
dot zero zero one i k
poll dot l zero zero one
and now i do have to do the image
kinematics two so i have to go control
tab
pose mode did i name this correctly yeah
uh 132. um honeykin uh inverse
kinematics
there and we need three segments this
time
and here's the armature so armature
and ik target here's the armature ik
pole and that's flipped out i have to do
a to select everything shift n view axis
roll calculation
tab again and we have to do this one
this
180 because it's probably yeah that like
works control tab
okay now i need to duplicate this so
shift select these
uh 57 seconds to go this
uh let's see i'll move that one to
g minus one okay g
there two minus one
minus two okay um
let's move shift d two shift d
two okay thirty four seconds
uh tab inside mode l to select all the
links here
[Music]
and then back shift d to
shift d minus two oh no
ah top view g
minus four that's it
and here we go 10 seconds to go and i'm
gonna actually move these
a little bit closer again l
shift select everything and
great great
so the 10 minutes are up and i did
manage to sort of model a spiderbot
and i created the armature roughly
but i failed to link it up and you can't
do automatic weights with this anyway so
i don't think i was even close when it
came to it at the end here
so the idea was to do a rigged spider
bot in 10 minutes
and that sort of failed so i'm gonna
have to move into the bonus content now
and
rig it and we'll do a little animation
for this spiderbot as well
but when you think about it maybe was it
a fail or was it a huge success because
i managed to model
the spiderbot well within the 10 minutes
so
this is the bonus material now and this
is where we take care of the rest of the
rigging
and the animating let's try to just
ignore that
everything that just happened and let's
move on let's proceed okay so
i'm still going to try to keep the pace
up though a little bit
but it's weird without the pressure on
kind of keep the pace open
you should always work on the pressure
it's always a lot better
so what we're going to do here let's
take these bones here
shift space g i'm going to move them a
little bit closer together again because
i think they ended up a little bit far
apart
so let's shift select a bunch of those
and move them up okay i need to move the
whole bone
oh the the tempo significantly drops
after the pressure is off
so g um
let's do on this axis 0.5
that's a little bit better i think and
then we'll move this one down too
shift select those g minus
0.5 there we go and then we'll do the
same for the legs here
so l l l to select linked g
middle mouse button zero negative zero
point
five start ll g
0.5 okay so the idea now would be to
let's see everything's there since i
named them the way i did
we can parent these now i think
everything's pretty much set up i've got
the inverse kinematics we had that in
time though
so that worked within the time limit
that's pretty good
could've been worse so with this done i
think it's time to do them symmetrize so
a to select everything no tab into edit
mode on the armature a select everything
f3 oh that's cache since the last
challenge
symmetrize there we go and that one's
all symmetrized
and control tab post mode the inverse
kinematics everything works
for both legs yeah that works and this
works so
let's uh parent it we have to do a
little bit different because uh
now since we're outside of the 10
minutes bonus
then when we parent this i can show you
that we don't really want to use
automatic weights because if i do that
ctrl p so i shift select there first i
select the
mesh shift selected the armature control
p if i do the automatic weights
now it sort of works but if you look
here ctrl tab into post mode
g and see that it's moving the face and
it's distorting the legs a little bit
so you don't really get that hard
feeling but it did actually do a pretty
good
job but this is no good so instead of
doing that we want to lock
everything 100 in place so to do that
let's controls that out now i'm going to
do
again select the mesh shift select the
armature
control p and then do with empty groups
i've done this a few times in the past
for
like the mech warrior type thing but
let's do it
we'll start with the body here so tab
into edit mode
l to select this one ctrl g and set
active group okay we didn't name this
one apparently root so let's
let's do that first
f2 i thought it did
ah did i name that one okay
tourette's
uh root
i alright do like a programmer's
tourettes like singleton singleton
singleton garbage collection garbage
collection
let's go l select the linked purchases
for the body
and then now we'll do ctrl g set active
group root ctrl g assign to active group
l this is going to be a bit repetitive
control g
set active group turret
ctrl g still a side tag to group you get
a little bit faster when you've done it
a few times so
l control g set active group gone
ctrl g assigned to actually group and
now comes the fun part we have to do it
for the legs so
l that's why we sort of named them a
little bit decently
control g set active group
leg a l.001 so i'm just going to do it
now instead of saying all this so we'll
do this one
and you get start to get into the
repetitive moment here so
you can slow this down if you need to l
g and this one this one ctrl g
assign type group that's why it's good
to have all the leg components attached
to each other as well
because it makes this uh sub part a
little bit easier i tried with them
i can't really speak and do this at the
same time but i have tried with
envelopes instead of automatic weights
and that doesn't really work so well
either so this is
pretty much the only way i've found to
do the hard surface
stuff when i connect them up and a
spider shooter i have eight legs
i only did six legs ah that was to save
some time
and it looks cool enough i think with
six legs so ctrl
l set active group and here we go the
last one
this one control a hope i remember to
assign them all here
l control g
there control g active group and the
last one
l we have only have to do one side sec
active group
like oh nearly another one no it was the
wrong one not nearly it was the wrong
one
it was nearly the right one and a
scientific group
okay now we can check it ctrl
tab post mode g
will it move that moved this one moved
and
that one moved and these should work
then yep
success and the poll targets here will
aim the legs
so that's done um we should also try to
animate this one because
i haven't really modeled any i haven't
really animated stuff that's not
like a bipedal thing so let's go into
the animation tab
we'll do the right thing first set this
one to texture and
shadow and we'll do cavity of course
both so we get a pretty interface here
when we look so
here we go there's the spider with a
little cannon on so let's animate it
first of all i'll go to the action
editor here instead
bring this one up and let's create a new
action let's call this one
uh just we can't call it t-post because
it's not a t-pose we'll call it
uh just default i'll do an underscore as
well
remember your neutral pose put an
underscore at the top of the actions
because when you import it into
especially unity i don't know about the
other game engines but it inherits the
post from the first
action so tip pro tip
from an from an amateur so there we go
uh a little shield light come to protect
that from deletion and go back to
first frame here and now we'll do item
search
not inset this time and location and
rotation and that creates that frame so
we've got the default post there for
everything
now should we do like an idle post as
well we'll do
idle
little idol billy idol no it's a spider
idol
there we go so on the idle frame
i'll spread the legs out of it g to move
that on
g if you move it from the top view like
this with inverse kinematics the feet
will always be anchored
really well to the ground so i y you
move them perfectly along that axis
so i should have actually had the
animation thing take down here for
automatic keyframing so i don't forget
insert let's lower the poster there
and should we just do like a wobble
bobble
pose here so this one goes down a bit
maybe the bomb goes up and
and we'll just change the pole angles
here a little bit
for some movement of the legs we want
the feet to be anchored though
that's important because you don't want
them to move
around on the ground so
there and there and that's and as we
rotate the body we could
rotate the turret up a little bit oop
to compensate so it look looks like it's
aiming the weapon forward at all times
and let's see that works and then
we'll do a to select everything b to box
select down there
shift d to duplicate on the dope sheet
to frame 40 and we'll do
39 and 8 select everything shift e and
make cyclic
and this one will loop forever then and
make a pretty good
thing so that could be the idle pose for
if we can hide the armature as well now
that the washing machine is finished i
just noticed
i'm hearing that they're drilling in the
road they're cutting the road up outside
but
don't worry it's for a very very good
cause we're getting fiber finally so i
don't have to stream these things
during my through my 4g little sim card
thing that keeps running out of data
so finally a decent internet connection
all right back to the thing we'll do one
more animation too
so i'll copy this one that's the idle
looks like he's breathing heavily
so wobbling legs there but that's okay
so walk let's try to do a a six-legged
walk cycle
okay how's this gonna go we'll have to
show the armature again
press space to stop it let's do
go back to frame one and the walk here
and
okay so control tab into post mode
select all of them delete everything and
for this one i'm just going to animate
the left side of the spider here first
so i'll take this one
this leg let's move it forward this one
goes back
and this one goes forward i think it's
like a an inverted cycle when they walk
so that one can go forward even to there
and i think i'll skip the pull targets
for now i'll just try to animate the
legs
so i'm going to go forward four frames
one two three four
five six seven eight so i'll go forward
eight frames because now we need to i
think just
move this leg back g maybe to
there this leg goes
forward and this leg goes also back so
it's like
the opposite
and we can't have the legs sliding like
this that looks super weird
so instead of him sliding we have to
lift but
only the leg in the middle here needs to
lift because the ones that are moving
backwards are anchored to the ground
pushing the spider forward
so let's go forward halfway there so
four frames and this is the only leg i'm
going to lift up
let's lift it in to shield this body
there too
like this it looks like it's a different
number of keyframes here
i thought it went from four or four
frames one two three
four okay i missed it
so move it forward and move there
i think that's should work yeah
and then we have to go back to this of
course so shift select these
i'll actually insert the keyframes here
as well i think item set
location rotation and then here
i have to think now this one is going to
come back to this post so
and i have to go eight frames in one two
three four five six seven eight
oh it's on cyclic that's fine that's why
it's animating without the keyframe
shift e clear cyclic that makes more
sense probably
yeah so and i'm only needing to animate
these uh
the rotations of the bones will take
care of themselves since it's a merged
kinematic so ctrl
c and then here we'll skip in eight
frames one two three four five six seven
eight
control v we're back to there and then
here the only difference here now is
that we need to lift those two legs
because they're moving forward
so this is the only one that anchoring
the spider and we have to mirror it i
think on the other side
so halfway through here
there we go one two three four then
we'll lift these legs up instead
front view g move it
and let's protect the body there so that
should be it
maybe you can do this more expressive i
think uh if you tried
so there
i think that works and then we'll loop
it on frame 16 here
shift space that works i think
and now we just have to mirror this i
think for the other side and then make
the body move a little bit
so it doesn't look so static and i don't
think you can mirror we want
them the post is offset as well so this
could be a little bit tricky
you should insert the location rotation
keyframe there
so let's think now i have to copy the
mirror post i think i'll do it straight
forward first so
control let's see can i do all of this
let's try it on the dope sheet ctrl c
ctrl shift v
okay that didn't work i i don't know if
the
paste mirror post works so well when
it's not like on a humanoid so i'll have
to do them manually maybe
ctrl c ctrl shift v
ctrl c ctrl shift maybe it was the
naming scheme that i used that was
broken so that's mirrored
the poses let's just do that for all of
them control c ctrl shift v
ctrl c ctrl shift v ctrl this is a new
one
ctrl c ctrl shift b and then this one
control the reason why you don't see any
difference because when i do ctrl shift
v
it's actually i've only got this one
selected and when i'm pasting it
mirrored it's actually affecting the
dot r bone here that's why it doesn't
change down here
ctrl c ctrl shift v
ctrl c ctrl shift v and then we've only
got a few more
ctrl c ctrl shift v ctrl c
ctrl shift v ctrl c ctrl shift v one
more
bear with me why do i change i could
have stopped it from there ctrl c
ctrl shift v ctrl c ctrl shift d ctrl c
ctrl shift b i couldn't be quiet
but i'm not so this won't work either
because
you kind of have it so symmetrical i
don't think so it works works like that
yeah i guess it was a bit robotic
but i think i'll try to mirror it to see
if the not mirror it i'll
offset it so on this side select the
ik target bones and then i think i'll
just control
i think i only need to there ctrl c and
then just control v
now because these are already mirrored
correctly og og
move it in original gamer there we go
and then now i'll delete these
delete g to slide them down this is
probably an easy way to do this but
there oh and we've got duplicate frames
here need to get rid of them because
they were duplicate
copied a little bit too many and
there and that one should be the same as
this one yeah
that looks better i think a little bit a
bit more creepier but we need to do
something with the body too
so and i have no idea how to animate the
body when it's moving here so let's do
let's tilt it so let's pretend i don't
know there's probably some science to
this which we should be tilting like
where the weight let's put
the weight on this one he's moving
forward with two legs so i guess the
most weight would be on the
on this side so to get some sort of
realism you should always think about
like center of gravity and stuff when
you animate so let's not think about
that too much
no you should think about it archer
rotate g to move it
to there let's pretend he's got the
weight like shifted over a little bit
ctrl c here we can paste the shift a
flip one or something so one two three
four five six seven eight
ctrl shift v that moves it over
and then we have to duplicate this one
on frame 16 control v
okay that's too much way too much
let's do a little bit more subtle then
shall we alt r
alt move it rotate
and let's move it down to there ctrl c
frame 8 ctrl shift v ctrl
or frame 16
is a frame 15 that i meant to do
no 17 oh it's frame 17 okay
easy to get confused control v
not control shift
yes like it's wrong one two three four
five six
seven oh that's on the wrong frame
okay and then maybe we'll do drop it
should we go up to here
ctrl c ctrl v
okay and then we could compensate i
think with the turret as well
so it's like a gyro in here are to
rotate
control c
and then go to frame nine then ctrl
shift v go to frame 17 control v
all right let's hide the armature
okay that could probably looked a lot
better but i think the general movement
of the leg it looks a bit spiderish i
think
so you could probably spend some more it
should be try to slow it down a bit
maybe it's too fast
so show the armature a to select
everything keyframes
scale two oh okay apparently then select
all the keyframes
scale two g move it to here
frame one and then we have to cycle it
on frame 32 instead
we can see a little bit slower here
and it's animated in place now so you
won't really see that it's moving
forward but it should be
possible to animate it forward at a
steady pace i think uh or you could do
root motion and animate it into the
spell
i think that should be all right
but then i think i like the more rapid
it's a bot after all it's going to be
like in a quick game
so let's make it faster again 16. there
we go i like that one more
a bit more rapid come back next week for
another
episode of the 10 minute mauling
challenge it's going to be episode 72
and not only that i'm going to be since
i've had the ludum dare out of the way
now and my wife's birthday which was
wonderful
and it's out of the way but that's not
what i meant to say
like that sounds weird it sounds like i
didn't enjoy it but it was really nice
actually we had a really good time
weirdo okay i'm taking myself a little
bit
of a pity so uh ludum dares out of the
way
um no matter how i put it it sounds like
like out of the way now that the ludum
dare is out of the way and
we've had birthdays we're doing a little
bit to the house and everything but
now it's uh i should have some time now
to do the rest of those
narration uh segments with the little
wild west game the gunfighter thing
so that should be a little bit fun keep
your eyes out for those videos and uh
i'll see you next week i've got a
patreon as well if you want to go there
it's uh patreon.com
infensia and if you like this video give
it a thumbs up and
subscribe if you haven't already and
i'll see you next week bye for now
[Music]
you