right folks just getting set up here
ready to do another ten minute modeling
challenge my camera wobbles a little bit
I have to just get that change so I've
got the camera mounted on a microphone
stand that's attached to the table and I
thought that was super clever first
because it's like a one of those pivot
arms that moves up and down left and
right
really smooth nice apart from that it
wobbles like crazy so every time I touch
the table it wobbles I need to change my
set up a little bit so pardon for the
wobbly Ness hope you're all doing good
by the way and it's a stressful time I
know but we'll get through it
we'll make some blender stuff make some
unity make some games stay inside
just don't let it stop you from having
fun at least hello everyone and welcome
back it's Thursday again and we're gonna
do another 10-minute build I'm excited
it's episode 15 already the years flying
past thrilled about all the visitors to
my channel I'm actually ecstatic it's
gone way beyond my expectations and I'm
think I'm about to pass 40,000
subscribers which is insane because I
was only a tenth while only on 10,000 I
was ecstatic about 10,000 there's about
only a few weeks ago or a month and a
half now so like Rylander so I've also
started another series if you haven't
seen that one check it out as well I'm
doing a little low-poly racing game
since I don't really have the time for
it because the editing takes quite a
long time but luckily enough I get away
with not sleeping too much so I spend
some late nights doing this during the
days I'm working with an RTS game with a
friend of mine I've said a few times
before we're having a lot of fun it's
going really well it's a lot of work a
lot of hard Quarry development stuff
when it comes to multiplayer and getting
all the units and everything working out
for having a blast and we're in an
exciting stage now where we're gonna
move forward not just with the
development but with a business side of
things as well so my days are filled up
with making the RTS games and my
evenings are full of playing with kids
and I have to try to do the recording of
unity and blender stuff in the nights
and also the editing it's a lot of work
but I'm enjoying it having a lot of fun
last summer I bought a set of Warhammer
40k I think it's called some units we
started to put those together but it's
been on the shelf for quite some time so
today after work I spent some time with
the kids we assembled some new ones and
started to you have to glue them
together
Stockton you don't snap them together
you have to glue their little bits
together we don't really play the game
as such yet but it's a lot of fun just
painting paint in those units so here
are a few sample clips from what would
come up with so far
my son Aiden spent probably two hours on
two of those center units now so he's
really enjoying that and so are the
girls as well we're all that all of us
are doing it together so we're having a
good time
and trying to find stuff if you I've got
stuff stashed away in shelves or in the
attic or in boxes or in a drawer it may
be that your reinvent having some fun
without doing these days thanks for all
the comments so far I've got a lot of
suggestions still but this week I'm
gonna go on a little suggestion that my
son had so he wants me to model a
skyscraper or yeah that's Kai scraper so
that's what I'm gonna try to do today
and let's just have some fun make a tall
skyscraper and see what we can put on it
don't even know what its gonna look like
at school we'll figure it out check out
in the description if you want to see my
blender setup video it'll tell you how
to get this pallets on the left and also
how to get this shader view with the
workbench render so you can get the
cavity settings so check that out check
the video in the description all right
with that said let's get cracking I've
spoke way too much go and we are off
it's ticking so tab into edit mode hold
the control key and move this one up to
there a to select everything scale shift
Z let's scale this out and we're not
gonna make it to true scale let's
extrude this one just random extrude
that one e to extrude it extrude again
whatever let's just make some shapes it
e to extrude it someone said that I
should make a t-shirt with this so I'm
probably gonna do that one day I'm gonna
make a t-shirt with e to extrude s to
scale would you buy that merch I'm not
happy with that
let's controls that one okay let's
expand that again expand this e to
extrude e to extrude now maybe we can
put some nice shape here I'm not sure if
I'm gonna be inspired by something in
real life but to to edge select Oh to
enable proportional editing
G to move it and G X actually on a
scroll the mouse wheel down a little bit
got some weird behavior there was all
that about see it's Ollie it's on random
that's good don't want it on smooth so
make sure you keep it on smooth if you
want it not to be random so X let's move
this one out to maybe there so let's see
if we can figure out what what this
building could look like maybe that one
G X move out and that's this one oh
that's okay
seven on the keypad top view eight is an
active note b2 box select and then let's
see we've got all the top phases so just
move those up a bit we take a
proportional way off there move it up to
there e to extrude again pi/2 insects
eat extrude let's just tick off some
things here now actually and we'll just
save some lower parts here this can come
up with us still actually but we'll take
that away and then e to extrude no
actually controls at the height inside
this e to extrude it and let's take a
few things off here so hold the shift
key and just deselect a few things I to
inset actually lets controls that arm
and just take these off as well I to
insert this I pressed elements by by
mistake right in sets e to extrude here
we go let's make that a little bit
higher oh it's meant to be a skyscraper
I have to go way taller than that okay I
to insert this we've got some stuff
going on there in the corner so let's
redo that on take away the edge here
it's a bit too picky actually we can
move this one in by selecting these
edges here shift come and then G twice
and that'll force the movement to the
edge so he doesn't go astray then we can
shift select a few of these again let's
make some terrorist type of things here
so I to inset this e to extrude that
here we'll make a terrace so I to insert
this one e to extrude that one down
let's make one here as well a double
terrace it's not really observatory
heights these floors I don't think so
let's put a swimming pool on this one
it can be here maybe in the center
heighten sets he takes good height in
sets Ito extrude it down and let's put
some water here G on the left side and
move that on to some water color let's
put a deck in here height in set that on
e to extrude this one make a wood color
deck here and then here's a bar or
something like that so let's set up that
height in set e to extrude e to extrude
again as to scale it out e to extrude
ITIN set and B to extrude it down okay
and let's continue up it's meant to be a
skyscraper after all so we have to
select a few more things here let's just
go wild here we can select these all of
those right in set that e to extrude
that and that can stay there for now
let's select its lease leave that on on
the side there so that's gonna be
another terrace e to extrude this o itin
sets each extrude up to here and then
here here we can just go right in sets
and make another little back in there
something like that let's go here for
some weird shape now we can do maybe
keep this shape that'll be a bit a bit
wider so I tend set e to extrude and
here what should we do here we need to
go way high over this one as well don't
me okay I didn't set this one I'm
certainly a skyscraper architect it's
probably not the fanciest skyscraper in
the world oh it's the time 518 ok I
should be alright we just kind of put
some windows on this thing as well so
let's move take to press key twice
move this one into here
if I press G twice it moves it along the
current edge so you don't mess up that
geometry okay let's put a bigger inset
here or it let's put here's like some
sort of our first absorb Atari
Observatory dick yeah so that's a bit
bigger so that's where the people that
don't pay as much will go but for the
people that have a lot of money will go
up a lot more to the top you need to
extrude that one s to scale it C to
extrude extrude again s to scale that
one down need to extrude there's gonna
be quite tall yeah that's good and
here's the fancy X is e to extrude and C
s to scale it out here is that fancy
deck note e to extrude this one I to
insert this one e to extrude it down and
here it's like something sort of up
let's see I have to move this one out
again here G twice so we move it along
that edge so we don't get so close to
the edge I tense the intercept that one
e to extrude these these guys get a roof
here as well it's how much they pay to
get up here so they protect it from the
rain probably not from lightning oh yeah
they have lightning protectors something
okay II need to extrude s to scale I'm
wasting too much time that's the scale e
to extrude s to scale eat extra s to
scale its extrude s to scale e to
extrude s to scale it's it's true as the
scale it down a lot okay so I've got 335
now just kind of put a lot of here let's
put a glass alt and select this ring
select clear e to extrude this one ctrl
+ G on the left side and colorized that
to some glass color and now we're gonna
do a whole bunch of random loop cuts
here so ctrl R and use the mouse wheel
just to put a lot of extra different
type of floors we'll have some different
type of windows here so ctrl R scroll
the wheel that will do here's some
taller windows maybe
ctrl R here we go ctrl R
control are upon share as well and that
should be okay and now let's do go to
this actually we we just press three to
go interface select here we got some
this bitters in the behind G twice
because we needed a fairly straight line
here for the windows so probably do it
like G twice to just move it have to do
good enough all right 2:32 so now we're
going to just all select a bunch of
these alt and shift select multiple
things here where we want windows not
there and we don't want them here we can
have a few windows maybe not there but
they're here we want to put controls at
all shift select open shadows and here
as well and here we want windows all the
way along here we want and there as well
let's skip some floors in between and
that's okay and then I to insert twice
now so first time you it does like that
but if you hit I again now you get
individual faces here and then alt e to
extrude along face normals and go in
just a slight bit G on the left side and
make like a blue window type of thing so
now we've got a whole bunch of windows
for the skyscraper got 143 so we can
also colorize it a little bit just to
break up the colors a little bit so
let's say alt selects my alt shift
select a few of these actually we're
going to do yeah this one maybe that one
do that one and this one and this one
and then G and move that to something
darker just it's not too dark maybe that
was too dark so let's go G on the left
side here in the UVs okay that's it so
about 114 now I'm just gonna be do a lot
a few more things here let's put that's
some sort of a grass thing and here's
just I twice to insert that one that's
sort of a utility thing
and then we can expand oh we need some
windows down here as well I guess I'll
select on item sets twice right insert
twice alt eat extra long normals there
we go Angie move it to color forty
seconds so let's just get some stuff
here on the ground there we go some
stuff for the base you here's some sort
of an entrance thing probably so that
can be so 18 seconds to go now we'll
just get a glass frontier
eat extrude that on on four three two
one that's it
I'm not even stressed this time sorry
about pop I apologize I made a habit
some of the later builds to become
really stressful so I'm sorry if we came
here to see me get stressed out every
now and then I should probably just go a
little bit easier so I don't have to
flip out like I do sometimes but I will
pressure myself many more times don't
worry about that I've got loads of
thoughts about doing like 10 aircraft or
animals I've got a plan for I've got
weapons I've got so you name it so don't
worry I'm gonna stress myself out in the
future again this one didn't stress out
too much so there we have it
it's a skyscraper it's not an amazing
piece of architecture I hope it's all
right son I don't know if I did you
proud on this one but I tried my best to
not stress out this time and just that
have a little casual modelling session
here every now and then it would be nice
to do a few of those as well so and I
realize here I didn't put any fencing
for the poor economy view deck here so
we're gonna have some casualties here
we're gonna have some people blowing off
the sides here they should have paid for
the top floors they've got some nice
protective glass there so keep that in
mind go to the top if you can I should
also mention that I got a lot of
comments and I don't know if I deserve
so many nice praises because I don't say
I just do these things to practice my
own modeling skills I'm not trying to
show off I'm not trying to do the most
amazing builds that you can in ten
minutes it's just a personal challenge
that I invite other people to watch and
hopefully learn from I'm really happy
that people can see it as tutorials it
wasn't designed to be tutorials it was
just me having fun doing some some
challenges and the fact that people
learn from it is just an extreme bonus
and I'm really happy about that but I'm
not gonna be able to push myself to to
better myself every time I've realized
that I'm not gonna put that pressure on
myself either it's stressful enough as
it is trying to fit these modelling
challenges in every week so I'll do my
best to to just that keep it all the
casual look every now and then I'll
probably freak out and stress myself out
like I did with the cars
I get a message at 1:30 in the morning
who is this it's my friend Jim if you're
in the chat Jim you shouldn't be texting
me this time well you should you can
text me anytime because I should just
mute my phone it's my own fault
so I'll have a look at that later Jim if
you're in the chat today and during the
premiere you were here last week so nice
to see you it's been a long time since
we met Jim's a good friend of mine we
grew up together we've haven't seen each
other in a while mostly because I've got
way too many things sort that I think I
need to do but I should prioritize and
go and visit him again but I have to
wait until this quarantine thing goes
out so maybe in a few months or
something like that well fingers crossed
we can see what goes on
anyway I hope you enjoyed this video hit
the like so if you did subscribe if you
haven't already and I think yeah
come back next week we'll do another one
shall we have a good week until then
stay safe have fun you know what to do
bye for now
[Music]