hello folks and welcome to episode 31 of
the 10 minute modeling challenge which
is turning out to be the 10 minute low
polling modeling challenge but that's
okay with me luckily enough i like low
poly so i'll think i'll stick to that
style for now
and then i'll have to practice some high
poly in the future this week a few more
merch samples came along so i tested
those out to see what the quality was
like and also what the prince was like
otherwise i've also got a vacation this
week so i'm not really working on the
rts game at the moment but i'm still
trying to fit in videos and i've just
recorded
four hours of a unity tutorial that i'm
editing now i'm hoping to release that
in the next
couple of days hopefully going to be an
exciting one and it's going to be for
the absolute beginners or people that
want to make sure that they've covered
all the basics
and it's also going to teach you how to
write your first c-sharp script if
you're scared of that sort of stuff
check that video out it's coming up very
soon so with vacation been chilling a
bit in the garden
uh playing a lot with the kids the
weather has been pretty nice so we've
also been out
for some walks around the area where i
live here in nina sam
in sweden and uh saw some boats that i
will never be able to afford probably
but it was nice to see them
and we've been riding some bikes a
little bit mainly the kids may have just
learned how to ride bicycle the other
day so she's like going up and down the
street
then i even hopped on mine for a few
minutes as well brush up on my wheelie
skills
that said we're gonna go into today's
topic if you've seen those isometric
pixel art
images of the little city blocks or
something like that i guess it's a bit
like a diorama i'm gonna model like a
little slice out of a town
and make it the so it should hopefully
look alright in
isometric view so basically that's just
uh
orthographic non-perspective but you
have an angle to it so it looks a little
bit
weird sometimes but the style could look
pretty cute as well especially for pixel
art it looks good so maybe it'll work
for low poly as well who knows so with
that said let's get started
go yes and we're off tab into edit mode
select that face ctrl i
and delete all those faces we'll just
keep the top one ctrl snap it down
scale 10. ctrl r let's make
19 loop cuts to keep it in sync here
with the grid
then 7 on the keypad top view and then
let's select or some road segments here
let's just do something like this
and then ctrl i again we want to raise
up
e here to erase the sides a little bit
ctrl i to invert
ctrl minus make it dark like tarmac
or asphalt i to inset it insert again
ctrl plus to expand selection b and hold
the shift key and deselect
the tarmac node so we just get the road
markings g on the left side and make
those
white then do box select let's make
something here for uh it could be like a
building there
maybe a car wash here could be maybe a
diner
and some other building maybe a post
office or something here
and here could be another building
whatever sort
and maybe a little shed there or
something
in a town i don't know e to extrude
two units and then now i'm actually
gonna
a period individual origin scale and
make some rooftop things
e to extrude eye to inset
eat extrude again now i'm gonna control
plus a whole bunch of time let's make
these white so they pop out a little bit
control minus and just select this top
and make that really dark
to make a lot of contrast in the picture
now i could do
for this one i actually want to make it
a little bit different this is going to
be a skyscraper
thing but i can still keep it maybe like
that so i'll e to extrude that one
up a bit it's not going to be a
skyscraper but a taller building anyway
or part of it maybe
so i'll select that one control plus out
to make that a little bit different so
it doesn't look like the
same roof as the others maybe like this
and then make it a little bit brighter
like that okay so pardon me this is
gonna be a diner of some sort
maybe i'll hold the alt key ring
selector on
or loop select that's gonna be the
entrance control r a few times first
actually i don't wanna
make smaller windows so deselect those
to i to inset twice to get individual
windows alt d to extrude long face
normals
just a little bit make blue windows here
we'll make an entrance so i'll do
i to inset at press twice scale
x e to extrude it in
and itunes set that one control plus
first to make it dark
control minus on the keypad and make a
glass door there as well
and here we could make one of those uh
what do you call those uh things that
are
on top of things it's like a marquee
thing
e to extrude like shift d to duplicate
that face first
e to extrude e to extrude again
move that face down ctrl r let's do
eight cuts so we hopefully get
an uneven amount here or is it even i
don't know
shift alt click select to loop select
those shift select those
and shift select those and then do g and
make those red
a bit diner-like maybe i'll select a few
things on the roofs here as well that
could be
maybe some coolant things or fans or ac
it's called
air condition i need to extrude
items that beat extruder and control
plus
maybe they look a little bit too uniform
but i'll have to be okay with that
okay the post office maybe that they
can't afford as nice windows
so let's do ctrl r first
actually i keep forgetting
and then shift d select those i to
insert twice
alt d to extrude along base normals
and g also blue windows and here
maybe they've got some fancier windows
here whatever this building is
so they've got corner windows hey fancy
so i
twice alt to extrude long face normals
and blue as well okay here's going to be
the car wash
so i to inset that one and bring it down
so the cars can actually get in
e to extrude inwards here i'll do
let's make that dark in there so g
move there here shift d scale it down
and then right click and subdivide that
one
and then do f3 circle that's the loop
tool add-on
e to extrude and then l to select link
then make a
red brush thing can a car even fit there
scale shift y make it a little bit
smaller like this
that should do okay here maybe a back
door here
not in like an i.t security type of
backdoor just a literal backdoor
maybe brown here could be also some
shed maybe not shed why would there be a
shed in here
that could be a window okay let's make a
dumpster
back here shifty scale
y move it e to extrude
he took street again scale e to extrude
what does the dumpster look like maybe
like this will do
i'll l to select the length g it has to
be green i guess
i to inset let's make an open one e to
extrude and move that one down to there
make it dark there okay so we've got a
door here for the
post office item set e to extrude
maybe it'll do a little bit darker there
but they've only got one
actual door here height instead that one
need to extrude
but it's gonna be glass as well maybe
we'll make a little
roof sticking out here height and set e
to extrude
move it down maybe control plus maybe it
could be orange
so we've got the car wash there maybe
that could have some
utility boxes here
so python set that one need to extrude
control plus let's make that great some
water pipes and things
okay we have uh 354 okay i have to do
something here as well
so this is going to be the entrance for
this one item set
e to extrude item set that goes in a
little bit fancy entrance ctrl r
alt select these i to select i to insert
twice
to get individual and now they can be
blue as well so that's going to be okay
we have to have something down here as
well
item set to make
uh let's see alt e to extreme long face
normals that could be
something down there i'll select these
items set these twice i'm not sure what
these look like
alt-d to extrude that's it
okay and uh three minutes okay let's put
a little uh
maybe a flower bed or a grass well just
something with some grass in here
i think set twice e to extrude make it
brown
like dirt height inset e to extrude
control plus make it green just and here
it could be a fountain they've wasted
the the postal
stamp money here now on the
little fancy stuff in front of their
building e to extrude item set
et extrude that could be like a little
red okay and
that's it here is a back door as well
item set you to extrude
and make a brown one there maybe a bin
here as
shift well scale it down make it green
e to extrude s to scale e to extrude
s to extrude that's the scale e to
extrude
and then i'll bring that one up too like
that so 2 minutes 15
maybe they can have a wider window here
as well i to inset
scale on the z axis bring it up
alt to extrude long face normals and g
to move it to a blue okay we can put
some text here maybe so
shift right click there shift a let's do
text rotate
x 90. we have to go into the a tab here
and do geometry we have to extrude it
yep there and then shift space g
losing my voice again so tab we could
say maybe
car wash and then we have to scale it
down
and let me bring it in move it out to
there okay and then shift d to duplicate
that one let's put
uh text here as well they've used the
same sign company apparently
so it's going to look very similar bring
it
up to there but it can't say car wash
there has to say what little diner or
something
little diner creative name
not one minute to go okay so i have to
colorize this maybe it should look a
little bit more interesting right click
can do convert to mesh
right click convert to mesh and then we
have to
pick both of these and change their
shading to
the same material here material so we
can colorize them
tab a scale zero on the left here okay
we've got a problem here
so shading come on why didn't it change
the material
here did that one yeah that one worked
scale zero on the uvs let's make it
red and again it's literally the same
sign company because this one's red too
so 32 seconds to go let's uh duplicate
this
bin here like shift d
they need to be maybe there as well
and they have to have a bin over here
rotate
so a little bit on this slant there okay
and they can have like a little entrance
thing here as well
so 10 seconds to go shift d
move it in scale
scale z e to extrude
l ah that's it okay
the strangest entrance thing ever
okay and we tab and now we have to look
what it looks like in isometric mode as
well
so because this is still perspective but
if i press 5 on the keypad it'll
probably look a bit strange
so but if you've ever seen those pixel
art
things uh i'll minimize the right panel
there
this is usually the perspective that
they'll have on a on the pixel art
what do you think guys does this look
super weird to you
if i go back into perspective mode it
feels a little bit more like it should
and i was thinking this was just the
lower part of the building so i didn't
necessarily go for any details up there
i wanted to frame it something like this
just so you could have something
shooting out of frame a little bit
so i i still prefer it with
real perspective but again i'd love to
hear what your comments are so put in
the comments guys what you prefer do you
like the isometric
non-perspective one or do you like the
perspective view here
so let's see what the comments say
nothing groundbreaking in
this episode it was uh stuff that you've
seen all along
all the time it's gonna be it's a lot of
e to extrude este scale
eye to inset eye to inset and often i
press twice
on i to get the individual in setting
and then alt e to extrude along the
normals in words to get the windows
so what should the tip be then something
that i made a little bit different even
if it's not that groundbreaking and you
might not already know this but this is
the first time i've used
text in one of my scenes and to use text
i did the
shift right click to place my 3d cursor
and then i did shift a and then i added
text
and it's a bit strange and maybe you
don't really know how to edit this text
because i would have maybe expected it
to be
like a text input field here on the
right when you have this text
one so the object data properties here
selected
but the way to edit the text is actually
the same way you edit objects so you
press tab on the object
and you get a little cursor here so
maybe that's a little bit confusing but
then you can delete the text
and put low poly here
and now it's a bit hidden so i'll tap
out of edit mode and then
see there and by default this one is
really really flat
so there's also here you can go into
like i did in the video let's see where
was it
geometry and then you can just slide
this extrusion one up here and that'll
make it
thick to be a 3d object and then
this is actually a some sort of a text
shape now
so it's not a real mesh so you can't
press tab into edit mode to edit
geometry or
things like that so what you have to do
because if you press tab
you get to type in the text here so what
i did then was i right clicked on it
and it did convert to mesh and now if i
press tab
then i actually see the the polygons so
it becomes a 3d object then
so that's going to be the tip for this
week if you haven't used text before and
if you haven't made it
automatically extruded and if you wanted
to convert it to
mesh in the end that's how you do that
all right guys this is going to be it
for this week i hope you enjoyed this
episode as well and a lot of low poly
stuff as usual
check out the links in the description
if you don't have a look at my merch i'm
rocking the
default cube at the moment and then i've
also got a link to my patreon site there
if you want to have a play around and
i've got a discord server as well so
hang out there if you want and
post your stuff that you're making and
make some friends
so hit a like if you liked the video and
subscribe if you haven't already
and i'll see you soon and check out that
unit tutorial that i'm making i'll be
releasing it
very shortly now so if you want to learn
unity check that one out
bye for now
[Music]
you