hello everyone and welcome to the last
episode of the 10 minute modeling
challenge that I will be filming in this
room I think so anyway because tomorrow
we'll be getting the keys for the next
house that we're gonna move to so we've
lived in this house for one year now
since we moved to Australia and we want
to look around a little bit and we're
excited to try a new house in a new
neighborhood so we're moving just about
five minutes in that direction uh to an
even steeper Hill actually so it's going
to be a little bit more exercise when I
go up and down which is going to be
great actually I'm going to be driving
the car most of the time so probably a
zero exercise but still it sounds uh
like it's gonna be a nice place I'm
really excited so uh that's going to be
happening and I'm we still have this
house for another two weeks so it's a
bit of an overlap but I think that I'll
be recording the next episode in the
other house so this is
I probably wasn't lying when I said that
this might be or I said it was going to
be the last one in this room so I better
stick to it so hopefully I'll get the
internet to work the internet to work in
the new house as well and it should be
connected and it should hopefully be
fiber again otherwise I'll panic because
I cannot go back to anything else than
fiber it needs to be high speed up and
down and even to Europe it seems to be
working pretty decently these days but I
that's beyond my control in me but I
think it's only two hop like through
Singapore or something like pretty crazy
so that's going to be happening I'm
going to be literally after this episode
tomorrow get the keys and then pack
everything down and then shift all the
stuff we haven't got a tremendous amount
of stuff because we moved from Sweden
with only 13 suitcases for a family of
five so whatever we've got now is stuff
that we had to panic purchase because we
rented an unfurnished house so we had to
look on Ikea I had to sit for like I
don't know two weeks solid and just
assemble a lot of Ikea furniture so now
we're going to be moving that along with
the washer dryer and because I'm fridge
because in this country when you move
into a different house that doesn't come
along with it so I'm pretty used to the
way it works in Sweden a fridge and a
freezer and washing machines everything
like that stays in the house which is
pretty convenient but in this case we
have to bring it all so that's going to
be interesting but we've got a bit of a
moving company to help us out with that
all right so what else is happening I'm
reading a book how about that for the
first time in my life oh well actually
not true 100 because I did read Rainbow
Six in the late 90s because I like the
game so I thought I'd have to read the
book I love that one and then I've just
not read since then first of all I'm
reading a game design book that I got
recommended so I'll be able to give it a
little review on that one because I need
to learn a lot about game design it's
not as easy as making uh just
technically making a game so here's a
bit of a tip for you if you're
interested in making games a lot of the
courses out there Focus very heavily on
just like how do you use Unity how do
you get a thing to move how do you jump
how do you do a platformer how do you do
a first person shooter how do you do a
racing Simulator game but very few
actually focus on the fact that you know
it should really be a fun game it's
taken me about 20 years to realize that
because it's very easy doing doing like
15 ludum tires that I've done I've
learned it the hard way that it's very
easy to put together the game and you go
oh this might be fun and then you get
the feedback from players going nah it's
not really that fun and then you
actually play it yourself and you go
you're right this sucks it's pretty bad
so I'm really wanting to upload level up
my skills on the game design so I've
learned a lot through the Journey of
line War as well because uh my code Dev
there is really good when it comes to
the balancing in the game design and why
things should and should not be in the
game and I hope that to be able to adapt
a lot of that thought process and I've
learned a lot of stuff not to do as well
for example don't make a game that
doesn't have single player like everyone
told us not to do and we've learned it
well still we prefer the multiplayer
part but if you want to have a
commercially successful game then you
should probably implement single player
and listen to what people say problem
for me reading is that I fall asleep all
the time and I've got the Kindle version
and Kindle version sucks
Kindle app sucks and I was really
surprised because I thought since it's
been about 10 years since I saw Kindle
and I thought surely it must have
improved super good text-to-speech and
everything like that I can just download
the book and listen to it and they've
disabled the feature you cannot actually
enable it anymore because I think they
just want you to buy a Kindle device
instead but I don't want to do that
because I've already got a phone and
I've got I've vowed not to get too many
electrical devices am I recording yeah
so I'm not going to buy a Kindle app I
just want to be able to read it on my
phone and I want to be able to switch on
text-to-speech on the PC version it has
text-to-speech and I enabled that and I
thought I'll listen on my PC then how
about that it's tough to bring along but
at least I could sit down here and
listen to it and if you want to have a
book read by Stephen Hawkins it's an
excellent thing because I don't think
they've stated their speech synthesis
it's like like 9080s or something so I
don't recommend it unless you're
actually reading a book written by
Stephen Hawking maybe that could be good
but I don't want to listen to all the
books like that it's not good not
recommended let's just stick to the news
as well blender version 4.0 is coming as
well exciting huh and I'll summarize
exactly what's exciting me about blender
4.0
with that said let's move on to
something else because I couldn't
actually find anything that interested
me in version 4.0 of blunder and it
seems to be it's like uoi tweaks and
some basic rigging things and maybe a
lot of stuff with geometry notes which I
don't really use because I haven't found
a lot of use of the geometry notes yet I
like to customize my low poly stuff and
just stylistically model stuff even
though I'm into procedurally generating
things I haven't been able to do
anything that I necessarily want to do
with geometry notes so I'm not super
excited about for the oh yet but maybe I
will be maybe someone will correct me
and go hey you should check this out
button so if you know something that I
don't and that you think would interest
me go ahead put it in the description
one more update as well since we're on
the topic of intros that are way too
long for a 10 minute video check out the
ghost behind me
it's the it's the Pac-Man ghost and last
week it cost their crayons anything
called crayons it caused chaos with my
white balance because I had it on auto
white balance which I know you're not
supposed to have but I thought nothing
is changing in the room well the ghost
is Shifting color so I look like an
Oompa Loompa half the time and then I
look like a ghost myself half the time
but I think I've fixed it now because I
fixed the white balance so it should be
fixed now and hopefully that goes behind
me should just shift colors instead like
the way it's meant to be doing I'm
actually also reading another piece of
text and I should probably not mention
anyone here by name giselda I still well
actually I can't really say your name
but I'm really excited to read what
you've got cooking there I know it's not
sci-fi you say well I call it sci-fi but
it's like a fiction anyway I actually
really enjoyed reading it so keep up the
good work and keep that going because I
want to read the complete thing now I'm
hooked onto your story so keep up the
great job on that one I'm really excited
to read more what you've got going there
all right so I think that's pretty much
sums up what I had to say and that's all
I had to say about that maybe some
people actually came to watch the
modeling so I'm going to be jumping on
the Discord challenge again the weekly
Discord challenge has been going on for
well over a year now and thanks to Arvid
who's relentlessly putting up new themes
and collecting all the stuff collecting
it into git repo and he's waiting for me
to create a video where I'm going to go
through it and I'm panicking now because
there's so many submissions there over
like 50 weeks that I haven't gone
through so I don't really know how to
tackle it but I'm gonna probably build
up my courage and tackle it at some
point in the new house when we move
there and maybe I can't really go
through all the submissions but hey he's
done it so good that it's got preview
images so maybe I can select the best of
so if you've been participating in the
Discord challenge there stay tuned
because I'll create the video about it
and maybe your image will be reviewed
and I'll get some feedback some
criticism should I be harsh should I be
kind should I be both I don't know I'll
figure it out so I should criticize my
own junk sometimes as well because half
the stuff I make look here hideous but
I'm not afraid to say that just look at
my thumbnails from the 10 minute
modeling challenge but then hey if you
haven't followed me before this is where
it comes in to just focus yourself on 10
minutes because then you've got an
excellent excuse X excellent because you
can say hey I did that in 10 minutes
what can you expect what else have I
been doing well I thought it was going
to go a lot faster but I spent
apparently 35 hours roughly modeling
interior objects for the low poly packs
and they're compatible with a crispy
crisply characters mini so now I've got
crisply Interiors modern really like
backwards with the naming there but it's
crispy Interiors is the collection and
then it's the modern because I realized
I have to do fantasy packs or sci-fi and
cyberpunk in the future as well so I've
created this one took me about 35 hours
because I know that it took about 35
hours because I recorded the whole
process and then I turned it into a time
lapse that I played at four times the
speed and that turned into about seven
seven and a half hours so if my math is
correct which it probably isn't well
maybe it's 30 hours or whatever so I'll
figure it out yeah I'm really excited
about that one because I imported all
the objects and created a little demo
scene inside of Unreal Engine and uh
Unreal Engine is really cool because it
actually works extremely good now I got
Nani to work and then I also got the
Lumen which is doing beautiful work
actually with the emission so with the
in fancy a pixel texture that you might
be using now hopefully if you haven't
just check out the link in the
description and go grab it because that
emission works extremely good in Unreal
Engine so the Lumen just picks up all
the emissive surfaces and actually uses
it pretty much as a light but without
any Shadows but it I'm really happy with
the way it looks so I'm excited about
that one so that pack I'll be releasing
onto my website and I've also got some
other channels where I'll be releasing
it one of them being the unit asset
store and then when the Fab store is
coming from epic later on I'm going to
be releasing it there too and I'll also
give it to my hero tier on my patrons as
well just need to finalize the packaging
and then launch it and then move on to
the next pack all right then so I know
you've been waiting a lot for the
modeling now but I just want to say one
more thing actually and that is I had a
few more questions about Ultra Nova so
earlier a few months ago I released some
teasers about Ultra Nova and I developed
that prototype that was going to be the
full game inside of unity and since then
I've realized I actually love the the
way that Unreal Engine is presenting all
the graphics and the way I can just cram
all the polygons in there so I've been
learning behind the scenes pretty much
Unreal Engine to the point where I'm
starting to feel quite comfortable now
at least with the with the way I can do
the graphically and the graphic
appearance and stuff I'm still learning
a bit of C plus plus and the blueprint
still still got a long way to go but I'm
at a point where I can soon start to
actually assemble what I had in unity
into Unreal Engine and then I'll be
building it from there so I'm really
excited about that one and behind the
scenes it's also been a huge process to
update the game design document because
uh I I have to whisper now because one
thing that is not popular amongst my
subscribers is AI and if I say AI I lose
subscribers I that's why I'm whispering
that and when I created a video thinking
that this is going to be popular because
I said I'll I asked chat GPT to help me
make a game and then it didn't really it
wasn't that popular and I think I
understand why because it's like
everyone's doing that and then while
we're discussing it in the Discord and
it's actually not really that good to
come up with a game design because it
can provide some useful hints but if
you're expecting it to create a Sci-Fi
story or a fictional story it's just
gonna left and right grab stuff from all
over like existing stories and it won't
tell you it'll sound confident like it's
coming up with something on the fly but
it turns out like the names are taken
from this one names of the planets is
taken from this the story plot is from
this either game or series or sci-fi or
book or novel and you don't know what it
comes from so people will be able to
recognize that so again I shouldn't name
drop here but but yazilra that's what
I'm going to say is helping me with a
really cool story so I'm I'm super
excited to share more about that so
we've been working in the game design
document a lot so thumbs up thanks a lot
for your help so far I'm really eager to
actually put all the stuff that you
helped me with there and straighten the
story out it's a really cool plot now
it's got a lot more twists and
characters and everything's strung
together nicely we'll still have some
work to do on that front but I'm really
excited I think it's going to turn out
to be a really cool platformer now it's
gonna have some swing backs to turken 2
style because I love that that era of
gaming I like the Sci-Fi part of it the
robot style character I like the glowy
neon firing balls and then I like the
music style and everything like that so
it's going to have a lot of those
elements but a lot of new fresh contents
as well so in the form of a narrative
that's going to be way better than
anything I could have come up with in
Ultra Nova there's going to be a load of
drone enemies and the theme this week in
the 10 minute not in the 10 minute
modeling challenge in the Discord is
actually drones you can make either one
or more and I'm gonna try to wake wake
make one drone here so a drone it is and
I'm gonna be modeling it right here
right inside binder 3.6 now no need to
go to 4.0 beta because I know it's a lot
of hype but I don't need that I don't
need crashes anyway so I'm gonna stick
to 3.62 for a while Ready Steady
go we're counting yep we are all right
so I'm gonna do shift d to duplicate the
top face there move that to the side
let's do automator actually because I
want to be able to have the Drone arms
here and then this one I'm gonna do
e to extrude and control R oh no do you
know what I'm gonna make this I'll do my
usual check right click subdivide and
next go Circle X and then dissolve
limited and then e to extrude and here's
gonna be all set well it's not going to
be there high to inset
and right click and let's do a bridge
faces so there we go our little cylinder
that I want and then I'll e to extrude
this one as to scale its scale on the
z-axis Maybe and I can't remember what I
don't look like but it's okay
um and then I'm gonna put the propeller
thing in the center here
Shifty to duplicate F to uh just do that
on alt and then flip the normals do I
need to do that no probably not
okay but still and uh how should I do
the propellers here I'll do Ester scale
it's extrude and
L to select the link and just grab this
one on the left here and move it up to
here some gray color there we go and
then alt right click F3 and then just do
checker deselect and ALT extrude long
face normals there we go
have I got back facing on
okay that's not supported there I
thought it was flipped so alt n flip
there you go
go back I actually like the model in
this view these days Zed and material
preview there I don't know why
so we should do
control okay so here's the stupid thing
why am I modeling this one like this
should not really be modeling all the
blades at once you should do like an
array modifier or something like that
but never mind I'll try anyway I'll test
the scale scale on the z-axis
uh make this scale and okay and I'll do
period individual Origins period and go
normal scale on their y-axis
alt D to extrude long face normals and
maybe I'll do rotate on the z-axis
uh there we go
I actually want this low poly look so
I'm just going to keep them like that
each extrude s to scale and I'll do some
heat extrude that's the scale there so I
think that's pretty good that's gonna be
it for that little drone propeller thing
here anyway it actually needs to be
attached somewhere it's extrude should
it be from the top or the bottom the
bottom I guess that's just oh no I won't
scale that on yet I'll move it up it's
extrude and then we'll just do some sort
of a connection here
bolt said that'll do eat extrude
and well we can just bring it into there
that's it so that makes a little bit
more sense
and then we'll do e to extrude that's
the scale there for a little bit of
feature how am I doing seven minutes
okay so I've only got this thing I can
uh maybe I'll do a little bit more
detail here as well I don't know what to
do yet but let's scale this down
alt select there
and let's do it inset all tests to scale
them down then I don't know what to do
here but let's just punch a hole here or
something no we shouldn't
I'll just do like a little eye to inset
and all test to scale along normals that
should be I'll be okay I think
some darker color here for some reason I
want that have I got proportional one
nope
all right L to select the linked G to
move it okay now I need to L to select
this linked as well that's it then I'm
going to put this one here
rotate it maybe okay I need to do comma
and do Global period medium Point rotate
and should I do I think I might do six
just because I can duplicate them so
fast
Shifty white just have four that's
boring
so I'm gonna be doing it like this
instead
yeah that's it I have no idea why I do
that but never mind
so we'll bring this one up here and then
what am I doing five minutes so half the
time is done
um e to extrude
let's go each extrude here this is a bit
like a spaceship I guess
scale z e to extrude S to scale I think
I'll scale this one too I have no idea
really what to do here
so I'll just have to randomize a little
bit e to extrude I think I want to have
like
each extrude for some reason I feel like
having something that pokes out like
this
and then I think I want to have
something Ctrl R Loop cut can never go
wrong just add some more detail there
and I should probably LL to select the
link here move this one forward and I
think I'm going to do like some
indentations here
so I'll Ctrl R to Loop cut here Ctrl R
Loop cut here Ctrl R Loop cut there Ctrl
R Loop cut here
and then we'll just do shift select
these eye to inset
alt D to extrude long face normals
and then I'll color this one a lot
darker
so that looks a bit strange but I think
it'll it'll be okay then alt select here
scale on the z-axis and here I should do
as well maybe I want to have something
the houses like a camera here as well
eye to inset B for the boundary in the
center alt e to extrude long face
normals G get this one to a dark color
there again and then I'm just gonna do
some sort of a lens here so this is
going to be a problem because I'm going
to be actually I'll do two lenses
because that's going to be easier than
one lens since I'm in mirror mode here
so I'll grab this one shift d to
duplicate it but I have to disable here
on the modifier I have to clipping off
so I can just move that into there
so let's why not make two camera lenses
here stereo yeah it's filming stereo so
it's good for VR right right click
subdivide Circle scale it down clipping
back on because I always forget it but
not this time G to move it to a a
brighter gray maybe I'll do metal out of
these later on so I'll do e to extrude
and it's going to be failing downwards
because this is like a surveillance one
so surveillance why can I not say that
word alt the extra long phase normals
again uh each extrude estas scale each
extrude and I to inset and e to extrude
it looks looks like a pair of binoculars
why not
so should we do like a focus ring as
well automated of course so iTunes that
all tested scale and Control Plus and do
that a little bit darker as well and
then grab this one
and I forgot to press X and do limited
dissolve each extrude that's the scale B
to extrude looks a bit quirky it looks
like a pair of binoculars this turned
out to be like a comical one instead but
let's go for it
I've got three minutes to go so I'll
just add some quirky details here maybe
something like this and I think I'm
gonna add a pair of eyes for navigation
as well this is gonna be more like the
uh the stuff that it uses to navigate I
think alt e to extrude because we make
can make these shine a little bit
instead so I'll do scale this one down
okay no I don't want to do that GG to
slide it down
gee okay I'll have to just Freebase this
one a bit it's not called Freebase I
don't know it's called free free freebie
or something
okay that's no good but I'll do like
this and I know I'm twisting the
polygons now probably a big time but
never mind
still gonna do it g g and GG to slide
this one and now I'm just gonna do eye
to inset and ALT D to extreme long face
normals scale that one down and this one
we can go and miss it right so
should we do like green eyes I think or
red probably evil red eyes there we go
and then I still got two minutes to go
so we have to do something about this
hideous top here and fins can never go
wrong uh unless you're from Sweden then
fins are not
well they're neighboring countries so
it's pretty cool uh we'll do comma scale
Y and scale why well I said why but I
did X so
ete extrude and Esther scale and I'm
running out of time so I'll just have to
put some stuff here now
so here's going to be some sort of a
hatch
we'll do actually should I do this way I
to inset alt D to extrude long face
normals scale it down and move it okay
pick comma again in global move it in
and then I'll just go darker
to there
and then we'll put some stuff as well
some exhaust here or something no just a
hatch here
no that doesn't work either
so I'll do what should we do
Okay iTunes that I'll just wing it a
little bit now that doesn't work either
because that one's messed up GG
iTunes set all tests to scale I'll do
some armor plating that should do
so itin set all tests to scale this
creates like a panel effect look
um we can just do it inset eat extrude
as the scale this is some sort of a
housing of something I've got 45 seconds
so I'm just going to add some fake
details here I guess or something under
here as well here's like a hatch where
you can pick things up you need to
extrude maybe quite a lot there
there we'll do eye to insect alt tests
iTunes that here's some sort of an air
intake or something you don't have air
intakes all the time but never mind and
here is something else I10 set we'll
just do this one it instead he took
extrude s to scale
g e to extrude S to scale these are some
like sensors or something uh height
inset
need to extrude as the scale
key to move and two seconds
i e
okay
it's basically not sounding well
[Music]
why do I always make this one there we
go all right so here's the Drone in 10
minutes it's got
you could rig it and have these things
flap about I think it looks a little bit
comical with these binoculars there
we'll go into Tinker Time now since this
is the last episode of the 10 minute
long challenge in this room I'll just uh
do a little tweak version as well I
think I'm gonna try
to change all of this
if I scale
scale it on the x-axis first to zero
okay that was no good here
scale X zero and then I'm going to try
to move it down now to shiny metal
instead
and then I have to scale it down again
and move it to here is this better or
worse
I think I'm going to keep it to the well
maybe it's too shiny actually but should
I bring it to a little a little bit
duller here that one might be good
think I prefer this
and then we can put some more controls
here from above it's going to be
vulnerable so e to extrude
s to scale and here I can just do right
click subdivide
let's go up with the subdivision a bit
like this and then I'll just do some
random
configurations here
where we can put
here
some cyan
blue lights
so some control points there or
something
this one could be red
the little one don't press the red
button
so that could have been none and maybe I
could have put some like Stripes here as
well
so GG slides it remember very handy
eye to inset all tests to extreme long
phase normal so I think I'll indent this
slightly
should we
no I'll just color it then
so instead here I'll put like a
an orange color on it maybe
there
I don't know if I like that
control r s
Ctrl r s
I think that's a little bit better look
to it
and maybe it should have been here as
well maybe we can put it inset
bring that to Orange as well
just some colorization on it no that
makes no sense either
and I don't think it should be orange
there because the thing is I'll put it
on red instead
it's like a mark a red mark one
and I think just for some to break up
the colorization a bit I think I'm gonna
grab these and change
the color choose something a bit darker
and then I think I might do that
blades
brighter so l l
there we go and let's make those like a
really bright metal
and these lenses I guess we could do X
and do limited dissolve and then I'll
slap them slap slap
them onto hello where are you
here really shiny but you might not be
able to see that anyway
sorry
and should we put some antennas here as
well
I think so
so how do we do antennas well you know
it shift a to duplicate move it up so we
can see it right click subdivide and
circle scale it down
bring it down again
and do move it there e to extrude S to
scale e to extrude e to extrude S to
scale I might actually keep the lights
on the top there
but I will move the colors here
to like just some plain gray there
and maybe this one as well
there we go eight select everything and
then just move them to
different color here as well
and I think I'm gonna do it a bit
brighter actually
so there's our antennas and
it's gonna broadcast the signals back
here now
should I put more antennas on Shifty to
duplicate
scale
G
forward a bit no that's good
and maybe some sort of an exhaust here
as well item set
heat extrude and then we'll do another
round thing here shift a to duplicate
move it
right click subdivide Circle scale it
bring it scale it
G to move it down
each extrude
G to move rotate
scale quite not scary though
we'll scale the whole thing down scale
he's a bit twisted but I'm okay with
that rotate on the x-axis
G and then just gonna do it inset and E
to extrude S to scale
Control Plus and these will just do
non-reflective
black here
so I don't know if it runs I guess it's
running on uh electricity but it looks
like it might be on petrol this one
they save their moments with some petrol
using so
I don't know what to do I change that
and it's extrude and I think that's it
so with some additional time there we
had a few more things you could like
create some claw things as well maybe or
some more armor plates I'd inset all
testes scale
height inset all test to scale and here
one more thing eye to inset and
alt e to extrude long face normals
Control Plus
and then just do this one a and then
dollar and darker
and obviously you'd have to make them
spin if you wanted in the game
alright folks so there we have it a
drone to go with the weekly modeling
challenge if you want to join in on the
weekly modeling challenge if you don't
know what to model if you want to boost
your skills and improve yourself share
your work and get some feedback from
some Discord members lovely Discord
members jump into the infancy Discord
server it's a link right in the
description there join us have a chat
talk about all sorts of random things
about modeling or game development or
watches play games or share our work
when we stream a little bit there just
go left and right if you're bored
whatever just go in there hang out a
little bit with us and we'll have a good
time speaking about these type of things
all right so with that said I'm gonna be
summing up this video I'm going to be
uploading this model here to my patreon
page to the tutorial tier they will be
getting a hold of all of the stuff that
I make in the 10 minute modeling
challenge so head over there I do it in
batches so it's not going to come out
right away I'll do like about 10 at a
time when I do upload them so I hope you
enjoyed the video and subscribe if you
haven't already and give it a like as
well if you don't mind that'll help me
out a bunch until next video have a
great one and I'll see you then bye for
now
[Music]
thank you