hello everyone and welcome back to yet
another Thursday I'm gonna spend another
ten minutes in blender I'm gonna model
myself a car I don't even like the
article what am i 12 I'm gonna set
myself aside ten minutes to create a
bunch of cars I'm gonna try to make
eight cars at least maybe even more
let's see how that goes I'll just put
some simple colors on them as well I'll
use the simple UV technique that I've
used in many of my other videos you can
check out the link in the description if
you want to see a little video where I
set up my start scene it's very few
tweets nothing complicated create a very
simple texture I'll link to the texture
file as well so you can download that
one and I just make some viewport
changes and add two add-ons now it's
gonna be the bull tools really handy and
also the auto mirroring auto mirroring
so thanks a lot for everyone who
suggested that I should start using
those they are actually saving time but
without further ado let's get started
straight away let's model some course go
tap inside it mode a scale on the left
side G and move it in green here scale a
mesh why - and then let's grab the
bottom face here shift space G and move
it into place here and then now let's do
ctrl e to subdivide the edges here and
let's do two cuts here let's apply this
one back e to extrude it up scale it
down and then shift right click here
shift a for a cylinder let's change it
10 faces are wide 90 degrees side view
control and then rotate it on our scale
it down for the wheel houses here that
should be okay and I changed the color
here to green as well I'll make better
cut shift D duplicate it move it to here
and then now with L and then let's see
I'm okay there move it out a bit P
separated to an object select this
object shift select on ctrl shift - and
then now let's do auto mirror for this
one yeah that's good and go into edit
mode again the shift tab move forward
from you make a bumper here and scale it
down G to move it down and G to move it
up to here
make it great shift the G move it here
let's make it white for a number plate
shift D again right click and then
disable clipping here make headlights
shift
actually make that one yellow 50 make a
rear-view mirror scale it down a bit
change that one to green as well let's
get it done and then let's move this
mirror back to here where it needs to be
and now actually shifty let's make a
door handle as well so these are just
faces for now we're going to change
those in a second shapes big scale X
into there and move it back to here and
then change that on the gray now I'll
shift select all of these eat extrude
them and control R let's make this one
ctrl + very well make an indicator light
here and for the rearview mirror here
let's do I - insect eat extrude in and
change it to a blue window color there
and then e to extrude or a glass color
scale move it down from you G okay and
now let's do select L here select all
these linked ones shifty and duplicate
them for the back here and that should
be okay and then L to select this one
select the yellow here and change that
one to read for the taillight now we
need a wheel so shift space cursor to
selected side view shift a cylinder and
let's rotate click thing is off that's
good rotate Y 90 scale it down G scale
it up that's okay
clipping back on scale X move it into
place and a scale movies to zero make
tire it--in set eat extrude you know the
gentle it--in set to eat extrude ctrl +
twice change the rim color to gray shift
select a few of the spokes here eat
extrude and change that to black side
view again and then L to select the
whole wheel shift B and move it into
place here and then now we need to
duplicate this car so I'll tap out to
that one make sure clipping is on you
shift the X minus three and then do
let's a whole bunch of cars 2 3 4 5 6 7
8 9 10 ok and then let's edit this one
delete to focus on it how am i doing 641
control-r it's okay
and then that one's done I think so next
car let's make a little smart career 7
one all set to see all the vertices here
slide this one into place make a little
bit smaller
all set again to see it smooth this
whole thing forward including the door
handle actually the door handle can't go
forward Kenny slide this one back
control or make a window here actually
let's bring the roof down there's gonna
be a small car like actually if its
color Isis as well they should be pink
maybe okay next car let's make an estate
here so tub move on forward this one
forward and you need to mirror forward
as well
now select a vertex here and snap them
into place here for the estate or the
station wagon or slide this one back
control our let's make some more windows
else's like this one shift D to
duplicate it a let's change the whole
color okay now let's make pickup truck
so let's bring that actually just bring
the whole forward this one needs to go
forward and that one too
so 527 let's bring this one forward as
well but on back of it and forward
control our for the window here three I
to in sets be to get that one center and
bring the bat down that's okay
eight select everything let's make the
pickup and make van out utility van or
whatever so gee that's actually I need
to make it bring this forward as well so
I can see and G coupe she slap that one
I'll bring this forward bring this
forward as well the door handle and then
we need to snap these all the way to the
back here as well I keep getting it
wrong and G bring this one back so I've
got autumn air John now so that's good
and control are you get this here as
well ates liked everything change the
colors to the white 431 okay that's done
let's make a police car so let's do come
here actually we can just keep most
things here the way this will just a
select everything will make it white do
a knife cut here to there and a knife
cut here to here and then I'll just
select a few of these spaces and make
them black like a police car color like
that and G make it black it's in setup
here on this roof and it's bringing out
fact e to extrude ctrl + and then change
that color to blue and then ctrl R or a
window here as well again and let's make
sports car so tub being this one down
maybe back a bit
let's bring the mirror with us and this
one to a select everything change the
color here to red make a little wing
here 331 okay move it back down let's
make a little cooler bonnets as well so
let's bring this down a bit k for a
knife cut up there 3 e to extrude s to
scale and inset here and make it out a
bit scale Y e to extrude is gonna be a
big intake here so it's gonna be a
muscle car G do ITIN set this one and
each food ctrl + G here then now let's
make a limousine so top view here
actually do I have a window for the
under control
so 250 so limousine here for this one on
top view here and one for Bob said to
see everything bring all the way back to
their old said bring this foot down a
select everything make a limo here
let's hit ctrl R which makes one shift
space a few those and then now let's
make Lori if I can't bring that on
forward bring this one forward and we
need to shift this forward out there and
see top view outside two minutes ago
vote let's make a lawyer here somehow
outside again three ITIN sets oh no
actually let's do a little cardio just
there eat to extrude make it a bit
higher and back maybe we have to control
our and just bring this one in as well
okay and now let's just make a little
house back here ago so I got 140 do we
need to change the color here so a
select everything let's just make a
white lawyer or a great one and then our
hatch back here now as well I've got 130
to go I need to do the windows as well
so I'll just do control snap that onto
there and snap that one today move this
one back and down control art that
should do okay and then you need to
change the color so 117 yeah okay let's
do all the front windows now so I'll
select all the vehicles tab into edit
mode on all of them shift select all the
front windows one minute four seconds to
go let's do all the rear windows here as
well
I'm shaking now I can no not that one
all of these windows 54 seconds I to
inset Denmark right in set alt e' to
extruding normals and then a scale 0 42
seconds to go let's do all the side
windows now as well so shift-click all
of these 33 seconds to go here and then
I to inset and iTunes that again so
against individuals yeah that's right
19 seconds ulti extrude long normals
found there a scale 13 seconds to go
g-get the window color there and we're
done
I've got 6 seconds to spare what should
I do ah ok
time's up hope I didn't forget anything
though my ambition was to do eight
course but then I thought maybe I can
make 10 but another one down in the
books guys so maybe not as close as the
last one but a little bit too close for
comfort yet again so I seem to be
impossible I hope I didn't break any
geometry again the topology is not
really up to spec if you want to do a
subdividing and things like that pour a
low poly game or a prototype this should
be perfectly fine or a mobile game the
topology is only important if you want
to add detail or if you want to change
the mesh for example bend it or
something like that
and that's not really going to be the
case in this so this type of topology
should work perfectly fine if you just
want to have those cars driving around
on a mobile phone game or something like
that oh guys I nearly forgot to give you
a tip as well this week but let's bring
one in so something I did in this one
was I grabbed one of the cars let's
enter on this one with a Delete key and
I pressed shift D and then instead of
moving it into place I wanted to snap it
by a secure distance so I pressed X and
then I typed -3 to give it adequate
space between the cars and then what I
did was I pressed shift are a few times
because I wanted to duplicate the action
and shift our is repeating the previous
action so that'll do the same duplicate
X minus three and and I did that ten
times to create the ten cars you could
use the array modifier but I don't want
to use that one for this because if I
use the array modifier then I've also
gotten a mirror modifier on it and that
would basically duplicate the whole
bunch of half mirrored cars and it
breaks it alright guys thanks a lot for
watching yet another episode of my ten
minutes and modeling challenge so this
has been episode number twelve and if
you haven't seen the previous ones make
sure to check out my channel history and
check those out as well but anyway if
you liked the video hit the thumbs up
and subscribe if you haven't already and
I'm looking forward to seeing you next
week for another ten minute build so
until then take care and have a great
week bye for now
[Music]
you