raucous and welcome back to another
Thursday it's at least so 26 of the 10
minute modelling challenge and I'm gonna
do more low poly stuff today I'm gonna
make a little red Swedish cottage there
are some regions around here especially
outside in the countryside you'll have
loads of little red cottages everywhere
and I think there's a bunt painted
anything else but red so I'm gonna make
it red just to make sure it fits in hope
you've had a good week so far and I hope
you've been doing a lot of modeling I
know the Sun is coming out it's a bit of
a noise because it gives glares and
stuff built myself like a bunker here
I've got one window and that one I'm
covered up so I couldn't make it look
like night at any time it's quite nice
no reflections no bad conscious that you
should be outside in the sunshine let's
put the phone over here
let's get cranking let's go cottaging go
when we're off carbon turret mode a
select everything's step it up with
control scale and shift said we only
want to go to scale it like that
proportional off here geez at and then
select these two vertices or edges right
click and subdivide I'm gonna make a
roof here so bring that up select these
two shifty to duplicate it s the scale
it's bring it down to maybe they're all
the extra long face normals and like
this and then we'll do right click
subdivide again this time maybe eight
cuts to create tiles I to inset twice to
make these tiles and then all T to
extrude them along their normals and
then now I'm gonna do mesh OOP mesh and
then transform and randomize these if
it's but that's too much 0.03 now let's
colorize them so G on the left there see
two circles select a few lease and we
make them a bit darker proceed to
deselect a few with the middle mouse put
them here Mike and darker and see again
gonna make some really dark eyes okay
now let's select this one again actually
we have select all of them get that into
a different brown now I can select these
you've got to make some planks that
cover the edges of the tiles here so all
to e to extrude long face normals and
then we'll do ctrl + once and I have to
manually deselect this cut loop select
here because I've broken their geometry
a little to sort all t extra long face
that's it and then now I have to say
he's again because I want to call it
these bikes I think ctrl+ and then white
ok let's move to the base make that a
red cottage and then I have to link
these vertices together with J because
otherwise I can't loop cuts after J and
then ctrl R let's do some white corners
here house ok that want to have to cut
them manually that way because I've
broken the geometry there as well so ok
for the knife cut here once
so these corners are going to be white
in Sweden that's common it's called the
tax new tile in Swedish white knots for
some reason no maybe someone knows why
it's called I have no idea but white
corners anyway all t extra-long face
normals control pause and make them
white that's it and here we can make a
door so let's select that face shift D
scale scale X and bring it down to there
eat extra Don I
I have to do both Lisa try to insert
that let's bring this out note e to
extrude out
lt's like linked make it white as well
like the corners but a brown door shifty
to make a door handle here notes X eats
extrude that one it's a big door handle
G black ok and the whole door needs to
go in wait too far out okay here let's
make two windows that one first shift D
doesn't matter if they're not the same
size it's perfectly fine to be honest
it's actually better if they're not
because it looks a bit wonky
can I try to stylize this house a lot so
ll make those whites select these faces
this one has to come out a little bit
more I think we've got something to work
with I to inset all T to extrude one
face normals and then make us
blue okay 6:36 let's make some planks
here so ctrl R to loot cut actually
let's select select a few these planks
every other and do all T to extrude
longface now almost again and we can
just do mesh transform randomize those
with it as well now we're going to
stylize this even more so over
proportional and G to move it I'm gonna
make these corners swing in and out a
lot here I think that looks a bit
cartoony so let's just do that
I've seen better days this cottage when
I build stuff I try it out I go over
done on there all the details with a
millimeters this one was built a lot
faster than okay G let's actually get
the tiles monkey as well it's falling
apart it's got some damp issues here I
think sometime I think we have to have
some surveyor looking at this g-gee okay
let's stylize this door as well the one
care the better okay 515 or something
517 now we can make some colorization
here as well we've got time I think K
for the knife to add some
okay you probably don't want to do this
if you want or actually you could do
this but you should make a separate
level detail version elodie version with
with less purchases and stuff if you
want to use it as a shadow caster maybe
and save some performance or if you
wanna use it as a Collider you should
probably not have all these vertices and
if you want subdivide it but why would
you want to subdivide it a cottage
I wouldn't okay so now we've got those
we can actually three face select and
select a few this I'm gonna make these
darker red so just shift select all of
these and 423 okay there and now we go G
and then alt eat extra long face normals
again and that's it now we can make this
basic scale that on e to extrude it I've
got an extra geometry here no L let's
make it like a rock base for this house
control or tool it cut it once and twice
and three times four times and L to
select everything we can scale it down a
bit again a scale on the x-axis
and now I'll just move these off
actually like as if it's some sort of a
corner stone here we can maybe bring
let's do all T on these as well stick
out a little bit as well shift select a
bunch of these
Balti extra long edges we can reduce
this whole slice of ability okay and a
bit of wonkiness to this as well we
don't want it to be too perfect
we should really have a chimney as well
so oh three minutes let's make a chimney
so let's pick one of the tiles here
maybe that one the sort of bugs shift D
altered if he's like proportional G
should make a great chimney all t to
extrude long face normals eats extrude s
to scale each extreme o
doing spit then probably sorry about
that
I can't even fix it in post because I'm
not editing this section where I model
stuff edit any of this out so I have to
keep everything in that just happened
that's it there's a chimney wonky as
well
two minutes let's make a little days for
this to stand on maybe shift D to
duplicate it s to scale that one out
maybe like this G to move it to gray
well why did I make it greener because I
wanted it clean
Oh proportional off a texture that one
down ctrl or maybe eight Lucas and
control Oregon eight lip cuts and let's
bring this down a bit
selectively here the corner ones here
and how am i doing 1:58 G Oh
proportionally and although the only
work link I don't the house dissing G
said
okay
geez that got some issues here with that
no that's okay
am I getting tricked let's do this
manually then
lower few the corners here it's gonna be
a little bit like a floating island
isn't it all set 113 is a waste of time
also that's it
we can do the base a little bit control
seven to see at the bottom and we've got
some geometry poking through everything
to me yep to rescue you and rescue you
that's it control seven how many links
four to six seconds see two circle
select a few of these just make you
brown eg to move it down e to extrude on
s to scale it of ctrl + it's making
everything brown here how am i doing 26
seconds
gee tune in the hunt that's a
I'll move the handling that's it four
seconds to go
that's it that's our little house on the
island again okey-dokey
[Music]
all right folks so we've got a little
traditional Swedish cottage here with a
little chimney and a wonky door it's
gonna be I wanted to have a really
cartoony wonky look to it hopefully that
came through yeah it looks pretty all
right I think and it's standing on a
little green pasture so should we
disable maybe specular
alright folks so there we have it we've
got a little Swedish cottage here seen
better days I think we need to have like
I said some some sort of an inspector
looking at this because there we've got
some issues with the roof here we've got
some dump issues going we've got some
wonky corners I'm dread to look what
it's inside it's probably bare enough to
just to be a dust which is the Swedish
word for an outhouse where it stinks
pretty much for this video let's see did
I do anything different so I've done
pretty much all the stuff I did one tip
is if you wanted to randomize some stuff
that you've got selected so when you
have a bunch of randomized or when you
have a bunch of faces selected like this
this one is called I think I used it in
the last one mesh transform randomize
that just offsets everything a little
bit and you can change how much and you
can also change some other parameters
there I've just recently started to use
that one and sometimes you have to be
careful because when you warp it too
much it'll intersect itself and you
don't ever want to have like a vertex
here for example you don't want that to
be proportional on G you don't want that
to be poking through the geometry like
that that's bad and if you go too hard
on this randomize that can happen it
doesn't have any protection against that
as far as I know it also works if you
have vertices selected for example you
can go to mesh again transform and
randomize those as well so edges faces
and vertices you can randomize like that
that was a lot of proportional editing
again and some K for the knife cuts to
create these little features to get the
colorization there and just a lot of
proportional editing here too too wonky
Phi it that's a new term one key fight
so instead of doing a lot of tips like
that let's just keep modeling a little
bit shall we
Oh
and a few minutes of modeling so if we
were to continue with this one what we
want to do maybe wanted to add some
plumbing so we could do here for example
on the side which side should we pick
that's this right side here so obviously
this is not part of my 10-minute
modelling challenge now this is the
result that I'll be using as a thumbnail
and this is what I managed to do in ten
minutes
but let's just be a little bit casual
now maybe today let's have a casual
Thursday episode 26 so if I grab this
one and move this down let's move a few
of this time as well what should we do
here for some reason I want to have some
sort of sewage coming out here so let's
move this out so imagine that the house
have got some plumbing in it that we
wanted to see here so if I just move a
few of these I've still got proportional
editing also I have to be careful with
the proportional if you do alt oh then
it toggles here between connected and
not because you have to be careful here
if you've got not connected only there
and you put G to move that one be aware
that you drag the whole house down with
you maybe that's what you want to do
sometimes to make it follow the ground
but if you only want to modify the this
separate and this is actually part of
the same object here we this is still a
default cube remember that we've
modified a tiny bit so this green part
here the grass it's actually part of
this cube object but if I press L here
you can see that it's all the vertices
are connected to only each other not to
the house so if I were to move if I take
proportional off and move it this is
actually just in the same object but a
lot of geometry that's not connected
that was just so much work to try to say
and I still didn't manage to get the
message across but I think you've got it
by note because I've said it quite a few
times so let's see here we let's bring
this down a little bit further even more
key Oh again for proportional this may
be there and here maybe we'd do this
brown a little slumped here
so not that once G move out to brown
here you can see as well that this is
one face now and it's got some struggles
here to render it and so what we should
do here is I should select that on and
that one and press J to link these
together that'll force it to cut the
triangle the way we want it because I
want to colorize these brown hairs so
now we've got a little slope here maybe
I'll do take proportional off shift D to
duplicate it subdivide it right-click
subdivide and then I'll only select
these faces here what am i doing now
actually I don't want to do that on a
scale it down and then f3 and then I'll
type in circle and that'll make it
circle and for that to work you should
have this if you go to edit here
preferences you have an ad on here
called loop tools and it comes with a
unique unit it doesn't come with unity
believe me it comes with blender by
default but you have to enable it and if
you type in f3 and type in circle you
can actually make it turn any geometry
and try to make it into a circle and
then we can rotate it on the y-axis to
flip it up and then e to extrude it L to
select everything here again s to scale
of town and plumbing I guess we should
make it like some sort of a teal pile
teal eye clay color orange no actually I
want to make it
it could be disappointing concrete or
metal metal plumbing select that one
again let's make it a bit brighter no
and now I select these faces each
extruder on s to scale it's e to extrude
it make your pipe entrance here and
again sometimes for a stylized scene
like this you probably don't want it to
be this perfect all the time perfect as
if it was perfect but yeah back with
proportional auto to make sure it's
connected only and then G to move on and
let's just make this pipe a little bit
wonky too because if you suddenly have
perfect geometry I can't it's not
perfect what am I going on about anyway
you get the point so maybe like that and
then Oh proportional off you move it
into there ctrl + and just simulate that
it's shaded in there so I'll move it's a
dark corner and now let's make some
water pouring out - if this is an
outward I can't say that if this is an
outdoor toilet then you probably
wouldn't want windows on it and let's
extrude that one I just did shift D to
duplicate that one now in there and then
I make this blue pull that on now we're
gonna make some water point out here we
can do all zet to see through press the
3 on the keypad no we press 1 on the
keypad to see it from the side here now
we can do that other extrusion method
let's just check actually which one I
want to follow I'll follow this path
here so I'll do one again here I think
it's this one that's the slanting here
so we'll just do some control right
clicking here as if the water is pouring
out here I'll try to follow roughly
where I think it was here and then it
just pours off here so I'm just right
clicking and I should do it hold side
again to see through okay we did it -
too deep but that's ok we can fix it
we can go press o for proportional again
and then do G and then zev to move it up
and then we can do the same here all set
actually first let's select a few these
but not this one ok let's redo that
it's funny it picks exactly the face I
don't wanna pick all set and scare we
can scale this to old said it's kind of
placed here Paul said proportional so we
don't have to be picky at all this so
that's the beautiful that's the beauty
part but we'll select a few these okay
down there
scale y-axis rotate it's okay that
didn't work that's okay
rotate this one just go a little bit
slower now so I can speak a little bit
better about everything that I do rotate
on the x-axis just rotate the roughly
into place there will give me a few know
a few of these faces up and we have to
bring it down as welcome you can scale
this whole thing a bit thicker so let's
just select this proportional is on
scale said okay then I can't select ease
making it a lot more complicated
information that I need to know every
time I try to slow down and explain what
I'm doing I'm doing a worse job at
modeling and I'm doing a worse job in
explaining don't know odd-eyes so small
its scale said
okay I'm scaling the hole in there
that's by scale is that bringing these
up with it awfully proportional again
mm-hmm now that I'm seeing it I'm
actually surprised so much water is
pouring out from this little cottage
makes me a bit scared to know what's
going on in there
I think they've left this sink running
where's the pipe coming there okay so
that's one thing we could have done a
little pipe there maybe we bring these
edges down to make or in together here
make it like so should it be maybe a
little bridge that crosses over here
should it be a bridge crossing over
shift D duplicate that I often work like
this I do shift I pick a face and then I
do shift D to duplicate it because then
it's detached then I can use this whole
trickery with the L key to select linked
and everything like that and I just
reshape that one and then I do e to
extrude it to make it thick and then
Estes killer on and now this is the nice
thing L to select it and then G on the
left here to move that one and then
we'll do just to shift D Y minus one
minus zero point zero point seven and
then shift are a few times make those
planks across and now they all look the
same so we can't really have it like
that obviously so we can just pick one
to do do vertical xo2 get proportional
and then we can just what we could do
actually let's try to do them
let's press L on all of these planks now
and then we did what their tip was shift
l if you're a deselect the whole linked
package like that mesh transform
randomize and now we can actually slide
it up a bit more make it more I don't
have to be so worried the objects are
quite big so I don't have to be too
worried about that they are intersecting
too badly so scale may be on y-axis got
one no that's okay I thought that one
what could have been in the danger zone
a bit but it wasn't danger zone makes me
think of Top Gun that was a good movie
1984 the Swedish number of people that
applied to become a fighter pilot after
that one aired in the cinema was I don't
even know the number but it was a lot of
people that applied and wanted to become
fighter pilots however we got off the
top gun I don't know oh yeah danger zone
that's it so we've got like a lot of
planks here maybe we should have some
posts as well so I can just do another
face we'll pick a random one that on the
loop off with proportional scale it down
keep to move it there get to move it
down get to move it there make it brown
eat extrude it l2 select the links and
again this is the nice thing you just
like back in the day which would have
been like four weeks ago or something I
would have not really made stuff so
wonky but then what I was modeling the
part island I realized that the wonky it
is probably the better it looks when it
comes to like a low poly look so don't
be afraid don't try to make everything
perfect and aligned and stuff like that
if you've got any sort of OCD similar to
what I've got which is like I mentioned
it in a previous video as well it's like
symmetry and pixel perfect alignment
that's usually my motto so it feels
quite liberating
no I'm not gonna use that word it's been
contaminated it's quite nice to be able
to just to do stuff like this okay
so that's a maybe we should do some sort
of a rail here as well so we don't want
to fall down into the sewage water which
it might not even be sewage water you
never know what it is actually so shift
D duplicate that face as you can see you
can pretty much take any face here that
might seem suitable put it there
I don't eat to extrude it I'm just gonna
make a really simple plank here but I'll
rescale it on a bit G to move it and
again we don't have to be picky that's
the nice thing have I said the wonky or
the better I think I did but we could
actually make it not go through so much
show but I guess they they could have
chopped it through now we'll do L to
select those links and then here I can
just move that onto that and now maybe
we wanted it to be that could be a bit
thicker like that maybe you want to cut
it like this as well actually control
our loop cut a few those control or
we've got a few those and now with
proportional oh I'll just pick a few
these and we'll even make the railings
here a bit won't you because who would
have cut perfect plank like that if you
build a house like this in a place like
this with a builder like this I doubt
that they'd be using straight planks and
here we could do the same trick as well
we'll do K to do a knife cut here let's
add some of that geometry luckily enough
the number of polygons compared to like
non low poly arch this is so few
polygons anyway that I wouldn't even
flinch to use this on especially on a PC
it's not a problem to have these
vertices rendering I mean you have
objects in some cases where the
characters alone are like hundreds of
thousands of polygons and where I'll
check now actually what counter we out
node you can go brighter as well you
know
right let's do Kate let's make this
brighter so G and step it up a bit there
I works too actually in fact it looks
even better so let's make that one
brighter so we've got little bridge
these are hanging in the air I guess I
could fix that too
let's make some beams here so I'll just
hop into edit mode select that face
shifty you know the drill
I delete that you know fantastic shift
the bring it down scale scale on the
y-axis bring it down e to extrude on
sometimes like now you can see that I've
extrude it in the wrong direction so we
made it to all the back faces facing out
they use this way to fix that it's just
to extrude it in the other direction is
tough so that's the easiest way you
could also flip the normals and stuff
that's a bit of a pain okay there's one
beam let's do shift the rotate rotate
rotate on which axis white key to me
whatever no no no that's okay
no I've got something stupid L to select
our own bar to rotate okay I don't know
what key I press there but controls that
will save you a lot of the time so we've
got a lot British go in there should we
make it we've already made a tree so I
won't really do that but we could make
some grass things growing here so I'll
pick this face deep you know the drill
scale it bring it to that scale it down
even more and now change it to brighter
green move it down and then here we do
the right click to extrude s to scale
right click extrude scale right click to
extrude s to scale right click to
extrude s to scale control our for loop
cut there pick that one right click
scale actually we'll press over
proportional here and then just right
click and you can scale them all
together there
control our look at our scale its
control right-click scale it's for like
minutes so maybe this could be like some
sort of adjusts grass thing growing
there or something what else could we
have we could have a barrel here maybe
they need a barrel not that they need
any more water but let's make apparel
I'll just tick the same place here I'll
pick this face shift D to duplicate it
that's the scale move it up control I
right-click it and subdivide it once
then we've got our trusted F 3 and
circle a circle going G move it to brown
scale it down
get off proportional now we'll just
extrude the first up a bit for the base
ring e to extrude again as to scale E to
extrude that's the scale let's make a
ring here e to extrude this is a big
barrel I have to shrink it that's the
scale e to extrude s to scale that's our
old motto back isn't it
I've said it so much lately I'm right
clicking to extrude all sorts of weird
stuff that's no good is it so that's it
and then we'll in I to insert like that
need to extrude this could be let's just
fill it with water as well shall we it's
plenty of it alt to loop select that one
shift and alt to add loop select on
shift also like to shift all select
faulty to extrude on face normals ctrl +
+ G great when they were got some sort
of a barrel strange-looking barrel
okay I'm a bit down today what else
should we do a little puffy this could
be very simple just cheap move it that's
it
passed on just a different color smokes
down here though you'll fall down okay
we can link this path together without
you randomized this moment of it I'm
here let's see I want to pick this
vertex old Zed then let's try to hunt
this vertex now mission impossible
but it wasn't impossible I just did it
so maybe that one that one should we do
it so yeah let's make this whole thing
you can walk around the house nope
oh yeah got another mission impossible
there we're gonna hunt for the another
vertex there a trick here is if it's
difficult if you just looked at this
picture it make no sense
but if you rotate a little bit you can
start picking out where the vertex is
that you want and it's probably that one
that we want yes and there's another one
your hunt it they wrote tracking lock-on
got it all set done and now this one's
not fitting there is it so let's
actually have some grass right there cuz
I like that that it grows right on the
corner for some reason the grass always
grows at the corner it's difficult to
cut there here let's make this look like
the grass is sticking up a little bit so
I'll select these and then e to extrude
it but let's extrude it down this one we
have to fix I'm not too worried about
the edge here because that's okay
I say that and then I break it so I need
to fix that we can't have this face
coming like that can we no we can just
delete that face select it
delete face and then we figure out what
to do here we can do switch on vertex
nothing you and then do ctrl key and
snap it to place there that's one way to
fix it
m2 merge by distance it removed five
vertices here that were double that's
okay then I'll just select that one
press f2 cap it and then dr. green as
well so that's it I just wanted to go
out there too and we can change these
little bits so they're different
thicknesses and not so uniformed just
some manual shifting there okay this to
be honest there's no right and wrong way
of doing it as long as you do right no
you just pick whatever method works at
the moment and if it works better for
you to do it won't wait do it that way
if it doesn't do it the other way okay
well I've already done a tree in the
other one so I'm not gonna bother to
make it tree no maybe we can just make
like a Ledge here so control has to say
that on let's bring this up as if it's
like an old corner here so maybe like
this and then let's just go eat extrude
that one and here we can do let's do
mesh transform randomized but let's do
it a lot more like this and then e to
extrude again and let's randomize it
again mesh transform randomize and slide
it that's it
and each extrude that one scale is that
now if you want to flatten it again and
then we'll do that I'll just do grass up
here no scale or all to eat extra long
face normals and bring it down like that
grab a few of these as well scale and a
bit differently how am i doing for a
battery battery is nearly dead on my
camera so I'm thinking that I've
recorded probably enough bogus modeling
now if you're still here on the premiere
thanks I didn't expect it to be this
long but you're free to leave anytime
it's makeup but I'm actually gonna
finish off any moment though so I want
to have it should I just do brown g2
move on let's do some more randomness
here Manuel randomness it's the worst
time to randomness humans are not really
good at trying to do stuff random it's
all these song patterns that you're
looking to do or something I'm not happy
about that but that's okay you don't
have to be happy with everything it's a
bit difficult to see the house not maybe
so let's move that one that vertex is
really annoying me that one in
particular
in fact it annoys me so much that I
might delete it and recreate this
because it annoyed me that much and then
I can show you that you don't have to be
too worried about something breaks you
can always repair it so if you wanted to
repair this one you could select these
press f2 no you don't want to do that
let's just do this you could eat extrude
this up let your vertex there's many
ways to fix it press F fix that
colorization there and then that's it
and then you can link these together so
like he's f2 link those and then you
just wanted to show you that you don't
have to be too afraid if something it's
like weird like that if you managed to
break the mesh you could just revert to
your save file that's probably the best
way but if you forgot to save some shift
selecting those pressing F but then it
does stretch this UV so you have to fix
the UV like this but that's not the end
of the world and then there we go you
have to pick the right edges as well f2
lot on mark that vertex
and now I've successfully just deleted
that vertex not annoying me and put it
back again just to show you that you can
actually fix the topology if you manage
to cut a hole don't panic
use the different F to cap the holes and
try to find the edges that should be
connected and you'd be alright I think
that's gonna be it for this week a lot
of extra bonus material they're probably
a bit more than I should have added but
hopefully gave you some extra insight to
do some modelling tips without the
stress of doing it within the ten
minutes but anyway please consider
subscribing if you haven't done that
already and hit like if you liked the
video and I'll see you next week for
another ten minute build alright bye for
now have a good week
squeak - check I've just hit the four
percent barrier of female Watchers as
well so thumbs up on that one and if
insya was a woman she'd look like this
okay that's it am I even in focus
[Music]