we're gonna make episode 25 today folks
uh so
a lot of uh familiar faces in the chat
every week really happy to see a lot of
people joined i think we set a new
record last week
with 418 simultaneous viewers for the
premiere
super excited about that so thanks a lot
boys and girl but i have to say girls
now we got proof now in the comments
that there are multiple women
or girls watching so that's great you
might
notice two changes well first of all
i've shaved that's a bonus i played
fortnite the other day and i hadn't done
that in about
half a year and believe it or not the
first match i had i got a
victory royale in solo and that's pretty
much the first one i got
uh because i'm not so very good not so
very good
i'm not very good at portland in fact
i'm rubbish i i love the
old fps games like unreal tournament
rainbow six
but that was uh easy back in the day
because you had like forward
backward left right to strafe and then
you could jump
and then switch weapons and fire that
was it that was everything that i had to
take care of
and with fortnite uh you've implemented
a whole set of keys that i didn't even
know you could uh press at the same time
by the way that uh just as i got that
fortnight kill
i got a mustache it just like that it
popped out you and i decided to advance
i thought i can't be sitting here he's
gonna knock out
so i start advancing i've got built some
ramps i've got no clue what i'm doing
and uh i thought i'm just gonna charge
here he shoots me with an rpg knocks my
ramp down
i don't secure my ramps or anything like
that and i thought i'll just run to make
sure i get high ground i've not
never done that before i've tried to box
him in i boxed myself in and he boxes me
and
shoot my shook my way up with a with a
tactical shotgun and then i watch myself
in i've got no clue
and then he's above me and i finally
managed to knock him out
with a classical shot so there you have
it guys that's why i've got this
mustache it just grew out after my first
win
so there are two things uh you're gonna
notice different first of all down in
the corner here
you'll see that it says 2.83 because
i've installed the new version and it's
crashed a few times on me
so this is going to be like a big gamble
now i'm going to do uh do some crazy
stuff here
check out my palette guys and girl
loads of guys and a few girls i've got a
gradient going
so i've changed it up a little bit i'm
gonna make a tree that's it
one tree i'm not gonna do a whole forest
i'm not gonna do a landscape i'm gonna
do a tree
but i'm gonna try to put a little bit
more detail in it but it's going to be
low quality so don't worry i'll have to
redeem myself from last
week's octopus giant squid slash uh
kraken that was
like 1.5 million polygons so i've done
it myself enough to last for
pretty much a lifetime so i'm going to
go low poly again and i'm gonna make a
tree all right
focus don't touch my face
it's corona i still haven't learned that
by the time the vaccine comes i'm gonna
have learnt maybe to not touch my face
ready steady go
tab into edit mode and m is the new
hotkey to merge
at center let's just do right click
hold the ctrl key and right click
and it will just swirl up here like in
an s shape for the tree
like this maybe and then
rotate the viewport a bit let's branch
off here ctrl
and let's do another one here these are
going to be branches just that we're
going to make
control to expand that
maybe here
uh just holding the control key down and
right clicking to
get this uh the branch system up
okay let's pick that vertex as well
and proportional rotate z twist a little
bit here as well
let's get this one back to the center as
well
g okay now we're going to apply the skin
modifier here
so if i could click in the right place
skin and symmetry off here and let's
pick this vertex here ctrl a to resize
the skinning
and then here shift g and do amount of
connecting edges and then deselect the
bottom one here so we get all the tip
ones
and ctrl a to scale the tips down a lot
maybe like change the proportional size
okay to there and then now let's apply
this one
and then select this bottom face row or
off with proportional
rotate z rotate set zero
rotate z zero
oh scale zero that's what i want ctrl
r loop cut that one because we're going
to subdivide this one now ctrl
one to subdivide it apply that one
select a few phases here and do uh
one of these little cut-off branches
here so f3
circle select e to extrude s to scale
e to extrude s to scale i to inset e to
extrude in
and let's do eight select everything
reset the uvs here
a scale 0 on the uv side g to move it
to there a brown tree and now we can
select
in there and make it brighter that's it
let's actually disable specular lighting
for this one there
okay and let's do some interesting
shapes here as well so i'll shift select
these
e to extrude that on scale it and bring
it down just to get some more
uh like definition to the tree here
i actually saw something similar in
fortnite that's where i got the
inspiration so
but they have uh branches aren't just
like normal solids so
and we might as well do some roots here
so it's
traditional e to extrude as the scale e
to extrude as the scale
let's do here as well e to extrude as
the scale
i could actually do uh control right
click here as well so control right
click
scale control right click but the merge
wouldn't sound very good if it said
control
right click so i'm going to do e to
extrude as the scale g to move e to
extrude as the scale g to move
okay that's it now we're going to make
the canopy stuff here so shift
right click here 1.636 shift a
let's add a mesh and we want to do an
ico sphere
let's bump that up to 3 tab and
let's we have to change the shading here
and pick the same material for that one
uv editing a select everything scale
zero
make that a little bit green like that
and then let's do side view and pick the
bottom vertex there
proportional should be on g zed scroll
it down let's make it
into something like that i'll scale it
up
a lot side maybe side view
and here and let's go to the top one
pick that one control plus a whole bunch
to there
three to get to edge alt e extrude long
normals
control minus alt e extra normals let's
get
like a layered uh canopy here so alt e
extra long normals alt e extrude longer
and one more time all the
extrude one levels 553
so now maybe we'll do select some random
here so select random
let's go down to 15 percent
and then do uh alt s to scale that into
some wonky shape here
and we can actually even put some random
stuff on here
uh control plus no control minus
scale okay that should be good
and let's twist as well with some
proportional here so let's go back to
smooth
rotates is that actually before that i'm
going to do this
i'm going to select all the vertices and
then reselect the bottom one so that's
active
and then switch here to vertex snapping
and we want
active snap width active now i should be
able to do shift
d and then hold the ctrl key to snap it
to the tip
of these branches here
that's it and now let's do some rotating
proportional rotation here
rotate rotate like that
and some different sizes maybe so 4 27
scale and let's get some stuff hanging
down as well maybe so i'll shift select
a few
vertices here and we've got proportional
on
just g to move these down maybe to there
okay let's make a little uh base for
this to stand on as well maybe
so i'll do duplicate
maybe that shift d scale
scale more to there
and p to set up create that into a
different mesh
no okay well let's extrude it first and
l and now p into a new mesh
let's make it green so l select
everything change it to a brighter green
341 we've got on the clock there
so maybe we'll do uh just
move this down a bit g to move that one
to there
actually let's sculpt this so let's go
into sculpting
dino topo okay f to scale this one up
and then thanks for that tip by the way
and then
uh let's see we do control left click
oh we have to switch off symmetry
so just control and left click here to
lower this down a little bit
got some stuff breaking there
maybe up a bit down a bit
okay uh 249. so let's tab out of that
one go back into uv editing
l to select everything a on the uvs
scale 0
bring it back to the green color
okay for some reason i was still in
sculpting there okay
now we can go to the bottom view ctrl 7
c to circle select
let's just uh do a whole bunch of these
here
okay before i do that let's decimate it
actually we need to
bring the low poly back into low polygon
maybe like that
apply that one i've got 2 minutes 12.
so let's do a nude double click a to
deselect
maybe circle select that
and now we should do we've got
proportional so let's just g
and then control minus and g to move
that on down
control minus g control minus
g control minus g
control plus a few times
here maybe let's select some of this
i want to make some dark look here
underneath
just to make the thumbnail pop a little
bit more for the video this is not the
tree no
i guess the roots are there but let's go
there
too dark maybe there
too dark there
very dark okay maybe i've got too much
shadow so
that's it and we can decimate this one
we've got one minute to go so let's add
a decimate modifier here
bring this one down as well to get a
little bit more low poly again
maybe there apply that one
did i even
okay and let's add a little stone here
for good measure we've got 48 seconds to
go so
there shift d to duplicate it
e to extrude s to scale
um got proportional there so g e to
extrude that's the scale
and then period and let's do or actually
comma
normal scale z flatten that one
to zero control plus a few times we've
got 22 seconds
so now we've got a stone here and
lasting about 16 seconds
12 uv
project from u scale
scale and we got the gradient going
just in time i should change this here
tonight
and i miss
okay we've got ours i lied a little bit
because i said i was gonna make a tree
only and i thought i'd uh enable i'll
add some uh some visuals so i added a
rock and a little
sorry about that floating island i guess
it is floating island
and uh it's a slight gradient now to the
canopy i don't know if you can actually
see that because i've got the
the whole thing maybe if we disable uh
cavity
um it's uh brighter at the top here and
then it goes a little bit darker at the
bottom so maybe that's uh
useful but let's uh re-enable cavity
here
[Music]
there we have it we've got ourselves a
low poly tree we're back into low poly
world literally and we're back even into
a floating island i'm back into my
element now happy with that didn't get a
waterfall but that's okay it was mainly
the tree that i was gonna make anyway a
low poly tree
uh so the tip for this week is gonna be
um
it's that method actually of the using
the skinning
so i guess it's a bit stupid to repeat
it so let's repeat it
um what i did was um if i go over here
shift right click to move the cursor
tab shift a let's add the it's not the
default cube but it's a very similar
it's a clone of it
so that's gonna have to do so the thing
here the
fastest way i know is to get into a
single vertex
and we have it theoretically we haven't
actually started from anything
else but the default cube that's very
important as you all know
so it's still the default cube that we
used but i i selected all the vertices
on that one
and then the new hotkey in 2.83 is not
alt m the new key is m just if you want
to merge
and then at center i did just to get
that little vertex there
and then you could do e to extrude e to
extrude e to extrude e to extrude e to
extrude
and that would be the right way to do it
but i cheated a little bit so i
controlled
right clicked to get it
i think and the other key is see that
it's really created everything on
on like a flat uh flat plane there so i
recommend that
you rotate the viewport a little bit
when you click
and that will make it go a little bit in
different shapes and to branch it all
you need to do is select
a vertex down where you were ctrl right
click
to branch it again another one ctrl
right click to branch that one
ctrl right click and then when you had
the shape that you wanted here and then
we added the modifier and it's the skin
modifier
and we have to disable symmetry because
we don't want symmetry
even though i love symmetry my mind
loves symmetry
in fact i love drawing when i work in my
day job as a
security architect i love drawing
redundant solutions because then i can
have
two trees that look nearly identical
well they look identical i make sure
they do
so redundancy is good for many reasons
most important
for my ocd needs that's why import that
synchronous what was i even talking
about
okay when i had the skinning there here
i applied it and then in order to i
didn't
i lied i didn't apply it tab into edit
mode and then i selected the
bottom vertex here because it's still
just uh skinning basic
basically makes it thick the the edges
that we had
so and you can't press s to scale you
can't scale a vertex
but ctrl a you can do and that's
basically the same thing
and then do that with proportional
editing you could click o to toggle that
on
and then with the ctrl a you could do
the base here and make it a lot thicker
and then i selected the tip here and
then i did shift
g thanks to those of you who suggested
to uh
to use shift g shortcut instead of
pressing f3 and then i did the amount of
connecting edges because
amount of connecting edges to this
vertex here is one
and the the vertices that are in here
have two connecting edges so that's uh
one of the faster ways to select
uh all the end points but then i had to
deselect this one so i shift
clicked on that one and then did control
a to rescale
these branches and you can have
proportional here to make it in
different
thicknesses okay and then i pressed ctrl
one oh no first i applied it and then
pressed ctrl 1 to subdivide it
okay and if you don't want this round
thing here at the bottom by the way
so when i press ctrl 1 to subdivide see
that it becomes like a droplet
here if you don't want that to happen
you can do
what i did here as well ctrl r for loop
cut and then make
that edge right at the base there
because then suddenly it's two edges
here for it to subdivide with and that
makes it sharper so when i press ctrl 1
now
you can see that it keeps a sharp edge
down here okay and then i
applied that one that's one way you
could do to create the interesting trees
uh one more tip
actually i'm gonna throw you some extra
bonuses here i selected these four faces
or not them i selected them one over
there and then if you go into
preferences here
there's actually an add-on called loop
tools
and that comes with unity by unity when
i plan
on my own it comes with blender by
default but you have to enable it
so you just click this little box there
because when you
press f3 now or there's a menu for it
somewhere i think as well
but if you press f3 and type circle and
that's one of the tools that it's got
and that basically turns those faces
that i had which were more or less
square into a circle
how to turn a square into a circle e to
extrude s
okay proportional so o to disable that
and s to scale
and for the canopy i guess uh it's a bit
similar to what i've done before a lot
of proportional editing stuff so nothing
magic there
did some basic sculpting for this one we
did that in the octopus one
so do you know what i'm going to cut
this video a little bit shorter because
i keep talking for too long and i make
my 10 minute videos
30 minutes and that's no good and then
i'm going to extend the video anyway
because
do you know what let's try to put this
tree i'm working on something so
scrap what i just said and let's do
something here so let's select that one
that one the floating island can stay
here
but let's go export and export it as an
fbx file
selected objects apply transform and
apply scaling
unit scale here and now i'm going to go
into a secret project i'm
filming another video i keep filming a
lot of videos that i haven't released so
i have to release it for you because i'm
just doing a week
weekly video now and if i want to reach
200k or 100k
i don't think i can do weekly videos i
have to do at least two a week
so but let's go into poly plays one hdrp
because i'm learning the high render
high definition
i'm learning the high definition render
pipeline in unity 2019.3 so let's go
into assets let's save
this tree here the 10-minute tree and
now my friends i'm going to bridge this
world
of blender into unity so let's minimize
that
so i've had some requests to do
something that i spent more than 10
minutes on
so i've spent about uh maybe uh an hour
and a half two hours
on creating a more detailed island here
um in unity
so um and i feel i'm filming that one as
well i'm just a little bit more casual
about it i'm like modeling
chatting away digressing on some useless
information that probably no one will
want to listen to
but then every now and then i managed to
throw in some sort of a comment that
might be useful for someone so maybe
people can take it away i found actually
when i modeled this i found a new trick
in blender that i'm going to share in
this video so come back for that one
subscribe if you haven't already if you
want to see that one this is uh like a
skull
island maybe i'll do uh well you know uh
with a pirate theme i guess you've seen
i've seen it all
so i've got the pirate ship i've got uh
the pirate i've got the kraken and
everything so maybe
this will might turn into something like
a pirate island
then i worked a little bit on this
shader as well i got a little bit
inspired from
there's a game called the bad north with
a guy oscar
something on twitter you should look it
up he's got some really cool stuff and i
got a little bit
inspired by that look uh to get a shader
just to do some ripples
i think his is better i'm just basically
throwing something together in
what's called shader graph with a high
definition render pipeline here
but i've got some transparency in the
water and i've got some ripples here
around there
and i've got some lighting effects going
on and if you press play actually it
looks
even a little bit better than it does
here in the editor
so i can move around this little world
here i'm not going to show you too much
in this one because
but let's bring the tree in that's what
i wanted to try so i imported it or i
threw it into this folder so it should
show up here i've got a lot of junk
um that i've been testing here so 10
minute tree here we go and it's going to
probably be
massive because i did it really massive
so let's scale it down r to scale have
you heard
something so ridiculous in unity or to
scale imagine one day
they'll unite the use of the hotkeys
that would be
strange but good so let's put our tree
that we just created in this world
our 10 minute tree still too big maybe
that's no good place for it
maybe we'll move it here instead let's
press play
got some rocks underwater here
here's our new tree that we just created
wow let's go under it
oh we've got some volumetrics here or
it's
oh yeah let's boost the volumetric i'm
basically just learning htrp now
it's been in preview for about i think
600 years
and that's a record that's the fastest
they've ever brought something out of
preview
let's go i i'm so lost here but there is
something here maybe it's a directional
light
no volumetrics multiplier here we go
five
let's boost the volumetrics thought i
saw some rays here from the tree
yeah some volumetrics here it's not so
prominent but
maybe i have to have dancer fog
when you've got stuff to play with like
yeah you you throw all the effects on
there and it just becomes like a big
soup of uh
way too overdone maybe it's better to
take a step back sometime and just
reduce the stuff
this is too much fog i guess uh but
maybe on a misty day maybe i should make
a little adventure game i'm gonna have
some waterfalls and stuff over here as
well and i'm gonna
bring a lot more detail here and put
some maybe some houses on here and
uh maybe a lighthouse and a windmill but
again
i'll record this into a longer video and
if you want to tag along and watch that
one
you're very welcome to do so should we
bring the whole thing in as well
should we should we just see what that
would look like
okay guys there we have it that's our 10
minutes tree with a little bonus
floating island
on top of a non-floating island all
right folks that's going to be it for
this week i hope you enjoyed this one
and come back next thursday if you want
to see another 10 minute modeling
challenge video it's going to be episode
26 then so
consider subscribing if you haven't
already and uh
also consider liking it if you liked it
i've got a patreon as well check out the
description
until next week have a great one and
i'll see you then bye for now
[Music]
you