hello guys and welcome to episode 76 of
the 10 minute modeling challenge
so last week we did a godzilla monster
animation literally where we smashed up
some pounds and we spent a lot of time
keyframing that in the bonus material
and this week i'm going to do something
a little bit different
we're going to do some low-poly turrets
and i've prepared a few things you'll
see that there's a little bit different
today
because instead of using my normal uh
colorizing texture i went to a
royalty-free image site i just googled
royalty-free images and i found
pixabay.com so i decided to go there and
search for supercars because
supercars tend to have some interesting
colors and shapes to them
and i downloaded a few random images
from there and then i cropped them out
game engines like to have square
textures that are the power of two
in size so i got uh some textures that i
cropped down to 5 12 by 5
12 pixels and i've imported one of those
and i'm actually going to use the base
color now
or just like a random sample in the
image for the modeling part but then
we'll randomize the textures
if you're making a game that you're
going to play on a mobile phone
or if the items are going to be quite
small the turrets in this case
then you get away with this randomized
look but if you want to have a close-up
you should really draw your textures and
have them fitted and
uv mapped of course but i won't have
time to do that in the 10-minute
video so i thought this could be an
interesting twist to it i've also
prepared a little unity project
where i've got some turrets auto firing
on targets that are closest to them and
i'll hopefully make a tutorial out of
that one too
but if you're a patreon of mine you can
actually go to patreon.com
and the game dev tier or the tutorial
tearing up in fact
we'll be able to download this unity
project that i've prepared so you can
have a play around with it maybe use it
as a base for
your own game so let's set the timer i
was cut this part out but maybe i'll put
it in one day
all right let's get going ready steady
go
let's model some low poly turrets tab
into edit mode hold the ctrl key
snap this one up there this is going to
be the base just so scale to scale that
one down
e to extrude s to scale heat extrude
just to scale that one down as well
that's going to be the base shift d
duplicate that one here's the
turret part so e to extrude that on
keep it super low poly of course e to
extrude that's the scale
um and ctrl r maybe we'll do slightly
different
thickness there shift d duplicate that
one
scale y scale z zero so we flatten that
e to extrude that one and actually i'm
going to
scale x to zero and make that square
again oh we have to do uh of course
auto mirror so that's the add-on yeah
it's included
just enable it and here
let's do some arms shift b duplicate e
to extrude
and he'll put the torrents now shift d
scale
e to extruder on e to extrude s to scale
z only the z axis and then here we'll do
the actual
barrel part so shift d duplicate test
scale e to extrude
shift d i'm going to make this a
separate object so we can animate these
height inset and then just do a little
hole here
that's it and should we put some more
interesting features here probably e to
extrude oh
that's wrong need to extrude move that
one down
just break it up a little bit more
need to extrude that's the scale bring
it in
here as well should we do maybe i'll do
uh
shift d duplicate i'm just doing some
random stuff of course normal
infensio style alt e texture long face
normals
control r bring that up
and maybe shift the duplicates eat
extrude
and let's put some interesting legs on
it two minutes gone
so scale why
just going to bring those in eat extrude
but we'll
bring it to there and then
we'll do maybe ctrl r heat extrude
should we do like clampy feet to eat
extrude
that should be good
and bring that in should we move it in a
little bit further
that's it ctrl r
scale i don't like the that vertex is
over there so let's move that on in
that's it and
l to select this one shift the scale
y minus one that flips it but we need to
do alt n
and recalculate outside to flip the
normals there that's why it's good to
have backface calling on
and one more feature here maybe on the
side shift b
scale e to extrude
that's it and each extrude that's the
scale
that's it that's going to be our first
turret maybe we'll do one more
or two more possibly
maybe we could texture map it in the 10
minutes as well so that's turret number
one
let's do shift d to duplicate it
actually i'll probably texture the base
should i
so we get the same look nah shift d to
duplicate the
shift space g hold the ctrl key to snap
it into here
and then we'll do this one a little bit
different so i'll select l just select
all the linked
ones because i'm still in the same
object delete all of those
let's make a different type of tart here
so we can change the base a little bit
too
maybe a little bit longer there and this
one can come
in all of it
ctrl r move that up
bring this in
gg slides it along an edge so that's
pretty handy
like good game and then the bass can
look pretty much the same shifty
duplicate
and we should have a different look on
this one each extrude
and ctrl r loop cut scale
ctrl r make it look different i say and
then i do it looking the same
yeah okay maybe i'll do all the texture
along the place normals there
and should we have it coming up from the
back here maybe
so we'll do uh here shifty
scale bring it in e to extrude
heat to extrude control r i have no idea
what i'm doing now e to extrude
with some randomness always good
unless you're making a game apparently
you shouldn't use random elements in the
game i annoys people
e to extrude should we do them hanging
down maybe from this one
so i'll do like an arm here shift the
scale
and e to extrude maybe we'll do each
extrude there as well that was a bit
unnecessary but it's okay
and e to extrude that on here we'll do
them hanging down e to extrude
s to scale maybe on the x axis
and shift the scale e to extrude
normal style and actually got allergies
now so
i've got something to blame for a change
shift the scale
for my little heartling it's extrude
and should we do just a different design
on this one all together
ctrl r again alt select around there
scale zed
maybe like this i need to extrude s to
scale and we'll do the
item set and e to extrude in
and some slightly different features
maybe two just the box here looks a bit
plain doesn't it
so we'll do uh shift d to duplicate
alt e to extrude long face normals
l to select the link scale x
and bring these in control r
ctrl r let's look at a few of these
all the extra long phase normals
and that should be all right i think
able to shift the i've got three minutes
so we should try to just do the random
texturizing here clipping off
clipping on again we'll just do two
turrets i think
two different looks on them and we can
put some different design here on this
barrel e to extrude
some fancy shifty
extrude i don't know if it's that fancy
to be honest shifty duplicate
each extrude and should
put one more thing here shift the
scale all the extra long phase normals
that's it
and e to extrude that one okay so we've
got two turrets here now different sizes
we've got an itchy nose too take care
took care of that pretty fast
two minutes thirty okay let's texture
map these so i'm just gonna go to
tab into edit mode select all of them
and then we're going to uh not shading
uv editing that's where i was actually
uv and then just smart uv project okay
and that'll just throw the texture
randomly onto this one
and then you can play around with the
panning of it so if i scale it
it'll just change it and usually i
prefer to go
smaller actually like this because
you're going to watch look at them from
a distance like this
probably but you can play around with it
you can also move it outside it doesn't
matter because it seamlessly wraps
around the corners there so you can even
find any place here and you can also
rotate it if you want to rotate for a
different look
so if you find like an interesting part
here maybe where it contrasts between
white and black and then rotate it
and you can find a decent looking like
turret like this
and if we wanted to have the barrels
maybe in one color
there's we can select l for or we'll
just do l here for the length
scale zero works on this one but
remember in unreal engine it's a bit
picky
so you might have to do a little bit
different there you can't go infinitely
smaller i think
but let's put it like that so we have a
solid color on there
and maybe here as well we'll do so solid
colors on these
you can keep the random look but usually
maybe for the barrels you want to keep
it slightly different
for this one as well we'll do tab 8
select everything
uv smart uv project okay
and then scale rotate just fine
usually symmetry makes it looks pretty
cool like this in different
angles and stuff we'll do l to select
the length here
and go scale zero on the left so we get
a solid colored barrel here it looks
probably a little bit better when we
animate
and if you wanted to change you could
just change the base here as well maybe
these are too big maybe we wanted them a
little bit more
solid colored i can make them smaller
rotate just random random stuff
so that's it we've got uh maybe we can
test
we've got 27 seconds to spare we can
actually try to
change the texture here as well so
let's just open and do the
blue one instead editing
okay that looked hideous so it's a
little bit dependent on which textures
they use apparently so
go tab inside mode 8 to select
everything and then you can move that to
a different color change it move it and
that's it
that's it 10 minutes is up and we've got
some random looking
uh stuff i'll go back just control that
a few times
so we get that other texture back i
think
i think it looks a little bit better
with the gray there but we can test it
around in the unity as well i'll show
you
a few tips there so what we'll do is
export these into uh two
like turrets that we'll import into
unity in the bonus material note so this
is not going to be a tutorial because
i'm going to run through it pretty fast
but i've got everything prepared so uh
put in the comments i always ask that if
you want a tutorial and people say yes
and then i don't have time to make them
or i find something else to do stupid i
know but
i'll try anyway so let's export these
i'm gonna export them as
three different objects so if i do l
here on the base
i will select the base stuff there press
p and separate the selection
and i'm gonna press f2 rename this one
turret
one base let's call it imagination there
and then here the barrels i'm gonna do
separate as well because we wanna
animate the barrels here so when they
fire
they're gonna shoot back a little bit
like a recoil effect like this
looks pretty cool so i'm gonna do this
one and then do
p to separate by selection and then
we'll do f2 and rename this one
turret one
is barrel how you spell barrel i think
so and then we'll do the top here that's
already separated so
f2 and we'll call this one top
and it's important that the center of
rotation for this now
is where you want it to be and we're
going to parent the the barrels here to
this
top here so don't worry about that the
barrels will rotate with the object
you might just petrify that i wasn't
recording again
so that's the first one and we can hide
this one for now
i'm missing something here okay then i
rename this
barrel there we go so let's hide those
i'll select this one and do alt g that
moves it back to orego or
the default center location here
so and then we'll do the same here we'll
do
f tab inside mode l to select the base
stuff here and then
p separate selection that's it
and then i'll do all of them first
actually we'll do the barrels here these
are the ones that are going to recoil
so p separate by selection and then
we'll do
f2 turret to barrel
and then we'll rename this one f2 turret
to
top and here f2 turret
to base so these are all prepped now
let's grab them all put them in the same
scene like this
select them all of them all of them
selected you can right click here as
well
and do select objects or you can just
drag and drop and then we'll go file
export
fpx and then here we'll do selected
objects
apply scalings we'll do unit scale fbx
unit scale and then apply time
transform it's a little shortcut to get
the rotation correct but it doesn't work
for armatures remember
and we'll rename this one to turrets
um 10 mmc 76 turrets
export all right so let's jump into the
unity project that i've prepared now and
i won't be able to go through it but
what i do have is i've created a base
turret
game object hierarchy with a base a
a barrel and some muzzle location so i
know where the bullets are going to be
fired from
and some audio when it rotates and then
i've created some prefabs as well
a bullet an explosion and a target just
a test target and some impact effects
and turret so what we'll do is
i'm going to go into this one and we'll
just drag and drop this
fbx file that i've created into this
folder
meshes so we've got these meshes here
you recognize them here
and we also have to grab those textures
that we got so i'm going to drag and
drop those into
let's just do here create folder
textures and we'll drag and drop those
ones that i created before i'll
grab the square ones so it's the same
ones so we'll drag this one in
which we haven't tested the orange one
here which we haven't tested either
and we've got the white one and the
other square one here which one
oh yeah the blue one there we go
and i have to set these meshes now as
well
so we've got turret what turret one base
and we've got turret one
top here which is called turret here
and we've got the barrels
turret one barrel and you have to grab
the mesh object down here
so it knows that's it
so if i grab that one we'll drag this
texture that we imported
we'll use the same one turret and we'll
grab
this gray texture and drag it into the
base map here
and you should recognize it there
let's move this one into the center so
and then i should move it up a little
bit probably
that's it so i've got the turret here
and like i said i won't have time to go
through how i've created everything
but just a short run through is on the
base here on the turret i've got like a
turret script where i can set
targeting speed a search radius how long
it should be searching for targets
and how many rounds per minute it should
be firing and then i've set which prefab
it should be
that it fires and that's just a bullet
with a trail on it
and then i've got muzzles here and these
we need to configure so
where you got select the muzzle l here
and then i usually click here on
perspective and go into iso
isometric click on the z axis because
then it's going to be easier to
position this one in the center of the
barrel there
then we have to do the same for the top
so i press on this y axis
and then we move this one down to there
and then to save time you could uh
i could just delete this right one okay
i can't because it's a prefab okay let's
do it this way now
i'll go to the muzzle l here
copy position and then right click here
oh no i don't right click
paste position and then we just flip the
x value for this one
and now that those two muzzles are in
the right place here for
so he knows where to fire the bullet
from so these are little helper
transforms and we can try this out now
so if i press play we should always have
ourselves a little targeting turret here
that we just designed and it aims and
fires at
just a target that spawns at the mouse
cursor
and if you click i just made it so and
it keeps targeting the closest one there
and i'll put some random sound effects
on there from my blasters sound effects
library and in fact if you go to
infantia.com and look up
blaster's sound effects library if you
use the code
10mmc ep76
then you'll get 50 discount and you can
download thousands of blaster sound
effects pretty cool
self-promoting my own assets here it's
not so often that i mentioned them
actually
okay we're seeing that it's missing the
target and it's because the target's a
little bit too small
so maybe i'll just increase the size of
those targets
test target we'll do scale maybe
1.5 instead should that work
let's try it
there we go
okay and it looks a little bit different
is because i don't have the same
texture settings that i did so if we go
into this object or the material
then this is probably the way it looked
one one
and zero zero here and this is a little
bit more similar to what it looked like
when it was in a blender
but you can play around with this as
well so on this texture now you can just
slide
on the tiling for example and that'll
change the way it looks a little bit
could get some pretty cool looking
styles on it let's
see we can see both here i remember now
you wouldn't want to have it like this
of course
you can't go this close to this turret
that looks uh not so good
so but from a distance like this in a
game if you're making that mobile game
or something then it works
but like i said we'll just slide this so
we can change the offset as well that
pans the texture
so you can find some interesting looking
shapes down there
this audio thing is annoying that a lot
out of me
so let's uh hide this one gizmos will
hide on
so
turrets and again slide tiling
play around with that one get an
interesting look
and you can slide around the offset to
pan it
and if you want it to be more solid
colors you go down with the tiling down
to something really small in both values
here
then you get more solid colors because
it's basically like zooming into the
texture
so now it looks like it's got some vents
that's probably let's
press play on this one and see that
looks a bit crisper i guess
but still some different looks to it
and if it's taking too long to shoot
these we could actually duplicate this
one
so let's just make a copy of this one
and put it
two to the side there we've got two
turrets maybe this one should be a
little bit different
we'll do one that rotates faster
so turret here maybe the tracking speed
is five
but it wrote it only fires like 60 shots
per minute
and then we'll do another one here as
well that we put next to it on the other
side
and then we'll change the parameters on
this one we'll do rounds per minute it's
going to be like 600
but targeting speed is super slow one
let's try this
okay some targets so
some different things to play around
with there
okay and now that we've got multiple
sometimes when you have more objects
than one as well not only the symmetry
make it look
pretty cool but when you have multiple
objects they look
nice together as well so we can change
the look of those
with the sliding just the offset here
panning and the tiling again
to whichever way you want we should try
the different colors here as well
so not entirely sure that this will look
so good so
but we'll try the blue one that we had
before there we go
blue texture and then we'll go this
changes for all of them so let's
see let's see what we've got here
on these then you get get that little
like a team color look maybe if you add
that one
change the panning again
there maybe looks like it's got some uh
head there that's looking
there we go let's try the other one as
well we've got
the orange one what's that look like so
it doesn't look so orange it's because
we've panned it somewhere
change the tiling one on
and then here change
there it looks like an industrial robot
type thing now so
it will actually won't maximize it on
play so we can see both here
the scene view and the top view
and it tracks the active part here as
well if it's closest
let's import the other one as well we'll
make a copy out of this one
maybe we'll put these up here to the
side
this can be like one team and then we'll
do
copy this one move that one down there
spin it around around the y axis 180
and then here i'll just swap these now
for the other
so we'll go base mesh here
we'll do turret two base
and then for the turret here we'll do
turret two top
and barrel turret two barrel
and this one we need to change those uh
muzzles as well since the
the they're placed a little bit
different so we'll go
barrel here no no no no no no they're
it's a little bit similar but not in the
same place so remember click on
perspective
and this is not a tutorial but i say
anyway like that
so move it into the center and then go
from the front view
okay that was the back here there's the
front here
oh yeah i'm looking from the other side
of course
okay let's go from the side then there
we go
and then we'll do copy position
paste onto the right one these are just
the placeholders
and then flip the y or the x component
there so
then now we should have it in that place
and
we could create uh maybe a separate
texture for this one so we can control
them so they look
different i don't know why i have two
pictures there
start two and here we can put
let's try the white texture that we had
white
and then for turret two here we'll
select these three base turret and
barrel
and replace that with part two texture
then we've got independent control out
of this one maybe we'll do
duplicates here as well so ctrl d to
duplicate that
and these won't fire on each other now
because i haven't uh configured
the other ones as targets so but that
could be a simple fix if we wanted to
put that one should they they should be
a little further apart maybe minus
four and four
and these have different rotation speeds
now maybe we'll give them some different
properties too
so turret here let's do
super fast tracking or no not super fast
but eight
and then rounds per minute how many
120 that's pretty good oh that's going
to be a dangerous turret
this one
we'll do two can remain there let's do
320.
okay never mind let's just give it less
sorry two we can change around here with
the tiling as well and look what do we
like
on these and the offsets
offset this panning and tiling makes it
more or less
solid colors and details you can go
negative as well so it starts to go more
detail again
but maybe like this would be
so we should separate these turrets a
little bit too
three minus three there we go
so now we've got two turret types here
and they're firing together
i've also made it so that it plays the
animation based on the speed of the
rounds per minute it calculates how fast
it should play the animation
and uh again if you're uh so if you want
to download this unity project
uh you can become a patreon at
patreon.com infensia
and i've already uploaded this unity
project so you can have a play with it
and see
maybe you'll learn from it or maybe you
want to copy some logic and build on it
and make a tower defense game why not
we can also change the sound effects
let's put these on
so for like a turret here maybe we'll
disable a few of these
so we can test some different turret
sounds so i'll just
shift select these
and here i've just done so in the turret
script
i've got a few audio clips here that i
can randomize
and in the blaster sound effects library
whoa whoa whoa
or x round robin it means that every
sound effect has got four variations to
it because when you repeat
firing sounds rapidly you don't want it
to sound like a typewriter
so if you knew some slight variation to
it and randomized between those
different samples it
sounds a little bit better so let's go
into the medium folder here
and go loud and then i'll just drag some
more sound effects in here
so i'll include these as well you can
use them if you download this
from patreon you can use the sound
effects if you want or you could buy
that
sound effects pack from infantia.com
so there we go let's bring some sounds
in let's just pick a random one here
i should pause that because i don't need
it to fire so we'll pick yeah i have no
idea maybe they'll try this one
any random sound there quick way to do
there is just to go zero
on the array click the little padlock
icon and we can
select these and drag them into fire
clips there
and let's see what this sounds like
okay let's try another sound
47 maybe
zero let's grab these in if you can see
them there we go
[Music]
okay should we do a totally different
sound here maybe
do a longer sound and some slower firing
maybe
so we'll go into the long and very loud
long and
just loud one this one low mid
frequencies
very loud there we go
zero on there really a railing
oh i missed one but never mind
that's pretty cool
and we could give it some more damage as
well
oh i didn't expose the damage the health
of these
and then if it works in unison but the
other one with a different sound here
oh yeah the padlock iphone
oh he's inside one
so
all right folks that's gonna be it for
this week i hope you enjoyed this
episode
give it a thumbs up if you did and don't
forget to subscribe and
just one more mention as well if you
want to download this project head over
to patreon.com
become a supporter there from the
tutorial tiering up and you'll be able
to download this project play around
with it use the scripts use the little
hierarchy of
turret logic there and make a little
game out of it why not
so uh until next week have a great one
and i'll see you then
bye for now
[Music]
you