hello guys and welcome to episode 70 of
the 10 minute modeling challenge can you
believe it
i cannot 70 episodes 70 thursdays have
gone past since we started this whole
journey while i've been doing these
thursday videos
i've in my day job that's making a game
as well so i'm making a real-time
strategy games with a colleague of mine
it's me and christian we're making a
fully-fledged multiplayer rts game with
lots of ai
and lots of netcode a lot of procedural
generation
and in this game i'm actually been
making
some 3d objects of course well a lot of
my part there is actually programming
believe it or not so i spend maybe 80
percent of my time
developing programming and maybe 20 is
all the rest which is uh like graphics
3d stuff
and the game objects and doing uh sound
effects and things like that and music
of course
but in this game uh we're making some uh
like rts
styled buildings or structures and some
of them are just static buildings like a
city
or a little town for example but we also
have some producing buildings and that
could be like factories or barracks or
airports and i thought
i'd give you a little a quick show how
you can make a rts styled
building in about 10 minutes so that's
going to be the usual time limit of
course
and i'm going to do it just a little bit
modular so you can animate the
construction of an object like that and
i want to keep it simple because usually
in rts games especially
especially if you were to play on a
mobile we're not making a mobile game
but then the buildings are going to be
quite small and also in our game they're
quite small regardless because you can't
really zoom in too close
so you get away with the low poly
objects they'll render fast and they'll
look pretty good
from a distance let's do a low poly
factory building or an rts
style game here we go i'm using the old
palette today i'm not using the gradient
and sometimes it's actually better to
use this static with fewer colors
because
then you get a consistent look to all
your objects so you don't have
loads of different shades and everything
and sometimes you can go even fewer a
lot fewer colors in fact you can go down
to 16 colors and get that retro style
and it's quite cool when all the objects
are really fitting the same palette
so i'm gonna go for the old school here
the eight by eight so it's still 64
colors
but let's do that one and uh let's get
started
so screencast keys we need to enable and
we're gonna be off now hold on to your
hats
why is there no skipping oh yeah there
we go ready steady
go and we are off timer's off usually i
keep the base of the building
underground like this um it's
uh quite good when you have uneven
terrain to put it on
and then what i'm going to do is keep
just a base plate here i'll do shift d
to duplicate it i do a lot of this and i
recommend that you don't build
everything into the same structure in
fact so we'll make like a little side
building here for the factory
select this one e to extrude this one of
course and then
shift d to duplicate this one and then
maybe i'll let's
scale it down scale it on the x-axis so
press
x to force it scale it up again we'll
put a little side thing here angle
e to extrude that one so we've got two
basic portions of this building
here we can make it like an entry so
i'll ctrl r twice to do some loop cuts
ctrl r here as well
and ctrl r and here i'll just extrude
this one in
and here on the factory should we do
maybe like we'll do
shift d to duplicate it s to scale it s
to scale
press y to scale on the y axis e to
extrude this one up
i to inset and e to extrude it down i
usually like to make
roofs like this shift d to duplicate
that one
scale it down scale x instead of just uh
working from the same object i quite
often now separate the geometry i'm
still in the same object but i separate
the geometry like this
so we'll keep this one here maybe we'll
put ctrl r loop cut here
select this one on edge select a little
maybe
anything like that let's put some things
here as well shift d
first scale it up scale on the y-axis
and we'll do similar type of the roof
here e to extrude
eye to inset heat texture down you can
start to colorize this
l to select all these linked go for a
darker gray maybe even black for the
root here
or a darker green like this and let's
put some features on it as well like
chimneys
usually on like a like a
factory so shifty duplicate s scale on
the x-axis
scale x-axis again and here i'll just
move it into the building
and e to extrude it out to here then
i'll e to extrude this one out
move this one in to get like a little
bevel here
and let's move this one and here i'll
make that chimney and this one i'm going
to put in our game we've put like little
uh
color accents depending if you're like
depending if you're blue or red players
so let's just do the same here
create this one blue and then i'll do
shift d to duplicate this one
i'm going to put a chimney i'll offset
this one a little bit e to extrude it up
e to extrude s to scale e to extrude and
s to scale it down that's the chimney
gemini and we'll make that one gray
a little bit lighter maybe and here i
turn set
and e to extrude down control plus to
grow the selection from down there and
make that dark this is usually i do
cavities
inside there so maybe this could be as
simple as this because we're going to
look at it from a distance
so i'll copy this whole thing now shift
d to duplicate that chimney put another
one here
and let's just put the same type of
accent here on this side as well shift d
as if this was like a side building or
something
so scale z and e to extrude this one out
maybe we'll go in a little bit over the
building itself here and ctrl r to loop
cut it
and move this one in and l to select it
and here's the nice thing now with the
pallets because i can go for the same
blue and in fact i'm gonna go for the
same blue
so i don't lie let's put two accents
here
i don't know why i call them accents
well
like little trims on the side of the
building there we go and
here inside we'll do it dark so alt
shift select there shift like that one
and
again simulate that it's a hole there
and here shift the let's put some
accessories here as well we've got six
minutes on the clock there scale
said i'll just e to extrude this one
and let's pretend there's like some i
don't know maybe it's like some
i don't think they have air conditioning
here but shifty duplicate
this could be like some sort of a pipe
that goes up help
selecting there and
should we do like a ramp here need to
extrude that on
i need to extrude that one down and
maybe the base plate here could be a bit
darker as well
and here we could do maybe i'll do ctrl
r loop cut ctrl r loop cut we can add a
little bit more geometry now
and here here is one thing i want to
make these smaller so
scale y just compress them into there
ctrl r and here we'll do like
could be like windows or something so i
to inset
all d to extrude long phase normals
inwards
and it creates a little bit of a strange
thing here we can actually fix that one
switch this one to vertex hold the
control
key as you move this line and snap it to
that vertex and then do the same thing
here move it and snap to that vertex
maybe there's a better way to do this
but you can snap it to the axis of the
different vertices there
shifts like these and control plus let's
just make this slightly darker
there ctrl minus and then do black there
maybe
so that could be and then here i want to
have some feature as well ctrl
r to cut alt shift select that one for
edge select
all the extrude long face normals and i
also want to do something with this
corner here so 4
26 on the clock let's do some corner
stuff here
pick this one shift d duplicate e to
extrude
l to select the linked
and bring it down to there and these are
just going to be like
corner trims so we l to select linked
and we'll make them
darker as well and
l to select the linked let's manually
put this roughly on all corners here
shift d these will have to be taller i
suppose
so let's move that on into there and up
to there
and l to select those links shift the
duplicator shift d to duplicate that and
this one
obviously we can't put it all the way
over there but we'll stick one here on
this corner
go in a bit under the roof
and out a bit
to there and then shift the maybe we'll
just put one at the bottom or maybe we
can even leave it like that that
pretty cool i guess a little corner beam
there
we could keep it like that uh maybe
we'll do something with the roof a lot
of maybes here so maybe shift d
to duplicate it s to scale it up bro
bring it down all the extrude long face
normals this is an old school
roof on a modern building
dark and could do
or really do anything fancy here i think
but here we'll put
like solar panel style things so
e to extrude that one bring this one
down
ctrl r let's loop cut it maybe just m
times
i to insert item set again to get the
individual and then just do them pitch
black there
and i think i'll do this whole thing
brighter so
for some contrast even brighter maybe
l there we go l to select the link to
shift the
duplicator and there's another part of
the structure there
and another thing that i like to put on
the top of the buildings usually is just
some
small little really simple objects here
so
simple squares here eat extrude
out select links go a little bit
brighter
and shift d to duplicate that one and
we've got two minutes on the clock so we
can just keep working here
let's put a little fake ground here
shift d to duplicate this one
s to scale it up and now i think i want
to
bring it down slightly there we go
and we'll color right this should we do
green just to simulate that it was on a
green
plot of land or should we go brown no
green that is
but brighter green maybe
and now you can if you've got the time
now which we do we can add a little bit
more detail
let's slant that one maybe and to make a
consistence
i'll delete these instead of just trying
to do the same thing i can do the same
on this one maybe
slant this one and we've got 127 so
l to select the link i'll select the
link shift d to duplicate that
and here as well we've got some time so
should we do something here
i i like to keep the primitive style but
maybe there's
something lacking in here we can tilt
this slope a little bit
make a little bit more interesting and i
think it's lacking something in here so
i'll also do
uh shifty duplicate the face
move it into there just looked a little
bit empty here
so e to extrude it
and again i'm working with a separate
piece of the geometry here
and that should be okay control r
control r let's move this one into
just a bit a little bit more interesting
there maybe
we don't have any doors or entries
that's not really needed either
and we'll put one more object here i've
got 24 seconds we can just put some
a little bit more trimmings again super
primitive objects here
we'll see from a distance when we're
done now that it should look pretty good
i think
you might not think so but from a
distance it will look good
maybe or good enough at least
five seconds to go and
a bit empty there maybe but i think
we're okay
that's it time's up
and we've made these type of buildings
for the rts game and as they are
constructed
i've created a little animation for them
and part of the animation is that the
different parts of the buildings
sort of appear from the ground and it's
also creating like a scaffolding around
the building and
it's got an arm that moves around like a
robotic arm that
puts some weld sparks and i'll just show
a little part of how you can animate
something like that inside of blender
and one way to do it if we go to the
animation tab let's get the
look and feel here the same way shadow
cavity
you don't know what the cavity settings
is it's what makes this
little shiny edges and stuff here we'll
put those on
i usually have that when i model and now
that we've got that one way to do it it
would be to set let's set the timeline
to maybe like 90 frames or something
and we've got everything is just in one
object so the first thing we need to do
is separate it
so i'll select the ground here p and
separate that
let's rename that to ground and then
let's call this one
factory and now i need to
select everything and do p and do by
loose parts and now it's created all of
these are separate objects now
so one way there's the camera so one way
to do it
is to animate the different objects like
this and there's some
maybe it's one easy way to do it but
it's got some drawbacks but i'll show
you anyway
you could select all the objects here's
a little tip as well
if you don't want to accidentally select
the ground here all the time you can go
to this little filter
and enable this selectable and then for
the ground here we can untick this
little
now it's impossible to select this
unless you switch that one back on and
it even works if you press a to select
everything it excludes
that one it's not possible to select it
intentionally or by
mistake so with all these objects now
let's press a to select all of them
and then i'm going to put on automatic
keyframing here and i'm going to go to
the
let's see we'll go to the first frame
here i'm going to
do shift space and g and then i'm going
to move these down here
and that creates a state now for all of
these to be animated outside of view
and then we'll go to frame 90 here and
i'll do alt
g and alt g brings the box to brings it
back to the default location
so if we were to play this one now it'll
just slide the whole building up and
that's not really what we want we want a
little bit more modular
so one way to do that would be to go to
frame five for example
let's do alt z so we see through and
then we'll take this base plate down
here
and on frame five with automatic
keyframing i'm gonna go alt
g and that brings that back to the
proper location for this one
and if we were to press play now that
one will animate
up from zero or from one here to five
really quick
and then you could animate up the next
one so with the old set to see through
and let's put
this part to the building of frame ten
i'll do all g
on that one and that will bring it up to
here and if we press play now
old said to disable c3 we see that they
too
they're just popping up like this now
and what you could do to make it a
little bit more interesting
if we first of all i think i'll move
this keyframe a little bit further
in so we'll go frame 10 for that one
just to show you how it works
and this one will move to frame 20.
let's play that one again
and here what you could do then is
you'll see that both of them start
moving at this
point it's a bit difficult to see but
both of them start moving at the same
time
and if you want them to appear at the
same rate that's uh
not so ideal one way to do it is just to
move this keyframe
g to frame 10 here for this particular
building
now that one won't slide up until it
starts here from frame 10.
so let's press play we'll see appear up
here
and another thing i do to exaggerate a
little bit one of the
principles of animations is that you
should exaggerate
and uh one thing that i like to do then
is
on frame eight for example here we'll do
outside again to see through i should
actually put on the
screencast keys here so on frame eight
i'm gonna do alt g again
and i'm going to move it above above a
little bit like this
and same thing for this second building
we'll go to frame
so two two frames before that one's
finished alt g
and move it a little bit too high and
then back down
so now it does like a little dent like
this up and down
and if we play this back it'll go up up
and then you just keep doing this for
all the objects all said
we could bring this one up next for
example and remember now that we want to
move this
keyframe the start keyframe to frame 20
so it starts at the same base otherwise
they'll
gradually change their pacing so from
frame
20 here we'll go to frame 30 alt g
and then i'll go back two steps alt g
again
and move it a little bit too high and
then we should really repeat that for
all the objects but this is what the
animation would look like
it starts to modularly build the object
one of the downsides to doing this when
you're constructing a factory like this
or a structure
is that you'll end up with a whole bunch
of different actions
spread out over all the different
objects so
if you're going to animate it inside a
blender i would instead recommend that
you keep
everything here as one object like we
did before and then you create an
r mature instead like we've done with a
lot of the characters and then you do
detached bones
in the side of the different building
parts and you map the building parts to
those bones
and then you animate those up and the
same way as you did with this one but
the benefit then is that everything is
going to be inside of one action
and it's going to be one object so it's
a much simpler thing if you want to keep
it inside of unity
inside of blender i said unity inside of
blender blender blender
so the difference though is if you're
going to bring that into unity i don't
recommend using the armature method
because if you're going to use bones in
unity it's going to be using the skinned
mesh renderer and
that's a quite performance intensive and
you don't really want to waste
performance on on that one
to have the bones affect the different
building parts so what i've done in our
game is
that i've actually exported it as
separate objects
into one fbx file and then i animated
the same type of appearance here but i
used the unity animator instead i did
all the animations inside of unity
so it has a very similar type of a
timeline with a
dope sheet style where you can create
keyframes and you keyframe the
xyz position inside of unity so i
animated them
inside there as unity animations and i
kept the objects
separate as we have here so i think that
one's
more performant and if you don't mind
animating it inside of unity i prefer
that method a little bit quicker video
this week isn't it
so uh not too much bonus material but a
little see-through a little hint into
the game development
that we're making for line war and for
the rts game
and hopefully gave you a little few tips
and tricks to
get you along the way to model your own
buildings
so until next video take care and i'll
see you then
bye for now
[Music]
you