hope you've had a good week so far it's
gonna be episode 27 of the lope oh no
I'm in Sweden where it's usually quite
cold and right now it's too warm for me
it's 28 degrees Celsius and that's like
a sauna for me
so struggling here a little bit but I'm
in the basement at least that's the
coolest place in the house literally
because there's my computer room as well
like I said I hope you've had a good
week so far and it's time for episode 27
of the ten minute modelling challenge so
welcome to that one I'm excited this
past week I've worked on the game the
RTS game quite a bit I've there played a
little bit EVE Online with my son I used
to play that game 2004 to 2006 so that's
a long time ago and I'm a space fan
really loved that game but it just takes
up too much time but now dropped in a
little bit during the last week because
my son plays it and he wants to get into
it so I thought I'll spare some time I'm
a complete noob so I'm not getting
anything done I'm doing a few random
missions and just there skilling up a
little bit again so if you haven't
played EVE Online you should try it
maybe one day if you want to have no
time left in your life I don't want if
you've already got no time and then you
tried Eve that's the real challenge
another thing I did last week was I
edited a video I've created a low poly
tutorial so it's about an hour and a
half long so like a full feature film
really too long probably but I wanted to
make a video I've had a lot of requests
to do a slow video where I'd go through
everything in detail so in contrast to
these 10 min builds I've made that video
now so I'm gonna publish it and it's
basically everything I've learned about
low poly modeling in one long video
where I talk a lot I haven't even put
any music in that video being one and a
half hours I thought people can choose
their own music and won't have that and
then they can skip forward back and hear
what I say hopefully to celebrate
space-themed I haven't done space in a
long time and I'm gonna try to make
spaceships as many as I can in ten
minutes and I'm gonna make the modular
if you've seen any of my past videos
I've done some modular spaceships so I'm
gonna try that now I'm gonna try to do
that in ten minutes it's a bit of a time
thief I think you know considering I
made ten cars you might be easy to think
I'll do at least 10 or more ships but
don't think I'll even get that far so
let's see how many we can do in 10
minutes yes it's taken on a mirror top
internet mode free a select everything
scale it down scale on the y-axis and
then we're gonna make some modules here
shift d on the y-axis for
shift are a few times let's make six
modules first one here control are it's
going to be a cockpit so I'll just scale
on proportional off scale it up control
our scale that one up and let's do here
as well Luke I am B and alt s to scale
up that's it that's our cockpit so let's
make it like here's another thing let's
make just some random shape a bit
similar to that one
l scale it up and let's scale that and
let's scale this I'll just do some
random edits here
oh god no clear what I'm doing all the
scale let's do all select that one I to
inset all T face normals and let's do
something as well just to make a little
bit more interesting I to inset that all
t to extrude scale have to fix this it's
a bit broken so that's a some well
flatten it a bit looks a bit too chubby
to to round L scales okay that's gonna
have to be it let's do some weird module
here and maybe six cups all select these
it--in set and period and go to
individual origins scale those down
let's make that orange have it glow a
little bit here another module let's
just make something a little bit longer
maybe control or again move that back
move it out control our it sounds like
the Pirates control
but then a missile like a pirate anyway
that's okay Alti make some other module
here maybe
right insert that each extrude best
scale and let's bring the salute extra
Buster scale how am i doing 802 okay
let's make an engine here I need some
more space for that so I'm going to
disable clipping on that on and move it
out and press F to cap it ctrl R let's
loop cut it not that we control or
control the part I'll scale why control
R let's loop cut here scale that down
oh I have to go to edge select a scale
on the Z scale on X okay and here let's
make the engine eat extrude oh I forgot
I'm not in the mirror section here e to
extrude s to scale I to inset e to
extrude n control force a few times
making block in the back us in a bit
dark here we need to also do ITIN set e
to extrude control also me to there make
that dark control our six loop cuts here
as well
scale on the y-axis okay we need medium
scale Y and let's do some loop
selections here I 10 set and alt s to
scale them down and make them and we
need a wing as well so L clipping is off
what's the F to cap it clipping on scale
that let's make it flat e to extrude s
to scale e to extrude s to scale here we
go e to extrude as the scale I'm going
to bring this up a little bit and then
ctrl + rotate on the y axis and get some
bender to this one move it in control
art let's make a loop cut here as well
scale it I didn't set that on scale that
and make it orange to draw okay 6:15
arms have to start making some
spaceships now so let's select this
whole object shift D to duplicate at X
minus 8 and shift
maybe I'll just to 5 that's probably all
so let's start assembling here this one
will just make scale on the y-axis bring
that on in able to select the linked put
it there I'll just have to do something
wrong to me rotates on the x-axis and
here get grab an engine not on there
that's gonna have to do first one I
don't have to change so much so that's
our first spaceship here another
cockpits tab into that one and let's
move that today I have to move control
okay I don't know why that's happened
well I've changed the center point here
which is really frustrating there we go
okay and scale X okay how should I do
this one rotate on the z axis maybe move
it out there let's rotate on the X let's
make some weird rotate X shifty rotate X
grab some engines maybe I'll put one
here and grab some wings here what's
happen here to these
okay I've done something here so this
one's gonna have no wings apparently we
can just make something else then
instead eat extrude that's the scale
that's gonna be at 435 I don't know what
happened to that wing I probably
destroyed it someone here L white Zeus
get on why here let's make something on
the scale a lot and maybe rotate on the
y-axis as well get that one said there
let's grab it today L on this one scale
okay what should we do this on rotate X
again scale it up a little bit down to
here maybe shifty duplicate that one as
well so 358 let's put some engines here
I'll scale those and you're not a little
bit should we do four engines on this
beast thanks oh yeah some wings they
were tiny about to scale these up to
scale Oh rotate why we're running out of
space between the ships here let's make
something that looks a bit like an
x-wing thing shifty I guess I have to
separate these little bit later on
doesn't matter if they're overlapping a
little bit now I can fix that scale
those down
okay 3:23 let's make another ship here I
have to move these south to give them
some spaceship space G omit this one
okay let's make some something else here
L to select link but wider let's bring
this out a little bit
scale L rotate is that let's bring that
back to there maybe rotate that L just
make something chunky here as well shift
D to duplicate that one move it out
rotate X yeah select these linked I'm
doing 240 shift D okay more engines so
let's bring these so let's put scale to
there maybe and then here what should we
do these just bring these down I guess
let's scale these wings scale on the y
axis make them a bit longer
you can probably pull this out as well
make that one longer maybe do something
like scale or e to extrude these stop
them back to scale those down and out at
sea 240 no - OH - what am I going on
loves the thumb there maybe rotate Y
that's Y okay
one more ship and then I'll tweak the
little bit as well l scale okay you
should do some different type of design
here maybe so let's go forward with this
stuff here and help
let's do clipping off cap those clipping
on put them their engines their wings
125 okay let's see scale there are some
small ship here rotates on the y axis
that in scale that thumb okay so I'll
just tweak some of their I've got one
minute to do so let's just do some
tweaking to decent this one maybe could
do with some feature here so select a
few these items that those eat extra
down and then call it up a bit darker
there maybe what should we do this shift
as well maybe we'll give it some
features on the wing here as well and
eats extrude up scale its scale okay
and for this ship here we've got thirty
four seconds just do some more tweaks
here so topping to that on scale up on
down a bit here maybe select those I
think sets each extrude select a few
these I two inserts it extrudes I
Tennyson
eat extrude down and just make them
large thirteen seconds to go so I'm here
as well I ten sets each extruded s to
scale but eat to extrude s to scale one
second to go that's it
one two three four five
hmm recorded this one actually myself
it's alert sound this is a big foghorn
up here on the mountain near where I
live so that goes off once a month and I
recorded that for me some effects might
be so here we go let's just arrange
these ships a little bit no I won't
modify them at all so let's just put
them into place here okay so we've got
maybe these aren't the most detailed of
ships but we've got sort of different
looking ships let's move them in a
little bit into it so they're a bit
better line top view maybe let's try to
get the center of gravity here for all
of them maybe like that one this one and
this one so they've all got quite
similar features on them because we're
using the same model but I guess if
you're making something like a top-down
shooter game or shoot them up or
something like that then spaceships of
this size are pretty decent they'll like
basically if you keep them at this size
and render them they'll look alright I
think when you get the 3d shading when
you rotate them you have another good
thing with them being modules is that
you can actually assemble the ships just
the way you want you can make hundreds
thousands not millions loads of ships
are out of these modules and they'll all
have a similar style I usually go crazy
I've been made a video a few years ago
where you can actually make a custom
it's like a custom editor where you can
assemble your own ships so I made about
maybe 20-30 modules and you could
basically create any ship with that one
I had a lot of fun with it and I should
probably pick that up something oh yeah
what I was gonna say as well not only
can you make a lot of ships with these
modules another really handy thing is
that you can blow the ships up and like
have separate hitboxes for all the
components and you can even animate them
so you could for example link them
together so when you rotate a wing you
can have engines following along and
things like that really really useful to
make the modular and I've had a few
people say or what about when you have a
geometry that's like linked into each
other so it won't that be wasting
performance of your graphics card but I
mean there's so few polygons there's so
few triangles and your computers and
everything even mobile phones will be
able to render these like a beast they
won't hardly take any performance and
whatsoever so I wouldn't worry about the
fact that it's geometry inside there I
wouldn't even worry about
a bit so go ahead go crazy with it maybe
and it'll be fun to make a little unity
project of this I don't know if a lot of
time for that but if I were to put them
in unity it could be fun to see them fly
about a little bit maybe shoot and
explode maybe I'll do that would you
like to see that in a video maybe give
me a shout in the comments if you do I
want to give a big shout out as well to
my heroic here
discord admins I've got c64 gamer that I
took and Alex rack to that are doing an
amazing job to keep the discord up and
running and they're also introducing
some BOTS now because we're starting to
we've hit over a thousand people so
we're starting to get some issues with
spamming and I'm so noobish when it
comes to this chord so these heroes help
me out a lot so thanks a lot for that
guys I really appreciate it that's gonna
be for this week I've spent so much time
editing that low-poly video so if you
don't have a look check out in the
description or in my channel history and
you can watch that video if you want an
hour and a half this week so this video
is gonna be shorter than my normal ones
but I hope you come back next week and
we'll do a pisode 28 them so until then
have a great week and don't forget to
subscribe if you haven't already if you
want to that is of course and Hittle
like if you like the video and check out
my patreon this one if you haven't done
that
[Music]
you