i'm gonna switch the fan off now and uh
get ready to record episode 34 of the 10
minute modeling challenge
hello guys and welcome back it's been
four weeks of vacation for me but it's
finally coming to a close now
i thought i'd be able to ramp up my
video stuff during my holiday but
more or less i've been spending most of
my time with the kids in the garden
going down to the ocean having a bit of
a swim
you could call it the ocean it's the
baltic sea really it's not been too much
video work for me but i've had a great
time and i hope you've had a great
summer so far despite this whole covered
thing let's just push that down the
toilet and get back
i hope that vaccine comes soon so we can
start mingling a little bit
more i'm dying to go to dying that's
probably the wrong word to use now but
i'm dying to go to the likes of gdc
and unite is it called even unite yeah
unite i remember going to unite berlin
the unity convention there and i really
missed that part of things and i just
want to mingle with some people
and that's coming from me who's normally
just perfectly fine on my own
the holiday is coming to a close so i'm
going to go back to work on the rts game
it's going to be a lot of fun picking
that up again then i'll be making more
videos
the 10 minute modeling challenge and i'm
gonna do more tutorials of course
and not to forget i'm closing in now i'm
past 95k subscribers
thanks a lot guys i'm really excited
about that and to
celebrate 100k i'm gonna do a 24 hour
live stream
that's terrifying because uh i i
struggle with it being a three one i'd
probably get an achy shoulder and all
sorts of things but i'm gonna do it i'm
gonna try 24 hours and i'm gonna model a
whole bunch of characters
so watch out for that one if you want to
know when i'm going to stream it i'm
going to announce it in good time
and i'm going to announce it even now
because it's going to be the first
saturday
after the day i hit 100k
so if i hit it on a saturday i'll have
to wait to the next saturday because i
want to give it enough notice anyway
so keep that in mind guys when i hit
100k subscribers
check when the next saturdays schedule
that in and you're going to have to sit
nailed to your screen and watch me
through the entire session
probably not not gonna happen i'm gonna
struggle myself even got rid of the
green screen for now because
it looked a little bit fake when i was
doing the intros but i'm gonna put it up
for the video so i can filter myself out
feels like i'm on uh on a lot of coffee
in today caffeine
i'm ramping up on the caffeine as you
can hear and i've got my extrusion came
through today after three weeks of
delivery so if you're if you live in
europe and you order
uh my merch be right back you could take
it because something i can't have from
the us
today guys i'm gonna be modeling
something that has been requested a lot
through the past half a year that i've
been making this challenge and it's
gonna be a tank
i'm gonna make a sci-fi tank i hope
that's okay but it gives a little bit
more creative freedom i think than
modeling a real one
if you also want me to model a real tank
give me a shout in the comments
maybe i can do a tiger or an abrams tank
or something like that
so a tank has been requested by drizox
nexus jacob marborg
alfred merton zenob xbb remore
dimitri cabanov does dirk basil aldo and
deerfur
niddler like knitter maybe probably not
that i think it's something else
anyway i also had a request not to model
a tank from shibby bill he said
there's enough tanks on the internet but
i'm gonna model a tank anyway so sorry
for that ship named little i also had a
request from
my female audience they want me to make
not only a tank but tank tops
so this is just going to have to be an
interim i didn't have a chance to
fix that much through my vacation time
but i'm going to be making the e2
extrude as the scale tank tops
especially the e2 extrude that's the
scale tank tops are coming but for now
let's model a tank
[Music]
thank me later i sounded irish thank me
later
no it didn't ready steady
go when we're off yes i can see it and
auto mirror
of course tab into edit mode scale scale
it down
go to side view move it up scale it down
on the z axis
move it to there remember this is going
to be a sci-fi tank now
i'm going to do it like that scale y
that's y
e to extrude scale y and
l let's go side view here make it longer
fatter and wider usually not always that
good but for a tank i think it's pretty
good
move it out a little bit more and uh
let's do
e2 extrude one more time and i'm going
to extrude these up
all t this time to do extrude long phase
normals this is going to be like the mud
guards
why a sci-fi tank would need mud guards
i have no idea shift select a few of
those e to extrude that on
select the little ends here now actually
i need that little
one as well alt e to extrude long face
normals
and here let's make the side tracks as
well
so shift d to duplicate those two faces
scale them up a bit
move them down and scale them on the y
axis
maybe like that and e to extrude that
whole thing and that's going to be our
tracks they're going to poke out a
little bit wider
the wider the cooler okay so
let's shift select a few of these
actually i could have selected it with
control but never mind
move that down get some angle on that
one and how am i doing 838 okay
now i'm gonna raise it up uh this is a
sci-fi tank but i'm gonna have a little
bit of inspiration from like the
m1a2 out of abrams
i'm gonna raise this rear part up a
little bit
i think it looks a little bit cool
control select to there
move that back and that should be all
right
now let's do here's the tracks then
let's just also do them a little bit
tron like
tron or sci-fi i'm not sure but it's
going to be low poly of course
need to extrude the center let's select
this whole thing and make it
brown black so like this make it i like
to instead of a normal gray i like to
have this
bluish tint to it i think it looks a bit
more metal like
okay and now let's make the turret so
i'm gonna do
actually i wanted these to be raised as
well i don't want
necessarily that to be no i don't that
should be alright
uh shift d duplicate that face scale it
down move it in there
e to extrude that one and let's actually
scale it on the y
axis shift d to duplicate it again
scale it before i scale it let's
let's see l to select it move it up a
bit e to extrude
slide it to there up need to extrude
slide it to there so this is going to be
the upper part of the turret
i always thought it was turrent when i
was a kid but apparently it's turret
i learned about 20 years ago e to
extrude that on
scale need to extrude and scale it down
maybe bring it in a little bit let's try
to get some
i think the lower and sleeker it looks
uh the cooler looks so let's do that
and ctrl r let's do 6 oh whoa not 60.
ctrl r 6 loop cuts there
and alt shift select these i to inset
and b to get the boundary thing in the
center remember
alt s to scale them down and
control plus to expand the selection and
make that black it looks a bit
some feature of some sort now let's make
the
this one we can tilt a little bit more
as well i think it's more modern to have
it
like slanted so the shells bounce off
this one now we're going to make
the cannon before i do that actually
i'll do i to insert this one
move it in e to extrude it
in like that now shift d to duplicate
that scale
y zero to flatten it
and scale it down a bit
and before i do anything else i'll do
ctrl r to loop cut that one
move it out i want to have some shape to
this barrel
a bit sci-fi as well i have no clue if
that's sci-fi or not but we need sci-fi
e to extrude
e to extrude s to scale e to extrude e
to extrude s to scale
e to extrude does that look sci-fi i
think
i think it does when it's like uh flat
or i need a wider like this
and higher control r
let's do uh like this alt e to extrude
long face normals scale them down
some feature of some sort and
i'm also going to do like a rail gun
type of thing so let's take this one
and do he tooks through that one need to
extrude it again
move it in a bit and now i'm going to do
this has got
sorry guys if you were expecting a
normal tank this is a sci-fi tank
remember e to extrude
s to scale move it in it's like a tie
fighter look here
scale zed but a railgun for some reason
the ones i've seen anyway i've got these
uh ramp things on the side or rail
things on the side so
let's move this one out a bit as well
control r let's do six
loop cuts here as well alt select those
with shift
i to inset alt s to scale them down
maybe like that and then g okay that was
black as well
and for this barrel thing we need to do
uh item
no select both of these actually
item set each extrude
i to in set one more time nope can't do
that
to move this down a bit to give it some
space
and then iten set e to extrude that on
okay that's not nice let's extrude this
whole thing in instead e texture that
looks
more mean i think control selector there
i to inset but b to get the boundary off
because i want to have these alt s
raised up a little bit as well
also gives it a bit of character and
maybe it will raise these up as well
i think set and move those up as well
like that actually i'll do e to extrude
those and then maybe
scale them down and then i'll take these
edges
here that one move them forward okay so
that gives a bit of a feature so 349
let's do some more features here then a
lot of feature stuff here we can put
some armor and plates on it maybe so i
shift select a bunch of these
maybe like that and maybe these two as
well
no i'll leave those i'll do those after
i didn't set twice so i get the
individual alt s to scale along normals
like that ctrl plus and then let's
darken those to there
control minus and make the armor plates
a little bit darker
here let's put some features here i to
inset twice so we get the boundary thing
off
alt e to extrude long face normals just
do some weird features here i think
itin set alt s to scale the one up
so i have no clue what i'm doing
hope that's okay with you guys need to
extrude that one
i'll just kind of slap some features on
here literally literally but
not slapping anything but yeah let's see
okay so here let's do shift select those
i've got 251 on the clock here
let's make that one armored colored as
well
there i'm feeling a bit rusty because i
missed last week
well i had a video last week but i
wasn't uh recording i recorded that one
two weeks ago since i was doing uh
the holiday thing so i feel a little bit
rusty here oh that's okay
scale that down no let's not skip it
down
okay let's do uh some more features i'll
just put some more features on here
all the to extrude long face normals
like that g to move it to black
here let's do more features
you get the drill the jill
you understand what i'm doing it's just
some random stuff here now e to extrude
as the scale
uh here inside the barrel of the
gun let's do that black as well
156 what more should we do maybe we'll
do uh
this track thing is going to have to
stay like that i think maybe here we'll
do also i think set
and move that out slightly more features
just some more detail
and here let's do
what should we do here any ideas
suggestions
this is not live things i couldn't even
take your suggestions if i want to do
i think the only thing i really have
time for is to do more extrusions and
scaling here so
that's all i'm going to do for now i
think balti to extrude long face normals
so this is all the detail armored plates
are there
should we do some coloring on the barrel
here as well maybe
make that dark maybe we'll
change this whole barrel actually to a
darker shade
there and here this color in there we
can change no that's all right
i think and
we could do here so 53 seconds maybe
we'll do some features on the back here
as well
items that when i say features
nothing magical here but let's do an
antenna here or something
uh scale it down there's going to be two
antennas
e to extrude or it's not going to be an
antenna at all it's just a separate
feature so now
my i'm i've been exposed now as you can
see i have no clue what i'm doing i'm
just
extruding scaling and doing weird stuff
height
and set e to extrude
18 seconds should we color that on
different
should we make that a different color as
well
for some more features i've got 10
seconds
um just make that one a bit darker too
and color that one a bit brighter
and that's it 10 minutes oh i restarted
it
ah what am i doing
alright guys there we have it it's a
sci-fi tank or something of that sort
and obviously the tracks won't really
roll
because uh it's more of a fixed tank so
again for low poly stuff this should
work pretty good
because all i would be doing is sliding
around um
and you'd probably put some track marks
behind it
like just like a particle system that
drops off some little tracks
and you could separate this uh into a
separate torrent
but i wanted to make a sci-fi tank keep
it quite wide
and uh quite flat and wide i think that
looks a little bit sci-fi
and then all i really have time for is
to do all of these different insets and
extrusions and scaling that gives i
think it gives a little bit like
jagged features like this that adds that
little sci-fi look without having to do
any uv unwrapping
and for the canon here i was a little
bit inspired maybe by uh
some sci-fi tanks i'm also think maybe
even
from what's it called starcraft 2 like a
siege tank type of thing and i also
wanted to have
those uh tie fighter sides to it looks a
little bit like a rail gun that would
accelerate the munitions
even further or the projectile so that's
one big
barrel though you wouldn't want to be
shot with whatever cartridges coming out
of the
cartridge do you remember those
cartridge
used to have a spectra video msx that
was my first computer that my dad bought
and you put the cartridge in
had a nice feel to it when it clicked
down into that slot and then it was
replaced by disk drives and things like
that
tangent anyway if you're not happy with
the proportions
uh these are separate objects so if i
press l to select that one if you wanted
a longer barrel
you just scale y axis and move it to
there
and there you have it a longer barrel
and if you wanted to have this one maybe
the whole tank
wider just l to select everything and
move it out since you're mirrored
so you're quite free to change these
things around even if you're
sort of finished with the tank and
another thing you can do
let's bring that down so i'm working
with the same tank as before
and another thing you want to do
obviously this is called cube because i
started with a default cube but if we
rename this one to
let's do f2 and call it tank sorry cube
i had to rename here for now
but it's still you in the soul and
for a game ready objects you'd have to
separate a few things because you can't
keep them
the same so this turret for example i
press l here to select the linked
vertices here for the turret
p and separate the selection there into
a new object and same for this
barrel here l p separate
selection let's select this one and call
it
barrel and this one is turret
you want these as separate objects and
you want this one to be a child of that
object because when you rotate the
turret
you want the barrel to follow along with
it
but what we could do here is uh first of
all i need to change the center of
gravity here because if i rotate this
one actually it's not too bad
and get away with it but
let's do a right click on this one and
do set origin
origin to center of mass i don't really
know what the difference is between
surface and volume
oh yeah you can't have the mirror
modifier on
when you do that because uh it breaks
the mirror modifier can i do
set origin to geometry
so this is a problem because it sets the
center of this object into here
which is not so good so i'll probably
what i'll do here is i'll
select this one press h to hide it tab
into edit mode
select this face here shift s cursor to
selected
and i probably want to slide it further
back here let's pick that vertex
and do shift s cursor to select it maybe
there
and now i can tab out of that one right
click set origin
origin to 3d cursor and now when we
rotate this one let's do alt h
to unhide rotate z that's a pretty good
rotation for that one so rotate
that yeah and now we also need to
select this barrel here barrel or barrel
is it like this is it barrel
barrel of a gun barrel must be barrel so
for this one we could just go to here
and do
child of constraints actually first of
all let's change the
central mass on this one too then we'll
hide this one
i'm going to keep that here so shift s
cursor to selected tab right click set
origin
origin to 3d cursor now alt h to unhide
that one
yes now we can go to the object
constraint tab here
add child of pick
the turrets and then we have the set
inverse there and now when we rotate
this one the barrel will follow along
also when
this uh bad boy or bad girl bad lady
when it shoots i usually animate a
little recoil here
so i'd recommend that for a firing
animation if we do shift space
g you just basically do that
looks pretty cool when it shoots so just
the whole thing recoil so you could
actually even separate these
uh rail gun side objects into separate
ones and just maybe the center piece
goes in and out
all right so time has come for the bonus
tip of this video and
someone suggested in the chat i think a
couple of premieres ago
something really nifty and unfortunately
i don't remember the name of the person
so apologies for that but i want to
bring the tip up and hopefully i can
give you a credit in the future
but when i've created new geometry or a
new object here let's say we have
we're in object mode here so let's have
nothing selected and i do shift a
and then i add a cube here and you can
see that this one doesn't have this
texture enabled so
i've in the past i have gone into
shading here and then i've selected the
objects and i've selected the material
selected it like this and then switched
back to my editing tab just to get this
here there's a much better way here so
i'll delete let's see i'll
delete this one add it again shift a
add the cube and see here it's got
nothing so i select this one first
and i shift select this tank afterwards
i'll do control
l and then make link to material and
then
this one gets that material so that's a
much much faster way
to get all the objects or all the new
objects to share the same material
instead of having to go into the shading
tab so thank you very much
i'm actually gonna look up so the
freshest was one of the guys apparently
in the comments a couple of weeks ago
that suggested this to control
l to link materials from active so
thanks the freshest
maybe it was someone else as well in the
in the live chat that suggested this so
sorry for not
mentioning your name but i really
appreciate this one it's a much faster
way
alright guys i hope you enjoyed that
video it was a lot of fun to make a
little bit of a sci-fi tank hopefully
i'll get my gears together
and get back into cranking out some
objects and watch out for that live
stream that i'm going to be doing it's
going to be a lot of fun
and a lot of coffee so i keep remember
the next saturday after i hit 100k
subscribers i'm going to do the 24 hour
live stream and
scream 20 24 hour live stream that's
going to be something
no live stream and i'll be cranking out
a lot of low poly characters that and
animate them as well i'll do a whole
bunch of characters i've thought of some
stupid names for them all
so i'm just going to be going through
the list and making one by one by one by
one
and then i'll just uh yeah see where it
takes me
so uh thanks a lot for my patreons and
uh i really appreciate the support that
you're
able to provide through my patreon page
and for those
i add these models so you can download
them likes a little bit behind but i'll
bulk add them and i'll be batching a few
more objects together from the most
recent 10-minute builds there for the
patreon downloads give it a thumbs up if
you like this video and don't forget to
subscribe and i'll see you
next week for another 10 minute modeling
challenge bye for now
[Music]
you