hello guys and welcome to episode four
is it 47 i keep saying it wrong yes it
is hello guys and welcome to episode 47
of the 10 minute modeling challenge this
time it really is number 47. i said it
wrong last week but never mind
in this video i'm gonna try to do the
impossible i'm gonna in 10 minutes
create a perfect topology car
with all the quads and i'm gonna nail it
hopefully
let's see how that goes well i've done a
lot of low poly cars before but i really
wanted to find a way to
to model cars quickly and keep that
perfect topology and i've never really
been a fan
where you have to actually model like
the side or splines
connect them all together and try to
keep that quad topology and i've always
heard that you shouldn't use
a box method to model cars and i've
actually always thought myself i can't
really create a nice
looking car with a box modeling but i
spent a bit of time now and i've
thought of how it must be possible and i
think i've found a method
to do it so make sure you stick around
now for this video and
look at it to the end because gonna do
the modeling and then i'm gonna show you
the bonus material as well how
you can actually work from that model
now and start using uh probably
proportional editing to get it
into doing some crazy stuff so make sure
you watch to the end now
you've heard me check this out as well
it's a book it's the sound of star wars
check this out
sound 125 it's the ray gun or the laser
la serie in swedish of boba fett the
bounty hunter this whole book is full of
cool stories how they record those sound
effects and you might be surprised that
everything that you hear in a film
is fake for example take a gladiator you
see a horse riding in you think that
that's
the sound of a real horse no no
obviously you've got the coconut thing
going
on with the with that well it doesn't
sound like that now but
the sword that he pulls out it's like a
fish slice and when he rides
his armor and uh sword and the shield
and stuff that's just uh some
rattling chains and some leather straps
that someone's swinging
yeah even the horse sound itself you'd
think that was a real horse but no no no
it's the same guy
who's like flapping the straps he's gone
stuff like that so it's not even a real
horse so all the sound effects all the
foley stuff
is all fake so check that out as well
google some videos on it and i might
even feature some on a video on my own
the lord of the rings
flapping of a dragon's wing a cheese
crater on a string that they're swinging
in the air
if you want to support this channel and
have a little shout out and if you're
watching the premiere you can actually
click the little super chat or the super
sticker icon
and i'll make sure to mention you in the
next episode of 10 minute modeling
challenge so we had andreas brill and
said
infensia do you mean like this and
exactly andreas that's exactly what i
mean and here's your shout out we also
had
draco so card i can never say your name
but you like to hear it because you said
me me me
i like to hear my name lol and then we
have lumenia
you uh said happy modeling ducks no
dudes
yeah and luminia is a guy from denmark
and he's making a super cool
fireworks game that he's hoping to
release i think now before
the new year so check that out it's like
a low poly style but really neat
lush looking fireworks and i actually
recorded a few of the sound effects that
i used i don't know if you're still
using those ones check out that channel
i'll put that in the description
check out that game and then we had toot
84 you said to buy some oreo cookies for
the next stream
smiley face thanks for all the nice
content and thank you for that comment
and thanks for their donation because i
actually bought myself some oreo cookies
and i'd like to show them but i can't
because i ate them and so did my kids
and my wife
so we appreciate that thanks a lot all
right strap things on
if that's what you do and uh let's get
started
i have no idea why i'm saying stuff like
that
okay for cars i've realized that the
cavity setting isn't the best
even though i've got the merch the
cavity shirt here with the default cube
of course i'm going to start with the
default cube
but i have to disable cavity for this
one because it doesn't look so good for
cars
are you ready i'm ready let's get it on
i used to watch uh ufc back in the day
so here we go ready
steady go when we're off yes and auto
mirror as usual tab into edit mode
scale y five move it up
scale z flatten it and now we're gonna
do loop cutting
ctrl r loop cut one along here and then
side view again ctrl r
let's put one here ctrl r put one there
ctrl r ctrl r there
and then one in the middle of each
control r control r and then we need one
more loop cut ctrl r
here and i've said you shouldn't really
use a box when you do
cars but i've changed my mind now i'm
going to use probably this all the time
though
so eye to inset now and make sure you
press b
for boundary so you connect it in the
center there down below
and now we can do side view double click
a to d select
b to box select just the side ones there
shift and deselect these note
and then e to extrude quite a bit to
there and now we've actually got a
pretty cool topology here
maybe i'll do alt select
those bring that down slightly if i
press
period make sure i've got medium point
here and i'll shift select a bunch of
these now i might
yeah the time is actually running scale
y axis
to there select that one shift select
these
scale y there i'll just do roughly
the same and then shift select these and
move them up slightly
and now we've got pretty good wheel
arches that the good thing about these
wheel arches now is that you can
they're real arches real wheel arches so
if i control and shift select a few of
these and then now we can bring this in
and make those little wide
things go in there so i'm gonna make a
muscle car i'll um
just come up with something on my own
but i think i'll uh maybe like a dodge
charger inspired
front or something where it is a little
bit aggressive
well maybe move this down to there
bring this forward get a little bit of a
mean look that should do it
and then here in the back we can fix
this in a second ctrl
r and now i'll shift select these and
here's another trick now i to inset
again
with boundary like this so we get the
center pretty good
and then e to extrude this one now and
it looks like a limo now so i'll
fix it a little bit but that's the scale
e to extrude there
and then now let's shape it into a bit
of a rounder shape
so just shift select those and
we can bring this forward quite a bit
now i think
so i'll select these whole faces
and bring that to there and this one
even further oop i'm gonna move that
down maybe
to there and forward both
that's it and we're still on a quad
topology here and
uh quite it should be quite good to work
off now
so let's shape this edge here so how am
i doing 709
bring that in and down a bit the whole
edge
to there bring this up a bit i'll wait
with that actually
but i can select this round this off a
little bit
to there and maybe round this off
slightly as well so that's it and it's a
little bit too long probably
box selected there and a bit too high
bring it down and to there
okay and this one we can change maybe
well
some shape
rotate there all right
all set to see that again and then now
we can do control r
do one more loop cut this is a nice
thing now with that finally having a
good topology sorry for
leading a stray for a long time but
this should work now hopefully now we
can just extrude this
bonnet or hood depending on where you
live in the world
so i'll shift select a few of these and
then just to
e to extrude s to scale this one down
let's make it a bit aggressive stylized
again it's not gonna
be able to see out through that window
but that's okay looks pretty cool
looks a bit mean okay and that's it
let's uh
see 548 i'm wasting time here precious
time
we need to put some lights on here so
let's do a headlight
in here gg to move that onto the side
actually i'll do the whole gg there
let's put a headlight here
i to inset e to extrude
and the grill e takes iten set e to
extrude
and down and then here make some tail
lights
iten set e to extrude
and i to inset and e to extrude that one
as well and then let's
do a number plate so to there colorize
the car a
select everything let's make a blue
supercar is that
is there such a thing we can bring this
down slightly
tweak this okay and
gg gg slides it pretty good up these
edges here let's put a wing on it as
well it's probably not very super
like a muscle car like but i won't have
a wing on this one so let's just do
let's wing it
we'll do e to extrude this whole thing
move it back
and then select these i to inset
and delete to delete them faces how am i
doing 4
35 alt shifts like this
and then right click on them and do
bridge edge loops and that's going to be
the wing
i think yeah okay let's colorize
uh taillights they can be red g on the
left side there
ctrl plus let's make a darker blue here
as if it was shaded
and then g get a white number plate
and then headlights i guess oh what's
happened here
i have no idea what's happening here
let's hide it this must have been
selected i have to fix this
control plus delete faces
and delete faces oh no
delete edges then expect this
select a few of these apparently delete
edges
so i've got plenty of time or something
g let's make it dark and then here
g orange okay now we'll make some
bumpers as well
uh i'll select these a little bit over
the top probably
stylized as well alt e to extrude long
phase normals s
scale and bring them forward a bit ctrl
plus
let's make them like a black color or
something
here as well how am i doing 320
ulti extra long face normals moving back
control plus do that one a bit very dark
lucky thing as well okay now color
and uh we'll do the wheel arches here
the real wheel arches
wheel real wheel wheels on wheels
real wheel spare wheels i don't know
what i'm talking about
what's going on okay i'm shift selecting
a view of these
and i should have just done a different
method but that's okay g to move that on
to there
and then oh we need maybe to make
something that looks a little bit like
windows as well not like windows 10 or
anything but
like car windows
and i should probably bring gg slider
as well let's try to color it just see
if it works
so it could be refined a little bit
probably
g let's make black windows gg
and gg okay this could have probably
been
perhaps a little bit better let's make
oh make it blue again okay
uh maybe not the best rear window there
but i've got two minutes to go and i
need to put some wheels on so
let's go side view shift right click
shift a cylinder and
let's do 12 scale zed
and let's do uh
i have to disable clipping i think move
them into there
rotate y 90 side view
scale them down to there rotate
move them up again a scale 0 on the left
and g to move it to black move it out to
there
we can fix this in a second 128 so
select that one
i to inset a to extrude let's do simple
wheels here
i to inset e to extrude s to scale
control plus a few times to there let's
come
like a gray like alloy
rims shift select these g to move to
black so it looks like
shadow and
move them out we can fix the wheel arch
just now a little bit overly aggressive
here so
l shift d move it to there
how am i doing 56 seconds okay here's
the nice thing now with the wheel arches
we can
uh select these if i hit them
i'll just shift select this control
i actually just do control r of course
and then move this in
and s to scale a little bit and then
here
same thing ctrl r scale them
and move them into there
[Music]
and we can do i've got 28 seconds here
maybe i can
get the rear view mirror gg
e to extrude r to rotate g to move
front okay this looks really weird so
alt said
we can fix we can stylize a little bit
later on
so here rotate
it extrude r to rotate one second e
takes red
that's the scale i rotate that
[Music]
okay so let's see what we got
so pardon the shape of the car that
didn't turn out that all that great
but i think the topology is really good
and i guess uh it's pretty good that it
ended up
this uh not so good because now we can
actually play a little bit in the bonus
material and
show why this topology is pretty good uh
there are a few things that we could fix
with it um there's a few things down
here that i did when i scaled it we can
do
the whole shape is a little bit odd
which we can fix
all of this now so here comes the bonus
tips now and i think yeah this is why
you should stay to the end and not just
switch off now really stay to the end
and watch this bit because
if you have this shape and you wanted to
start to refine this either into a make
it let's say you wanted to change the
front here we could uh
let's see if i do proportional editing
and make sure
connected only is on so we don't want to
scale the wheels now and then
i can do scale z and then
scale that up maybe use the mouse wheel
to change that
maybe i want to bring this down g z
scroll the mouse wheel down change it to
there maybe
g to move that forward even more if you
wanted it more aggressive maybe we
wanted to change this whole thing
a little bit so maybe it's too long so
alt z
one select these
move it in maybe here
move that in make it shorter
back is way too long here as well so
let's do control
move it to there move this in
move that to there
and then alt side again here let's say
we wanted to
make this rear view mirror actually look
a little bit nicer we could do
e to extrude has s scale that one down
maybe we'll bring these back and
the bottom here
to there colorize this black g
black
move that down to there maybe oh that's
with too much
g
okay and here the wheel arches as well
here's uh i think this is probably the
most important
part that i'm most happy with the whole
build as well it's uh the fact that
these wheel arches now can be really
just
selected like this usually i ended up
with really weird edges right here
so but now s to scale if you want to
make more room for the wheels you could
do o for proportional again as to scale
down
has to scale it move it up if you want
to do that
and same here in the back if i do select
this one
ctrl select to here all the way down to
there let's do scale on this one
move that in maybe
and if you want to bring this in
let's select these move oh proportional
off now baby
bring those in get this whole thing
flaring out a little bit more
and if you wanted to change here i
noticed that the bonnet was a little bit
too started too far
so let's just slide that back maybe we
can do either
so it goes like this we can bring
this down
g g
bring this up out
and if you want to change the look of
the headlights maybe you want this
to be more like a teardrop so front view
o proportional g move that
to maybe like this
s to scale it g to move it
and then we'll bring this down as well
to there
we could control select the whole front
there maybe drag it forward
a little bit pointy nose also a bit over
the top maybe
i like the film with sylvester stallone
over the top
cow's a dog a weird film just out of the
blue everyone was so
hyped on rambo and rocky and stuff that
they pretty much binged
anything that sylvester stallone pulled
out of his
repertoire so maybe something like that
okay oh yeah i wanted to show this as
well i managed to
mess up a little bit here you can if you
wanted to space these out you could do
gg
just move them apart a little bit here
to keep the quad gg
gg that's it
and you could work on uh fixing the rear
window that was a bit strange maybe we
can
move that forward a bit down
so i'm not a car designer by the way so
sorry for this
i should have probably used some sort of
a blueprint the good thing about the 10
minute modeling challenge is
that i can just blame it on the time
frame so
and if you wanted to make the whole
thing wider a select everything just
move it wider
that's it or it controls that if you
didn't want to make it wider
if you really want to go crazy you can
actually do that as well and
uh check this out let's say we wanted to
make a
like a fun looking car not that this
isn't fun looking this is looking dodgy
already
but let's go back with proportional now
let's go crazy
let's do g to move this one scroll it up
let's lean that one forward let's pick
that one
g to move that on scroll it up sometimes
i've seen these like cartoony
uh looking cars so i wanted to try to
make something a little bit similar
r to rotate g to move that on
let's go even crazier with the front
here g
r to rotate g
that's this looks a bit strange maybe
move that one let's do this whole thing
g to move this
wheel that up let's make it a lot wider
here
let's select control selected there
g x
control selector there gx
and now you can even r to rotate
do the same here ctrl selected to there
or to rotate and then we have to do the
same with the wheels then
so has to scale them up
and i think when i see these funny
pictures of these they even do the crazy
stuff when they draw them like with the
wheels
so let's bring g x
and then here let's do the same thing
here
l scale that up g
pick the bottom g x
and here we can just g to move this
whole thing to make it fit
like that and i understand if you don't
like this card that's perfectly fine i
just wanted to make a point that you can
make them uh really
like the cartoon stylized ones again
with the topology now it should deform
really nicely well
not that this is deforming that nicely
but
you get the point i think that you could
make these uh funky looking cars
and maybe we'll do a over the top here
with a
bonnet or the hood let's do one of those
intakes here as well
e to extrude
bring this in
and bring that up even more
g is that oh no g y
and g is that that's what i want
i to inset e to extrude
g okay g
proportional
all right
shift selector there rotate
i've always thought that box modeling
didn't really allow you to create a good
car and i've even seen tutorials from
some established people to say that
don't start from a box start from from
splines instead
but the two key things here that i think
really makes this work is
when you do the wheel arches that you do
the inset with the boundary off
and also when you extrude the top of the
car but you also do an inset and then
you extrude that inset that's going to
be the key takeaway from this video that
you can make
car topology from box modeling and you
can get it pretty good as well and
you can keep those quad going you don't
really have to compromise on them
anywhere
and you'll always be able to do the loop
cuts it'll always deform nicely
i'm really really happy that i found
this method now because i've it's been a
bit it's probably going to be the
holy grail for me when it comes to
modeling because i always like to start
with a box i don't really like the
spline modeling where you outline them
and i'm really really
happy that this box method now works and
i'm super excited about the wheel arches
because the loop cuts now will allow you
to keep those arches coming out
and always when i've done trying to keep
the quads when i do spine modeling i
always end up messing it up
around those arches so i hope you
managed to take some stuff away from
this as well and i think i'm gonna do a
proper tutorial on this topic as well
maybe i don't have to stress the car to
make it look a little bit so
so weird of a car maybe i can actually
use a blueprint so i make some real cars
how about that i'm going to upload this
to my patreon page so anyone on the
tutorial tier
which is two dollars at the moment
anyone on that tier will be able to
download this blend file have a play
with it and all the other 40
whatever episodes that i've got those
blend files will be added there as well
so head over to patreon.compencia if you
want to give that a little bit of extra
support and hit the like button if you
liked the video and subscribe if you
haven't already
and i'm going to see you next week for
another 10 minute modeling challenge
bye for now
[Music]
you