[Music]
[Applause]
okay
[Music]
it's got PI it from jumping from the
camera to here not a good sign
alright guys and welcome back to episode
number two of making the low-poly racer
I'm super excited that the other video
did so well I was really surprised that
it had had a lot of use a lot of
visitors a lot of the new subscribers as
well so welcome to you guys I'll still
spend a little bit more time in blender
in this episode I've got a model some of
the rocks and trees and some fences and
Road barricades like yes tire sucks and
things like that I'll slow down a few
parts because it contains a few maybe
trick tips and tricks that I haven't
mentioned before so I have a look at
those but then we'll start exporting the
objects and bring them into unity so I'm
also really happy to hear that so many
people enjoy looking forward to the
unity stuff because that's where I feel
most at home I do blender but also the
unity and I'd love to show you guys how
we put this game together so I've had a
lot of requests will you show the wheel
physics will you show how to do the
powerslides and how to do the colliders
and yeah you name it so I'm gonna try to
cover as much as I can in this series
I'll jump back into blender for a bit
and then we'll move on to exporting
these things and bring them into unity
and episode 3 will be pretty much all
unity so stay tuned subscribe if you
haven't already hit a like if you'd
liked it and let's let's get a move on
let's make this racing game happen again
[Music]
first of all we're going to create some
stones they're gonna be used as
decorations and obstacles so you can see
here the car hits them maybe they're a
little bit too light but it's easy
enough to increase the mass of the rigid
body immunity in blender I you do shift
a and I create a new mesh it's gonna be
a cube this time and I use I create
these models in the same scene as I did
before and it's just find a little bit
easier to get the scale correct and I've
already got the material set and don't
be afraid that there's a lot of objects
in your scene just hide a lot of them I
pressed ctrl to to subdivide the mesh
into two levels to create this stone and
then I just select a few vertices and I
switch into proportional editing you can
hit o on your keyboard and that'll
enable proportional editing so you can
just start moving some objects use this
mouse wheel to scroll it down and work
up the regardless of what you need or
depending on what you need and then you
can just shape the stone a little bit to
get a shape that you prefer
it's not too picky about it I just
played around with it a little bit to
get some I like to have a flat bottom so
they can rest nicely on the ground as
well just there repeat this by moving
some vertices around until you're happy
with the stone shape then you can hit a
to select all the vertices and then
press shift D to duplicate the mesh and
I'm still in the same object I've just
the touch those or and attach them I've
duplicated those vertices and then I can
create a new stone and just change the
shape a little bit
I often work inside the same object yeah
I think it's easier to just duplicate
the mesh inside of an object instead of
necessarily duplicating the objects but
it's up to whatever you prefer okay this
is going to be a bit boring to watch so
I'll fast forward this a little bit but
I do a bunch of stones think five in
total and just shape them a little
different and have some different sizes
you can always rescale them inside of
unity later on as well but I made two to
the last box I made a little bit larger
and pointer you could use those as
bigger obstacles if you want alright you
can add a bevel modifier and that shapes
the edges of the rocks a little bit as
you can see I
like two maybe gives a little bit more
of a cartoony look and you can play
around a little bit with the angle
settings to get the look and feel that
you want again I think it breaks up the
little plainness of the of the mesh so
you can do it if you want and then you
apply the modify and that will bake the
changes into the mesh and then what I do
is I add a subdivide modifier a
subdivision modifier and that adds a lot
more detail but I'm not gonna keep them
like that so I add a decimate modifier
which is a bit contract contradictive
and then I slide it down and that's that
actually reduces the the number of their
faces again you wonder why I'm doing
that but that's because I like to get
them a bit irregular now we're gonna
create some tires some type barriers
they'll be used individually and in
stacks of tires so again I'm in the same
scene and I'm gonna use the car wheel so
if you haven't seen when I model the
cars check out that video but then I
just hit L to select the linked part is
this on the wheel itself and then I do
shift D to duplicate the selection again
into a separate mesh he could create
this tire all the way from scratch again
but since I had it I wanted to keep keep
the consistent look so I decided to
duplicate it I applied the mirror
modifier so I didn't have that messing
around I could have probably just
deleted a mirror modifier instead
because I don't really need one wheel
but I decided the family to do that just
remove the interior rimmed geometry and
keep the tyre you select whichever
vertices you want to delete and then you
just delete them the faces in this case
and then I ended up with a bit of a
weird-looking tired so I had to shape it
and fix it a little bit and I selected a
face on the back that was solid I
deleted that one clicked all left mouse
to ring select the edge and then I slid
it in and I hold the control key and do
snapping so I get to the exact same
location as the vertex or the inner rim
I do f3 to bridge the edge loops and
then that bridges the faces and now I've
got a tire I applied the mirror modifier
apparently I didn't do that one before
and then I just delete I think here this
one now my
like a and I select the all the vertices
and that is shift s a new cursor to
selected the reason for this is I want
to set the origin so press f3 and type
set origin and then set it to the 3d
cursor you have to do that in object
mode so top out of edit mode and do that
again
so again f3 set origin and then I'd set
it to the center of the mass for all the
stones here as well origin to center of
mass volume if you select that one
it'll center the object volume on today
I do this for all the stones we want to
make sure that all the objects have a
nice center position then for the wheel
I rotate it so I hit R on the keyboard
and I rotate it by typing Y 90 that will
flip it nicely 90 degrees I move it down
to the ground just so I can see what it
looks like I'm gonna create this a stack
of tires as well they're used as
decorations and obstacles you can see
the car hits them and they're a heavier
in mass so they don't fly around as
quickly as a tire and they'll save some
performance as well by being a single
big mesh press shift D in blender to
duplicate the entire object that I did
before and hit tab to go into edit mode
and then I do shift D a bunch of time to
duplicate the selected vertices I just
do this over and over again shift D and
then I'm position at reposition the tire
this is no particular order that I have
to do this I just went off just random
basically duplicating these tires then I
move them up a little bit to try to
create some some sort of a stack of
tires for a stash boss - normal stash a
stash of tires I rotate them a little
bit as well to keep a bit of an
inconsistent look so it looks like
they've just been thrown a bunch of
tires on to there so I'll fast forward
this part because it's basically just a
bunch of shift DS and R to rotate them
and then I try to place them so it looks
decent it's not too picky to be honest
just do it whatever way you feel it then
I wanted to add some straps to hold this
into place they look a bit weird if you
hit that and the tires didn't go flying
all over the place I hit shift a and
added a new mesh
and I added a plane this time press 1 on
the keyboard to enter vertex mode and
then I can move the vertices into place
make sure you have vertex snapping on
because then it makes it easy to hold
the ctrl key and you can snap that to
the vertices of the other object which
is the tire object in this case I just
hold the control key and I move the
vertices so it snaps - pretty good
places onto the other tires go into edge
mode and then select the edge and hit e
to extrude upon and now you just repeat
the process of moving the vertices with
the ctrl key and then you extrude again
and you keep doing that until you wrap
your new mesh around the tires so you
get something that looks a bit like a
strap around it and that fits a little
bit snug around it I'll just fast
forward this again I do all T as well to
extrude the faces along the normals so I
get a bit of volume to the strap so they
don't cut through that'll expand the
strap out and then I fast forward a
little bit again because I added a
vertical strap I thought that would look
a little bit better as well to keep them
in place
now we're gonna create a fence and as
you can see it doesn't break on light
impacts like the red car or the little
racecar did but when the police car
comes and those are 90 then it will last
up there it doesn't have to be the
police car but then the fences break
anyway so what I ended up doing is I
created a simple fence so you have to
make sure that the geometry sticks down
a little bit on the ground then I made
it 2 meters long so it'll be nice to
snap it or nice and easy to snap it in
place in unity because if you're all the
control to keen unity you can also snap
in there this is how I made it basically
I just had a starter from a cube and
then I extruded it I made a bunch of
blue cuts and I in such a few of their
faces and then I extruded the inset hold
the control key to snap it into place
I actually adjusted it to make sure that
it was exactly 2 meters the reason why I
created a separate fence post as well is
because when you duplicate objects in
unity in particular you shouldn't have a
lot of additional geometry so if you add
two thousand all they'll be duplicating
all the fence posts so what ended up
doing here is I just created a separate
post so I can do that
endings quite nice now we're gonna
create a police station and it's only
gonna be used for decoration but that's
for now I'm probably gonna use use it so
the police car will come out of it later
on as well and chase you I don't know
why it would be a police car and buy a
racetrack maybe he's here eating Donuts
having a good time and then racecars go
past he's gotta have some of the case
I'll just fast forward this this uses
all the normal techniques that I use in
my 10 minute modeling challenges and
also in my tutorials my if you want to
check out the 20 tips for blender low
poly modeling for example check out the
link in the description below and you
can see the techniques it's a lot of e
to extrude as to scale if you know me by
now and also inserts a very common thing
that I use and control are for a bunch
of loot cuts and also use the UV
coloring technique that I've used for
the cars to give the police stations and
color
now we're gonna create some trees and I
start from a primitive cube again and I
colorize it brown and then it's a again
a matter of extruding it and hitting our
to rotate it when you hit our you can
press the axis that you want to rotate
there rounds of the Zed axis for example
then it'll force a rotation around the z
axis I'll fast forward this it uses the
exact same techniques as I always do
when I model so it's probably gonna bore
you if I do this in real time in another
game that I made before that I never
finished but you can animate these trees
quite nicely so I'll probably add that
later on in a shader as well so that
that would be shader driven inside of
unity and you can actually have the
graphics card animate the trees without
any performance impact whatsoever it's
really good
so I'll be able to show that I've got a
video in my history if you can be
bothered to look back long enough in my
history you can see that already but
I'll probably make a new one for that I
use a lot of the proportional editing
when I model trees and stones and things
like that so that's all on the keyboard
and you make use of that it's really
handy to shift the shape of the tree
all right then I separate the trees and
make them into individual objects I just
select all the vertices and I hit P to
separate the selection into an object I
always like to export them as separate
objects by the time they end up inside
of unity it's nice to have them
separated and set to the center of the
scene don't be afraid if the scene looks
a bit messy I've got loads of geometry
and trees you can always hide them
select the object select the geometry
and press H to hide it so set the tree
origin as well to the pivot point it's
really important that it's at the base
of the tree but to have some geometry
that sticks down on the ground as well
just a little tiny bit it makes it super
easy to place them inside of unity
because when you drag the trees out into
the scene they'll automatically use the
pivot point towards the center point of
the tree to place itself if you place it
as a prefab it's really good inside of
unity to have it like that then make
sure you name the objects properly as
well the name that you give them in here
in blender is what they'll end up having
inside of unity when you import them the
mesh name will be so trying to keep a
good naming standard there you can move
their objects as I mentioned into Oracle
or is zero zero zero if you select an
object and hit alt G that does that
automatically for you it resets the
transform and it's a really quick way to
move objects from wherever they are in
the blender scene to the center of the
scene which is really nice when you
export them as I mentioned it's nice to
have them in zero zero zero XYZ I have
some problems with a car so I had to fix
them I had some inverted faces so if
you've downloaded those you'll probably
notice that if you have back face
culling this enabled and I had to fix
that for the game because unity doesn't
render with the back faces of objects
unless you tell it to and I don't really
like to have
some of the faces inverted so I have to
fix that by and I enable all the cars in
the scene because you can do that for
all of them at the same time and then I
select all the car objects in the scene
and then I press tab to go into edit
mode for all of them at the same time
and now I can hit L on the keyboard to
select the link faces and it was a bit
tedious here because I had to hover the
mouse over each element that was
inverted so all the door handles all the
rearview mirrors all the windscreen not
the windscreen but the bumpers and
things so I had to do that for all the
cars and hit L and select all of them
and when you've done that hit f3 on the
keyboard and type in flip normals and
when you apply that one it will flip all
the faces so the back faces are no
longer facing outwards they'll be facing
inwards like this should be so now the
cars are fixed I should mention that the
pickup had some problems with the wheel
arches but it was quite a long fix so I
had to cut that out for this video then
it's time to detach the wheels they have
to be separate objects when you're
bringing it into unity because the car
chassis is gonna be one thing and then
the wheels have to be separate so I
basically zoom into one of the cars and
then I hit L again when I hover over the
wheel and I select the link to vertices
and then I had shift D to to touch the
selection into a separate object I
rename it to wheel because that's the
name it'll have in the unity later on
and then I take away the mirror modifier
we only need one wheel and I wanted to
tidy up the geometry because I wanted to
be able to see through the wheel so in
the quick build I only kept the full
face inside so I do some editing here by
inserting the inner inner side and
extruding inwards using the normal
techniques that I always do for my
editing so there's no probably no
different things here really - compared
to what I normally do right you can hit
F to create a face so when you've
selected a bunch of edges then if you
had the F key it'll fill that gap and
create a face for you alright if you
have to alt and left Mouse it'll ring
select a bunch of edges and then I hit
again to fill that as well or fill that
gap
alright I'll just fast forward again
it's the same type of editing so you're
probably fed up with that now but I
colorized it so it looked a bit like a
rim inside and then I just made sure it
connected on both ends hold the control
key to stop those viruses into place and
and merge them together that's it the
wheel is done and now I had to delete
the wheel so for all the cars they don't
need any wheels on them when I export
them so I make sure I do it for all the
cars so I'll fast forward this again as
well and just hit L on the keyboard over
all the wheels and then delete the
vertices and now it's time to create the
unity project finally and we will spend
a little time here we have to do export
a few more objects in blender as well
but finally I'm just creating a new in
unity 2019 whatever version so I do a 3d
project and I just name it appropriately
I decided to call it low poly racer and
then I just create a blank unity project
from that alright when you're inside
unity rename the sample scene it's nice
to not have it named sample scene so I
rename it to game
[Music]
I have to switch back into blender
because we're going to export the FBX
file sorry it's just a little bit more
blender first so I'll either show all
the cars at once
I just unhide them by clicking the eye
icon and I export all of the cars into
one single FBX file you could have them
multiple but just thought it was simple
enough to export them all into one file
they all have to be centered so I had to
reposition the center point and I do
that by just going into the object
selecting all the vertices and sliding
it into place or the center point of the
object is in the center of the car it
can be at the base of the car that's
fine but it has to be center so it
pivots around its own center point that
would be save you a lot of hassle inside
of unity later on in object mode select
all the cars and now it's time to export
them so go up to file and do export and
select FBX files here are some really
important settings you have to first of
all if you've selected the objects you
need to take select selected objects we
don't want to export everything that's
in this scene so that's really important
if you have multiple scenes and lights
and things like that
another one is apply scalings set that
to FBX unit scale and because that will
make one meter in blender will be one
meter in unity so it's really handy that
the scales are the same and the last
thing we need to do is take this
experimental apply transform again
because then the rotation will be
correct in unity otherwise the objects
they look like they're correct but
they're actually flipped 90 degrees
around the x-axis unless you do that so
because they use different up and down
axis navigate to a folder I actually
like to save it straight into the assets
folder because then unity will
automatically import it for you so I
create a new folder there that I like to
call meshes to keep it tidy
so bone is as well if you want to make
changes to a mesh you can just save over
the old FBX file and it'll automatically
import it but be careful if you have
animations in there because then you
have to redo some of the workflows
hit the export file and now you've got
your cars exporting them I'm gonna hide
the cars and show the wheel instead
because it's time to export the wheel as
well I mean need that in unity as well
make sure the pivot point is in the
center of the wheel you don't want to
have a wheel that that rotates around
it's some other weird axis so first I
moved it manually and for some reason I
forgot to that just hit f3 type set
origin and then do you can have a really
nice way to do what I did before
actually with some of the objects it's
the origin to center of mass
then it's time to export the wheel same
settings as before really important to
keep those and then I forgot to change
the name here so I overrode the course
but that's no panic I do that all the
time just have to redo it but I'll spare
you the time and now the cars are
already in unity because we saved them
in the asset folder so that's really
handy so if you expand the meshes folder
now you'll see that there's a new object
called cars and all the car meshes as
you can see are in the same FBX file
here I like to go into material and
disable import materials and apply
because we want to create our own
material instead so I create a new
folder then I call it textures and then
I dragged the texture in that we used in
blender into this texture folder and
after that I create a new folder again
and I named it materials I like to keep
it tightly like that and then I create a
new material there and I call it common
because most objects actually will be
using this one since I often use the
same palette drag the texture that we've
brought in before to the albedo slot and
notice now that the texture looks really
blurry that's no good
we don't we can't have it like that so
we need to change a few settings so
click on the texture and then you have
to change this compression you set it to
none otherwise it'll be wrong colors and
also the filter mode you have to change
the point otherwise because it will be
very wrong and then you have to apply
the changes as well now when you look
here the texture looks a lot better just
like we used it and then I reduce the
smoothness slider so I like to keep
their reflections a bit lower and now
we're gonna drag the cars object into
the hierarchy and then I expand it and
select all the cars and then I drag the
common material onto the elements 0 of
the materials and that'll give all the
cars the proper colors and then I do
unpack prefabs completely if you right
click on it and then I drag all the
objects into the route scene and I
delete the original cars folder now
we're all set actually for episode
number 3 this is gonna be the end of
this one a lot of their blender stuff
and the housekeeping and doing the
exports and things like that but don't
worry next week we will be doing a lot
of
stuff in unity we're gonna actually get
these car we're gonna get the wheels
mounted we're gonna got the wheel
colliders have touched we're gonna have
them drive spin the wheels we're gonna
have them steer check out these clips
guys we filmed these in 2005 on a lake
not too far away from here
we bought a bunch of old Volvo's Volvo
240 my friend add I had a Volvo 360 we
bought some old rally tires with spikes
about that long got the mounted drove
over to the lake and we paid a guy there
who plowed the track on the lake with a
little plow just like that now any
protective gear or anything I thought I
was just stupid but the water started to
leak up in some of the corners and all
we did was like we paid the guy a little
few more extra Swedish kronor to plow a
new track for us so we didn't have to
wait to get the cars wet those alright
enough about that it was a fun time
anyway hope like this video and if you
did don't forget to hit the subscribe
and press a like if you do guys wrong
that'd be nice help me out a little bit
with some extra visitors and let's trick
that YouTube algorithm and make it blow
up again like just like the last one I
don't know what happened to that one
maybe it was the thumbnail or something
whatever it was it worked quite good so
excited about that
lot of excitement here alright here's
the train as well nice one
[Music]