hello everyone and welcome to episode
131 of the 10-minute Ming challenge
today I'm going to be doing a low poly
face and I've been doing low poly
characters for a long time usually I
just kind of keep a simple head and two
dots for eyes and I really wanted to try
to add a few like a little bit more
definition to my low poly phases now and
I don't feel like I've gotten close
enough to where I want to be yet so
maybe today could be a practice run and
then see if I can improve on this front
I'm I'm really looking for a specific
style hard to Define but I think once I
find it I'll be happy with it but today
I might not get there but we'll have a
good laugh trying at least I'm also
going to throw some shape Keys woo in
there as well cuz I want to have the
character to be able to Blink and then
just a very basic speak animation I'm
probably just going to do like a one
like a mouth movement and we'll see how
we go from there so let's get started
straight away I'm just going to model a
low poly head and we'll see how it goes
Ready Steady go and off yes all right so
T into edit mode eight select everything
first I'm going to go to edit and do
auto mirror now tab into edit mode a
select everything scale it down move it
up and go to here and then move it in as
well and on the left side I'm going to
do a select everything and then just
move my UVS down here to some sort of a
skin tone maybe like this would be all
right or maybe over here there we go all
right so I think I'm going to do control
one here to do a subdivision modifier to
get started and I'm going to apply this
one on the right here so contrl a on the
the subdivision eight select everything
and then just scale it maybe like this
and this is probably looking similar to
how I've done in the past but let's see
if we can get it going I'm going to move
this these edges down maybe like this to
here and uh here let's do a controlr
subdivide and move these up and for
let's I think I need to move these in
all side I don't want to see through
anymore alt shift click on that edge and
then move it into here and then I'm
still going to move this one in I think
that's a good like shape and control R
move this one and then move this one
into here so still a bit similar to
maybe what I've done in the past but I
think once I find what I'm looking for
I'll be happy I don't know exactly what
it is yet but I'm know that I'm not
happy when I search for references
online I still don't really feel that
I'm getting happy with the any anything
that anyone else has created either so
I'm just going to keep trying and see if
I can find like a face that I like on
this one I usually never noses but I'm
going to do a nose now so I'm going to
go control R cuz I need a little bit
more like lines here anyway and here
I'll just grab these and E to extrude
and here is going to be our hideous nose
it looks horrible at the moment I know
bear with me GG and GG to slide this one
down G to slide I think I'm going to
have to go into overtime again today cuz
in 10 minutes I'm not going to be happy
with the result so we'll see if I can
just edit my way out of it whatever it
is proportional o on the hot key there
so I'm going to select all of these and
G to move that on and there's our face
this is looking a little bit wonky so
maybe okay oh cuz I want to do
proportional off now and then we're
going to get the nose in G and how am I
doing 744 so uh not the airplane that'
be too big I think G to move that one
down and I'm going to do like a an old
man with a beard white hair and stuff
and I think I need U some sort of a
here's uh where I think I want to do it
a little bit different uh I want to do
like a shape like this to get and then
I'm going to do eyes here and it's too
wide too round so Al said this is what
is driving me nuts a little bit scale x
g to move that in scale X cuz I'm going
to try okay big forehead so not saying
anything not saying anything uh there we
go all set to see through again and G
and here I'm going to do a mouth now so
control R I'll actually I'm do you know
what I'm going to do I'm going to cut it
so K knife to and then I'm going to
create a mouth like this just as simple
cuz I'm going to be able to shape this
one later on and I've broken the
topology now so I'm just going to fix
the topology so instead of doing that I
actually have to do this k for knife
tool if as long as I do like this I can
introduce a quad topology again cuz this
one I might want to subdivide in the
future so J to connect that on and J to
connect that and I think I'm going to go
control R and I'm still on a quad
topology here this is looking very but
it's okay I'm I'm okay with it uh g g
cuz I'm going to put some beard here to
cover this stuff we'll see how it goes
and G move there and usually I do like I
don't do enough definition on my faces I
think that's why they tend to look a
little bit I don't know cartoony and
boring so now I'm going to start by
first of all I'm going to okay this is
might have an issue here with the think
I'm going to do control R here as well
so I can get a little bit more shape
there GG and gg gg gg and GG slide it
like if you do double G there and like
this I'll do all right that's going to
do how am I doing 550 on the clock so
now I'm going to probably just put uh
I'm going to colorize a little bit to
get um some like darker that's I
probably don't colorize it enough I'm
going to actually going to shift the Hue
as well all the way to over here and on
the lips here I'm just going to do like
a really dark color there as well this
looks stupid so the mouth is going to be
smaller I've this just decided a lot
smaller cuz it just want a little like
okay this is still too big so I want to
do shift select these
G G and you're not going to see too much
in the mouth cuz I'm going to be putting
a beard here so we might have to do the
fail check today cuz I'm not quite sure
I'll be able to finish this on time we
shall find out we shall find out for
sure G to move that on and I think I'm
going to do uh let's just do like this
I'm going to put eyebrows so and start
to do do with the hairs cuz I need to
I'm running out of time scale y z and
scale Z move it down G to move it in and
e to extrude it now I'm going to put low
poly eyebrows cuz I'm going to just
animate these later on so I'm just going
to put them to be like white as well cuz
this going to be like bit old cuz I need
like um a wise man or something in like
I can just see it need needs have a lot
of white so old yeah whatever Shifty to
duplicate this one and I'm going to do
like eyes here and I'm already hating
what I'm seeing but it's okay uh it's
okay I think I've had that tip in the
past that you it's okay for things to
look super bad as long you can always
delete it at some point famous words
scale uh Zed G just going to do some
carony style eyes eyes here so G to move
the in El select the link g z just go
for a dark gray there and then scale
these down rotate G now I'm just going
to start refining a bit and hopefully
this will come to some sort of a it'll
make sense in the end don't don't uh say
anything in the chat if you're watching
the premiere I know this is looking very
bad at the moment it definitely needs uh
some hair now and I don't know if I can
rescue this thing I think I've already
uh I see the fail chick already starting
to come out but we'll see I think I also
want to bring these in it's I think this
is the thing with when it comes to
phases I don't have any reference to go
now so I'm going to I think I'm going to
just keep tweaking I think the ver until
I I feel like something is making sense
and I think that's going to be all right
for now rotate G and then now I'm going
to put hair on it cuz I hate what I'm
seeing right now this is so bad actually
this is probably the worst head I've
ever done uh but it's okay it's okay and
I'm going to do ears here as well so gg
gg and then GG and here I'm just going
to I guess I'm just going to inser this
uh scale Zed G I think the had I did
last time was better this is why I need
the practice you see so I to inset scale
y okay o proportional off scale Y and
then uh I'm just going to let's let's
see uh will I be able to salvage this
I'm actually getting nervous now as well
cuz this might you see I feel like
imposter syndromes every now and then
and this is the reason why like I don't
deserve to have a reputation of being a
low poly model and this is what I'm
creating so all said say let's see if I
can bring this in a little bit G all
right and now I'm going to have to put
the hair on cuz I need to get oh two two
minutes to go okay all said so I'm just
going to do like I'll just grab the top
faces here Shifty to duplicate this SK
like scale it like that e to extrude it
and then uh we'll just do I don't know
uh shift select these I just need to
cover the mouth cuz it's so hideous that
I really need to cover it before the
time rounds out and that if if I manage
to do that I'll be
happy uh and then I'll just do scale and
E to
extrude okay I missed the face here I
missed like the whole face G scale scale
Zed G all right I need
to I feel uh Panic set me you
know all right I need a beard I need a
beard I need a beard this to like to fix
this thing shift e to duplicate that on
E to extrude all right I've got one
minute to like just cover this mess up L
to select the link R to rotate G to move
and E to extrude R to rotate e to
extrude R to rotate and then I'm just
going to e to extrude this one down and
then I'm going to e to extrude this one
in and E to extrude again and then here
I'm just I'm going to have to definitely
tweak a lot of stuff here but it's all
right e to extrude rotate Zed g e to
extrude
rotate oh whoa whoa who whoa whoa what's
going on here it's got some serious
issues and then here I'll should I link
these together and rotate 47 second okay
let's just color this white anyway
that's a step in the right direction
there we go and then I need to do
something with our here so I'm going to
g e g whatever what what am I doing here
g g e to extrude this one rotate let's
link this down or something something so
I can
like that's not good at all let's do
control R I think I need to just do the
hair needs to poke through a little bit
like that and then here ah okay I've got
some sort of a slit here 12 seconds to
go e to extrude G to move G to move e to
extrude G to move rotate oh rotate and G
to move okay I I link them together by
mistake ah let's just pretend that's not
going off and H you TTR it
ah it's not over I
refuse it's rigged it's rigged it's
rigged it's rigged I need to switch this
thing off that's why I made it so
loud uh it's like right on the buzzer
isn't
it there we go
just just made
it okay
I think I went 33 seconds over there but
now we need to rescue this poor thing so
I'm going to press contr s to save this
and then now let's just see how we can
salvage this thing so apologies for this
hideous character maybe from a super
long distance this would still work so
but now let's see I'm actually going to
duplicate this one and then let's work
on this one
first 10 min I call this one and then
here I'm going to work on this one now
okay so let's just analyze this thing in
10 minutes like what went seriously
wrong first of all I need to colorize
this cuz I think uh what I usually do is
I kept keep the same color mostly and I
just shade like on the neck or something
what I'm going to do now is I'm going to
move these to make it quite radically
different the colors here and also I
think up here in the forehead I think
the hair needs to come up a little bit
so El select the link okay have I got
two I've got two heads of hair or
something all right delete don't know
why I had two sets of hair oh did
I no there we go El select link so that
was one issue there I double sets of
hair for some stupid reason uh so I'm
not happy with the air here so I'm going
to press control plus press delete faces
and then I'll have to salvage this so L
select the link here H to hide it this
could be oh I've got everything's
duplicate why okay I must have pressed
shift d by mistake so delete these ones
as well then I guess this is duplicate l
select the link yep all right delete
those as well are the eyes duplicate l g
y all right let's get rid of them too
eyebrows I'm guessing L select the link
G yeah they're duplicate everything's
duplicate all right and then here now I
can slash on the keyboard actually
pretty good if you high like this El
select the link and then press slash
okay that didn't work when I'm zoomed in
so I'll just press control I and H to
hide it then and I've got to link the
hair up here again now cuz I I wasn't
happy with what I was doing so I'm going
to shift select these edges press F to
to fill them F to fill F to fill and F
to okay there we got an issue as
well so I could not do that apparently
so let's link these instead them to F to
select the
link F to select the link oh this is the
quad I want it there we go and here I
think I'll do control R and I'll have to
check the poly count later on but here
I'm going to do G to move and E to
extrude part to rotate and I think
that's better cuz now I I've got a space
for my ear here so alt h on hides this
face thing all right so what's like
there's a billion things that I don't
like with this face but let's start
fixing them one by one uh this I want to
change color so I'm going to change them
one to like some darker even on a
different Hue as well I want to have
like really like Stark contrasts Tony
Stark good film the first Iron Man was
really good actually didn't really like
the well the other ones are good too but
the first one was great so it's
difficult to compete with that one so G
okay maybe the front here needs to come
down maybe this needs to come up so
again I'm not using a reference for this
I'm just trying to like look at the
thing and see like what am I unhappy
with and then let's just try to fix one
thing at a time so I'm going to go this
feels like it needs to come in a little
bit
G and then here like leave some space
for there I think the ear is not high
enough so shift select those and G to
move that and then G this one sometimes
I I keep the eyes ear
did I say ear before or I I don't know
anyway I want to keep the ear part of
the head now cuz usually I do like I do
them separate but for some reason I want
to keep that as part of the mesh now all
right let's see what's uh this mouth
thing is looking terrible so let's see
what we can do here maybe I think the
whole mouth needs to come up a little
bit cuz what is this what is this
thing so it's a good thing I can like
fix a few of these things now because
the thumbnails like if I had it looking
like this I'd lose subscribers straight
away so
G all said g and then GG to slide these
down GG to slide I can have pretty small
I I really want to try to keep the poly
count pretty low and then G G and I
think I want to color this okay this
should probably go in La still G
rotate there we go g and ALT H to on
hiide and then see what do we do here I
need to link the beard and the here the
hair
up so let's see I wonder how much extra
time we're going to end up getting on
this video now it's my own fault um I
need to get faster or better or
something but that's what this is all
about I need to PR what what is this uh
hair do that he got going obviously he
got more hair than I do hair do I do um
but yeah this is the whole point of
these exercises anyway I need to
practice these things if you don't
practice you're never going to get
better so and there's clearly room for
improvement
here uh we can see that I can see
clearly
now and well I cannot actually cuz I
need glasses but it's uh sometimes it's
better to not see that well I guess if
if you're unhappy with what things look
like so maybe e to extrude this one to
or why am I like extruding it into the
center am I off on my scales or
something G to move that why is he like
there we go so again I'm not happy with
the fact that it goes like a bobble or
whatever you call this thing so I'm
going to G to move this G okay I could
go proportional now probably and I have
linked proportional off so I'm not
affecting the head underneath there so
there we go there we go and because I
need like NPCs for ultranova I need them
and I need like a few human quite a few
humans and I don't want to go overboard
with poly but I don't want to go
underboard either overboard underboard
so I I need to practice these
things so here we go that's a bit better
and I think I I actually want to just
link this hair all the way into let's
extrude it again so G and E to extrude
this one cuz I want I think I want to
link these up like this maybe I'll even
actually to the point where I'm going to
bridge these I think that's what I'm
going to do I'm going to shift select
that one shift select that on right
click and the bridge faces that connects
them like this so that's pretty good and
then control R cuz I think I still want
to have a little indentation here okay o
for proportional off and S to scale it
and G G there we go okay I still need to
I think I need to bring this up to here
and out a bit and now I think I want to
okay so that beard all Z to see through
and then G to slide this back G to slide
that back and I'm going to get so many
comments now in the review saying like
this is a false statement you said that
you did this in 10 minutes and clearly
you sat there for ages afterwards you're
a
liar but it's okay I can take it it's uh
I still model something in 10 minutes
it's just that it required some
salvaging anyway I think I'm going to
change this as well now and I'm going to
go for a different Hue here there we go
I don't know it doesn't make much sense
now but I think it might do in a second
so here I'm going to move this
up and I'm going to put some virtual
Shadow on this stuff now I think I'm
going to also bring this part of the
beard
in and
G and I'm going to also extrude the must
mustache one more time maybe control
okay I'm I'm putting too many polygons
on actually so e to extrude that on
scale it G and then let's go I'm not
going to put any more polygons here now
cuz I'm already feeling like I'm going a
bit too too much here but it's okay
there we go and the nose is uh okay I'm
going to bring this in L select the link
here the eyes are too far out so I'm
going to rotate
them and a bit cartoony these eyes I
understand so but I'm okay with that so
G and okay so what what's still wrong
here I'm going to do bring that on down
slightly this in and okay so maybe like
that and I'm also going to change I
think the color okay here needs to go
darker it really needs to go dark in
here I think
like to that point am I missing a face
yeah and with that done I think the lips
will even have to go darker
too and then I'll bring this up to there
and
then I'm not happy with uh that either
so G to move that
on G G I should have known like how to
do this now because I did the the beard
I guess for the other character that I
made the the big boss that I did for my
game so G and all right I think okay
here's what I'm going to do now so I
have to probably switch off uh mirror
modifier at some point as well because I
need and usually I always forget that I
do that but the reason why I think I
need to do it is because I need to have
some
irregularities going to shift select a
bunch of these and then go darker here
as well maybe under the ears there as
well and I'm Shifting the Hue as well
from a yellow or skin tone there to like
a redder color as if it was going darker
there all right so and then maybe I'm
going to even put like a different color
on
here R there you go and now for the hair
I'm actually going to throw different
like shades of light like really light
blue as well so on those I'm going to go
on the left here Beats Box select those
G and move them down to maybe
here there we go okay that's too dark G
and
then a few of these as well I think I'm
going to do a few of those this is again
like it it's like a cool shadow on them
and I don't mean cool as in looking cool
I just need them to have like a
different color to to create contrast I
think that's what my some of my stuff
has been missing before in here I can
probably go quite a lot darker but I'm
not going to go gray dark I really want
to try to bring those Blues in so I get
so it looks a bit like it's got like
some tint on it so G to move all the way
down to there I might do oh press two
sometimes I scare myself when I do that
quite often uh but when you press two
sometimes when you're not in edit mode
then what you're doing is basically
hiding the collection so and I mistake
that sometimes for like accidentally
deleting something G all right so there
we go and here we can put some fake like
Blues here as well maybe I'll go in like
super dark like that and this is looking
super weird this one G oh what's
happened here
I've selected way too many here so
control control select to here here here
here here here hair hair G I'm just
going to go for that lighter and then
here I need to change as well how many
Poes am I on now actually I have to
check G and G and what's going on with
the hair here here oh my
God so I think I'm bring that on into
G what what am I doing
G there you go and the reason why I
think I need to like apply I need to
triangulate some parts as well because I
cannot get the colorization i i Envision
a little bit more like irregular
coloring rather than these like clear
squares so I think I want to Triangle it
at some
point um under the eyebrows I think I'm
going to go dark as well there and maybe
that that triangle could qualify to be
darker do you think
and some more saturation in there
maybe could be G to move that one in and
G okay now I'm going to just keep
refining so this is like an old guy I
think the problem is still that it's oh
yeah like it's starting to look a little
bit maybe I need
to Al I I'll save this one for like mod
one and then I just duplicate this one
and save that on too so I'm going to put
on my patreon as well so if anyone wants
to like download these so my tutorial
here on my patreon thank you so much
patreons you guys are absolutely
fantastic um I'm trying to do this for a
living it's not the easiest
thing so I'll hide that one uh but so my
I'm super grateful for your support So
patreon's tutorial tiering up I guess
it's about time that I start uploading a
few more of these I've uploaded uh and I
usually do it in batches so I don't have
to do it like after every week but I
will uh probably look into uploading
another batch soon cuz I think it's been
like quite a few so you'll be able to
download these soon all right I need to
bring this up I think rotate on the
x-axis scale down and okay I'm T I'm I'm
doing like tinkering
now H oh I'm just trying to save
something out of this G
G all right
so should I bring this one
up to here
even maybe and the hair is looking I'm
not happy at all with the hair so I'm
not I'm not sure why maybe it's too
thick too much hair so I'm going to go
proportional on this thing shift select
the bunch and G to move it in I think
it's too much hair I'm jealous that's
what I'm trying to say G to move this
in shift select shift select shift
select shift select G G and G all right
I'm still not happy with this so maybe
if I bring let's see like do I bring
that down well that created a little bit
of definition on it it's like he's got
something G wrot it now it looks like
he's popping out of an eggshell for some
reason I'm okay with that still g g okay
so not happy with this
this is too close not happy with this
G not happy with that g
g g hey I'm I'm imagining like a wizard
or something here as well there's
something that's really disturbing me
with the face and I cannot like exactly
like put my finger on what it is it's
well apart from it looking super strange
so maybe El select the link hide this
and then see well now we see what's
going on here this is a problem so he's
not meant to look happy so that's
okay but I think I'm going to create
even more def definition on his face
here we'll colorize these a different
color there and then this one as well
maybe slightly darker and I really want
to get like a nearly like a fake low
poly look like I drew it or
something and but I think that's okay
and
this I guess I should really extrude the
neck e extrude that's the scale
and arer rotate but I'm not going to do
any longer than that that's as far as
I'll go and we're not going to see this
part of the head so I'm not going to
worry about the colorization in there so
this is okay now I'm going to I might
just bring the mouth out slightly
G rotate and this is only for
colorization that's why I've got the mou
there like that or the mouth should go
in
maybe maybe this needs to come out I'll
select the ring Loop there and bring
this in no matter what I do uh it's
apparently looking not good so let's put
the hair back alt H there we go that
saved it
and we've got maybe this is coming out
to more much yeah that's better we need
to reveal the air ear I think a little
bit more there we go old said to see oh
it's starting to difficult now I have to
check the poly count
now uh g s that on and
one I have no no idea how much extra
time I put this control r g okay that's
a bit better as well I'm just trying to
create like definition in the face
that's what I'm after so it's not like
super like
Bland maybe this needs to come in
rotate yeah that's good G well I I
wouldn't say it's good but
it's somewhere something all right G
here we go all right so let's just try
to do some radical like changes here so
if I change that vert is that better or
worse that's pretty interesting like I'm
bringing the eyebrow that's could be
interesting okay let's try this vert
single verts here in the face will
actually make a big difference so you
can really change the like the look of a
face here if he wants to be like s like
a a boner
face more narrow bigger cheekbones there
we go and then probably the nose I'm
guessing you can like that'll change the
face quite a bit but I'm okay that one I
think maybe let's try that ver and see G
you can do like a narrower nose like
that or a wider I think that's all right
and I'm guessing this beard is um or
this mustache maybe that's what it is
that's too too
big G to move that and I'm going to
change these as well color-wise
G again I'm going to shift into like a
darker it's still light but like a
darker color at least and let's do these
as well
G that can go darker there we go and O
there we go I pressed number two
again G and okay this vert is probably
going to be a problem alt Z to see
through that one I need to move down I
think cuz when I do my shape key soon
going to have and then that creates a
problem for the
ear so let's bring that down to
[Music]
there there and there there there
here all ti so okay that one can go
darker too I'm not going to be too
afraid of like putting you see like
these blue shap like like the blue
colors now I think that actually helps
it just look a little bit more
interesting it's not natur like it's not
real light that's falling on it but it's
creates the illusion maybe of light so
maybe like that here we can also go to
like that
color and here let's go a little bit
darker there I think that's all right
all right and the hair obviously I think
it's because it's like perfectly
symmetrical I think that's one of the
issues so ideally you should probably
have let's go proportional G move this
one in a bit
more there we go and maybe when
[Music]
I when I apply the mirror modifier we
can throw some different shapes on
there all right so there we go
oh G OG
OG all right I'm going to have to call
it quits there I guess maybe dark behind
the ear asn't washed
there but that's all
right okay so at least I'm happier with
this pH anyway I can imagine in a game
and now let's let's put uh all right
what should I do first I'm going to do
so mod two we'll call this one there we
go and then I'm going to shift duplicate
this one and see El select link have I
got duplicate geometry here again no
that looks
hideous I don't know if uh these need
changing too it's like a cartoon style
eye think you can change the appearance
quite a lot of the character like if the
eyes are narrow or far apart or
bigger okay don't know and I might also
like think of a character where I don't
have like these little eyes but I think
that will work for what I need and G to
move on all right that should work maybe
slightly darker under the
nose
there
and here I think I'm going to go even
darker on the blue there nearly to a
black all right and
two G and these should probably also be
blue too dark there we go
okay maybe someone can put in the
comments like why is the hair looking so
bad there's something about the hair
either it's too big or it's just that
it's too uniform so now I'm going to
regret applying the mirror modifier
because then but I think I need to do it
just so I can get some different uh
shapes on the hair otherwise the hair
will be perfectly symmetrical like this
so I'm going to regret this in a minute
but I'm going to do apply mirror
modifier here so going to do contr a on
it and now I'm already going to start
regretting this but I just wanted to see
if we can get a little bit different
like shape the hair so I can imagine
maybe here this one e to extrude as the
scale Control Plus G okay oh we need
proportional
G rotate G I have no idea if this is
actually what the problem is but it
feels like it is and I might triangular
just triangulate just the
hair I think that's what put me off that
the hair is a bunch of
quads and g g g and maybe it just needs
layering or something there
here I have no idea but let's do L
select the link here and then contrl T
to try angulate
that and put some okay maybe I'll just
randomly select a few few vers here so
I'm going to shift select a bunch of
random ones like this I know you can do
select random as well but I think I just
want it a little bit controlled alt s
now to
scale on
the with proportional
without I'm not sure what I'm trying to
do here so
G
and G
maybe I need to color the different
triangles a little bit as well maybe
that's what it is oh he needs like the
hair to the side like this maybe or
something and then I'll bring actually
this down and maybe he needs a little
like a little part here maybe that's
what it is so this is I I've never
really done hair like this before so
that's why I'm like a bit
lost to say the least uh rotate G I
think I just need it to be like bit
different anyway and then like usually
it swirls here doesn't it for the people
that do have quite a lot of hair still
you probably know if they it swirls here
so we'll do
that g g g and here I can probably go a
little bit crazier as well
g go crazy I moved it like moved it like
half a
centimeter G all right and then if I try
to there's something here okay this
maybe it needs come out a little bit
more sorry for occupying your time now
while I'm like just trying to figure out
like what what is going on here with
this rotate g g rotate what am I doing
okay so that's the hair there now I'm
just going to randomly select a few like
triangles maybe these especially where
it's like on the
part select a few of them and then just
go to like the Bluer color there as well
there we go so creates like a fake
Shadow maybe these will go in even
darker a little bit not going to be
afraid of putting them quite super dark
like that cuz it just looks like it's a
bit more
shade and here maybe we'll do so I'm
going to actually remove the shade from
these cuz it feels like they would like
get a little bit lighter even or maybe
we can keep a light blue on
there it just okay maybe this will help
yes there we go little bit of hair
hanging
down and some random here as well there
there there there there I I don't know
if this works but what do you guys think
like does it help with that those colors
and I think this needs to come in oh
select the link
G this keeps reminding me of like that I
heard a story when I was a kid my mom
told me it was uh like someone made soup
from just a a rusty nail and the point I
I don't know it's probably got a famous
name or something and it's probably a
famous story but it's something about
you can C cook a bowl of soup on just a
rusty nail and nothing else bowl of
water and and soup and then it just said
yeah but you know what it'd be slightly
nicer if you just added a bit of stock
to it and then he said yeah but it's if
you just add a little bit of vegge it'll
become a little bit better so and then
it keeps adding and adding more and more
things to the soup and and then people
were super impressed by the end cuz they
managed to make a bowl of soup on just
one Rusty Nail but in fact a lot of
stuff was added so I feel a bit like
that I just keep like in 10 minutes I
did this face and then it looked
absolutely ridiculous and then it I just
had to keep adding until I was happy but
I think I'm going to do a few of these
faces I need to like if I make like a
phase like this a week or something I
think in the end it could probably work
out to to looking something decent how
many have we got now so this is I've
applied the mirror modifier now so we're
at 458 vers and I was aiming for between
2 and 300 before I applied the mirror
modifier so I think I'm still like in
the ballpark there and I'm also going to
just try to change the okay here's where
I'm going to actually not like this now
oh that's that could be good
actually so actually like that a bit
more scale that on down in like
that and maybe we'll color eyes it feels
like I've I've said like nine half
finished sentences now so sorry about
that should probably try to think about
what I'm saying a little bit more and
complete my sentences but never
mind and there we go so now I'm going to
just uh I'll save this one again and
then I'll put some shape keys on now cuz
I think I want to be able to animate
this so like when they speak in a game I
want to have just like blinking will do
a huge thing I think plus you can do a
lot of Expressions just with your
eyebrows so like if you do okay now I'm
already annoying I'm not annoying I'm
annoyed well I am annoying as well but
uh now I like I'm raising one ey bro
okay and this is too uniform the
mustache GE since I've got the power now
of not uh being symmetrical but then I
actually want that to be a little bit
more symmetrical anyway let's go to this
one now the vert Tab and am I recording
my screen properly yeah good it's a good
thing to check now I'm going to add the
shape Keys here here so plus there no no
no not there here shape keys and then
I'm going to do plus again and then I'm
going to call blink here and now I'll
tab into edit mode and then I'm going to
now I have to do everything double
actually can I do this I can enable this
one little thing up here the
mirror thing yeah there you go so it's
nearly like having a mirror modifier but
you can actually edit if the verts are
in the same place on both sides and I
haven't done anything to the face that's
asymmetrical so now I can actually use
even without the mirror modifier I can
actually get these things going with the
Symmetry on the x-axis so I'm going to
create a blinking animation now so I'm
just going to like move these down G
this one down and this is going to come
up a little bit to meet and then G to
move this down and I guess I'll have to
move this whole nose section down a
little bit G and the beautiful thing is
I can
actually even like these now El select
link El select the link scale Zed and
then I'm going to move these in just
into the head that's all right and then
maybe I'll just tighten a bit there as
well G G and the eyebrows I guess will
have to come down as well l l and I
slide them down and then I'm just going
to how how would these rotate would they
rotate like this if he
blinks rotate I don't know and then
these verts I think I need to just hide
so El let's see I'll do El select the
link all set to see through scale on the
Z axis cuz I'm just going to scale
oop what am I doing there material
improve scale on the Zed axis and G so
I'm okay with that so now if I Tab out
edit mode the blinking here now will
just be like that ding ding ding ding I
think that'll do quite a lot to the game
cuz if you're just looking at a
character and every now and and then
they just blink I don't know if I should
have pulled the cheekbones up I think
I'm okay with that and then so that's
going to be the blink and then here I'm
going to do also so plus here to add one
more and I'm just going to do some sort
some sort of a speaking thing so we can
speak so
speak and here I'm going to go I'm not
happy with the mouse mouse with a mouth
here it's uh got some gaps and stuff but
never mind I'll fix that some other day
maybe so now I'm just going to do with
the mouth I'm going to go like I still
got symmetry so I'm going to make it
rounder I
think G G G and G G g g because now I
should be able to just make animations
with shape keys in the in the game
engine and then I think also when he
speaks the like the mustache should move
a little
bit and maybe this comes out maybe this
whole thing comes down a
bit rotate
G and how do we do there not too much I
guess I wonder if it should move down
here as well maybe
G G and I don't know let's try it out so
there you go that's not so good I need
to do more movement
here so I think more radical movement is
what's needed so I'll
do bigger change here there there
proportional let's go proportional and
the whole thing now is going to move
like down a bit oh no this this moves up
I guess when
speaks and this goes down a bit and
rotate and then this goes
down to there I don't know this one this
one's a bit
tricky
g g g g or maybe the like the jaw bones
need to change a little bit too
here so when you round the mouth you'd
probably there maybe slightly on the
nose as well I don't know I can imagine
that would be affected if you speak
would it so now we'll try
it yeah I think that'll do so again it's
just to get a little bit of uh movement
so like when a character speaks like
that you can
do maybe I'll do one with a closed as
well and I think what of an issue here
is I'm going to actually modify these
now and I'm going to bring this up a
little bit I think I was uh
a bit unhappy with the the way this
looked
anyway cheat there we
go yeah that'll
do and then blink blink
blink okay that'll
work all right so contrl s on that
that's um a good practice run so I think
it managed to salvage it maybe it's just
because I'm used to looking at it now
but from a distance I think this will be
good enough and tab interet mode we're
still under 500 Birds three 700 triangle
so it's pretty low
poly could probably do with removing
some triangles maybe on the head and
stuff but overall I think it'll work all
right give it let's see I have no idea
how long this took can I look at the
recording 47 minutes I've been recording
nearly I've been recording for a long
time anyway so I'm going to try to
compress it down a little bit for you
guys and have this compiled and uploaded
cuz this is supposed to Premiere in like
uh 4 hours so I've got better just edit
this now and get it uploaded so give it
a thumbs up if you like the video and
don't forget to subscribe if you haven't
already and don't forget to if you're
interested in my game on Fair Rampage
Nightfall that's a mouthful to say but
then you can uh wish list that as well
Link in the description I'm going to
launch that at the end of next month
probably so I need to get my wish list
so I can actually have a like a spoka in
Swedish um a bit of a chance to to
actually make a few sales on that one so
feel free to do that and uh come back
for the next video I've got a Unity
video coming out about that game very
shortly as well so keep your eyes open
for that one and I'll see you next week
for another 10minute balling challenge
as well so that was a lot of words long
outro instead of a long intro in this
week but I'll see you soon again bye for
now
[Music]