[Music]
[Applause]
okay
[Music]
hello guys and welcome to another video
it's really windy and cold today
hopefully it's warmer where you are if
you haven't checked out my video where I
make ten low poly cars in ten minutes
go and check that on up first because
today I'm gonna start putting those
little racing cars or just normal cars
as well I'll put them into a little
racing game this won't be tutorial
detailed all the way through but some
things I'll put a little bit more in
detail and some things I'll just have to
fast forward and explain roughly what
I'm doing so tag along I hope you enjoy
this series let's do this one together
let's have some fun and make some low
poly racing I'm using this scene that I
used before when I created the cars but
I'll just hide most of them and keep one
in for reference and first I made a
little straight road segment so I went
to top you and then I just did shift a
to add a new mesh and I created a just a
simple quad or a paint plane the gold
plain I switched into edge select mode
and I extruded the size of the edge
because I hold the control key as well
because then you can stop the movement
so it's equal on both sides and then I
also hold to move it downwards so it
snaps in place the reason why I do this
is because if you have a road profile
like this with a slanted edges and you
can have the ground profile and
basically just to sink that into the
ground I'm trying to show here I'll just
slide it up in unity so you can see and
then I add a mesh Collider to both of
them and the good thing about this is
that you can keep asphalt physics on the
road and grass physics on the terrain
itself so you have different
characteristics so if you have a wheel
Collider like this it's gonna be really
good because they really like these
smooth transitions so here's a clip from
the game as well where I just in slow
motion roll the car and you can see that
the wheel collided just nicely goes up
over that slanted edge so that's why
I've got it cutting down through the
ground like this another benefit is that
the profile allows that you can have
uneven ground and you can still you
don't see the underneath of the road
then I'm gonna add some road markings so
I use just simple geometry for this you
could use a texture map but I like the
geometry method as you've seen in some
of my videos because you can basically
infinitely
zooom without losing any quality what
why else is it good oh yeah yeah it
doesn't take up any texture space hardly
any at all so that's really good so I
just do an inset here and I did a loop
cut first because then I can delete the
top and the bottom so I have the road
markings nicely ending like this and
then I just slide them up as well to
make a bit of a bigger segment it didn't
really have to be that precise but it
was quite useful to just have a I like
to precise I'm a bit picky so I like
things to be precise believe it or not
press end to get the properties panels
up and you can actually type in the
coordinates for the vertex is there so
that's why I move them up and down so
I've got a really nice square Road
segment here or more or less than square
anyway I've got a video check out the
description below and you can see how I
do this colorization so that should help
you along the way if you need to next
thing I wanted to do was to make a
corner so I extend the existing Road
segments to do that and then if you do
shift and right mouse you can place the
3d cursor and then do shift s to bring
the snap menu up and you can stop the
cursor to the grid and then I use this
spin tool to extrude and spin the road
as you can see here you can just you
know it crushed
protip save files before it's too late
the reason why I crashed is because
apparently you can't run screencast keys
with this tool so I'll after we do it so
I held the ctrl key to get the angles so
I can slide it up to exactly 90 degrees
and you can see that it extrudes and
bends the road segment really nicely
here so the corner is nearly done
already then I have to do a little bit
of tweaking as well because I want to
add some curbs on the sides so on the
inner and outer side I want to have some
curbs and things like that but the road
segment itself is pretty good at this
stage
so now it's time to add the curb as you
can see here we've got a little police
car skidding across the curb love that
shop well slow mo for you there guys
press 2 to get into edge select mode and
then I basically Clifton Clift clicking
left mouse click to select the shortest
path to get all them and just selected
and then I do shifty to duplicate them
again now I do Shift + right mouse click
to place the cursor and I snap it to the
grid this I can get a really precise
coordinate for the scaling because if I
do the pivot point with a period key I
can set that to be the 3d cursor and
then I want to do extrude it really
extrudes it nicely so I get a nice mesh
for the curb to use and then I do a loop
cut with ctrl R and I use the mouse
wheel to just slide up the number of
cuts so I think three should be
sufficient for this one and then I want
to raise them up but I want to do
proportionally so in order to do that
you can enable proportional editing it's
Oh on the hotkey or you can click up
there at the top as you can see use the
mouse wheel to change how much it should
affect and I just put press key and move
it up so you can you can type and I
think I end up typing in the number here
to go together exactly 0.2 I think I
checked and now you have a nice Bend to
this curb segment as well so because I
want it to be a nice bumpy curb so you
can skip across it make sure you have
Auto merge vertices enabled as well
because we're going to be merging some
of the sides now of this mesh so I do be
for box select and then I collect a few
of these vertices and then I just move
them into place and I do this a little
bit even though I like to be picky I
just do that a little bit off what do
you say white chance no yeah and just do
it shooting from the hip that's what I'm
doing
so I'll just move it a little bit it's
not that picky even though I like to be
picky
I like to talk about me as well I just
select these vertices and move them in
to get a little bit of a curb shape then
I do the selection I hold the shift key
to just to select the number of faces
here because again I'm doing the
colorization using just bringing the UV
Islands to a pixel on a really tiny
texture as you can see on the left but
check out that video check out the link
in the description that will help you
along the way hmm
every time I cough I get comments that I
shouldn't so that's not grab the outer
edge again and I want to extrude that
one as well and I do the same method by
setting the 3d cursor and extruding its
you can't really do alt s to extrude
along than normal because I just
apparently don't have normals so you
can't do that so I have to do this
method instead and the reason why I
extended like that is because I also
want to bring that down so it slides
down nicely under the terrain and you
could extend it further if you want to
have even more possibility of a bumpy
terrain fast-forward a little bit
because I do pretty much the same thing
here on the inner curb it's the same
technique to some tweaking adjustment
and then I select the UV islands and
then I do the conversation as well nice
thing is well you can just sweep up
sweep out swap out the texture as well
later on if you wanted to have blue and
white curbs or something like that same
thing here I extrude the inner edge so I
can get the little slump down and then I
clump those down I hold the control key
to just move and add some vertices there
so I can just clamp it down so it's got
exactly the same profile as a road there
so now it should connect nicely when I
do multiple corners later on I should be
able to link those up with a straight
road and also a bunch of corners now
we're going to do some jump love jumping
[Applause]
and you played supercars too
[Music]
so some slow-motion shots there for you
and two I use the road segment the
straight one that I did I do control R
and I do about nine or ten loop cuts
here and then basically I can just
proportionally edit this now to get a
little nicer slant so usually you want
to duplicate your objects as well so you
don't overwrite the road I over wrote my
own segments a few times so I keep
forgetting so make copies save and
duplicate your objects now I enabled
proportional editing again and then I
just used the scroll wheel to scroll it
up so I could get a nice there's no
signs to this but later assigns to this
but I didn't use it so I just shot from
the hip again like a cowboy do they
shoot from there I don't know if they
did but anyway then I selected the
bottom vertices and I pressed scale s to
scale and then just Z is zero so I could
just I got those in a nice straight line
and then I just brought those down to
the one one unit below so I knew that it
will match up nicely with the road
segment then I select the outer edges
here in the in the empty space and then
you just press F to create a face to cap
that end nicely and that's pretty much
it that is done now so the jump it's
ready to go
same for landing whoo now we're gonna
create an overpass they're quite fun too
and they're not as fun as jumps but
they're quite fun so it will enable you
to drive over the road and I think they
had that in supercars two supercars too
- yeah okay so same technique here I
duplicated the road segments or at least
that's what I should have done and then
I do some more loop cuts this time
because it's gotta be slightly longer
I'm gonna do the same technique here I
select a bunch of vertices and then I
click o to do proportional editing first
I forgot it but then I enabled it so I
do the proportional editing and I just
slide it off to a decent salams make
sure you don't do so the very tip of the
road it gets affected because that's or
the end of the road because that needs
to link up nicely to the road segment
that you have
and then I had to do some tweaking as
well you couldn't just have an empty
like basically no faces underneath so I
did some testing here for different
techniques but I ended up going for
something where I just pulled down I
extrude it down the edges vertically
down and then I selected the bottom
edges and I pressed F along I selected
all the edges and I just repeated that
over and over again and created faces
underneath the road because here you're
gonna be able to see some camera shots
in probably not when you play the game
but on replays and things like that
you'll see the underneath so you can't
have a no back faces there maybe there's
a faster way to cut this I didn't use
that a faster way I used this way this
will way but I fast forward it a little
bit in the video for you so that's
pretty good in the end I just linked it
up again and I have to make sure again
that it should link nicely to the road
segment so I have to make sure that that
I didn't affect the very very first set
of vertices there you want to make sure
that those linked oh so I use ctrl key I
switch here to vertex snapping hold the
ctrl key so I can snap those into the
original vertex there you don't have to
create the end faces because all the
roads will be linked up to each other so
that can be left as a gap saves or
massive performance not really look
pretty good anyway alright
some final tweaking there with the
burgesses probably didn't have to do
that but I did it anyway this road
segment is pretty much ready to go now
the car is just there for reference I
could have hit up
oh I have a some margin on the sides as
well because I wanted to put some
railing on it or some fences so that's
why I extrude it a little bit to the
side so I didn't just drop it down
straight next to the road itself all
right now it's time to do something
completely different
we're gonna do this straight finish line
and that's the same technique as before
to colorize but I do a whole bunch of
loop cuts here both vertically and
horizontally into a little checkered
pattern again I'm gonna get loads of
comments now saying that this is way too
much geometry you're wasting performance
you should just use a texture but I'm
not gonna use the texture because that
uses texture space and it doesn't zoom
it's nicely assists us cuz I can zoom in
infinitely there enough anyway and it'll
look perfect no no messing around there
with blurry textures even if you had a
4k texture or something like that
so I'm gonna use this method it's so few
polygons anyway that the performance is
not gonna be a problem and if you're
really concerned you could do a
different one for the collider so it
doesn't have that geometry you could
just use the normal road segment
[Music]
I use all the different segments that
I've created now and I linked them
together I have got Auto merge of
burgesses on which is really important I
do this in the same mesh keep in mind
keep keep in mind and keep in mind I
don't create a bunch of separate message
and meshes
I don't create a bunch of separate
message message I don't create a bunch
of separate meshes because tried that in
unity before and if you have separate
meshes the colliders go a bit funky so
basically if you jump over a jump and
the car hits on the on the down slant
for example and there's a joined Road
segment there it could catch the
collider and it doesn't work is good so
that's why I've decided in this case
anyway to do the entire road as one mesh
in blender and export it there is a fix
if you wanted to really have it modular
and that is that you could keep separate
modules assemble them in unity and then
run a script that merges all the
vertices for the Collider in unity it's
a bit out of the class for this time but
maybe I could do that in a future
version if this game becomes to a point
where I wanted to start to make it a
little bit more modular and maybe a
track editor or something like that I
have to do that so maybe I'll come to
that one day this is quite fun I just
set the inverse and probably not that
fun to watch but it was fun to make so
just use your imagination and I I just
basically select using box selected I
select a bunch of faces and then I
rotate them using the same method before
with I have to make sure that I used the
cursor it's snapping to grid so the
rotation is aligned perfectly and then I
just link a whole bunch of segments
together and I create the track that
you've seen in the intro screen there
if you want to select the part of the
mesh you could either box elect like I'm
doing or sometimes you can press the L
key when you hover over a segment and
I'll select that particular part so you
could use both methods whichever you
feel more comfortable with and then it's
just a matter of I fast forward a little
bit here because I just can't decide
what I'm doing I'm tweaking a little bit
probably too much changing my mind back
and forth and forth and back but in the
end it turns out to be a little nifty
race track so I think if you've checked
also my previous videos either the ten
minutes fast builds or my tutorials my
20 tips on blender tutorial most of
these techniques I show in those videos
pretty much in detail all the keyboard
shortcuts and things like that so make
sure you check out my channel history if
you want to check some more check check
check
a lot of check in it but if you want to
see some techniques anyway to learn a
little bit more about this
so obviously this part is not really a
tutorial I could probably spend hours
talking about this in all it took me
about what could I say maybe half an
hour to make the track something like
that so because I kept changing my mind
a little bit using different techniques
and then I messed up the vertices a
little bit and I had to redo a lot of
merging process and things like that
and that's it that's the track done so
then I have to just do one thing more
and that's just as simple terrain so I
add another quad mesh here or a plane I
make it about a hundred units in size
and then I do a bunch of loop cuts again
both horizontally and vertically and I
like to keep the low-poly style and it's
also nice for the for the car when it
drives around to have some nice slanted
edges I might increase the detail
slightly in the future but for now I
just kept it like this so I press ctrl R
to do all the loop cuts in both
directions here and then I just select a
few random basically a few random faces
and I raise them up a bit and I drop
them down couldn't make up my mind again
that's a bit of a trend that I've got to
change my mind a lot but up and down
down and up and then for some reason I
selected all those individually totally
idiotic but I did it anyway and made a
little room there it's gonna be a police
station there so I left a little gap
there and here's a little canal or a
little stream of water and there's a
little lake part and then I created a
little raised area as well so this is a
lot of a bit of a diorama of a racetrack
so maybe I'll add some stuff to the side
so later on I'm not sure that's actually
gonna be all that I show in this episode
I've got everything the game is actually
running now so I've set some fast lap
times I had to make sure I kept playing
until I had some 20 second life time it
was a lot of fun took me a while maybe
40 laps or something like that but it
did in the end and I also use this it's
super simple in unity to tangles with
all the cables but you can either run it
with a keyboard or you can use the
controller and I think what I'll do is
I'm gonna put together soon a little web
playable version and I want to see how
you guys can perform and what sort of a
lot of times you get maybe I'll even
throw a leaderboard in there before it
maybe get a little healthy competition
going while we make this game but should
be fun I hope you liked this video and I
hope it gave you a little bit of an
insight to how I started making this
little racing game I've got pretty much
all the content recorded up until the
game played in the plane I've got the
wheel Collider the
the life timer things with the
checkpoints and things like that so
everything that you've seen in the intro
video and things like that I've already
got that immunity running it's just a
matter of me finding the time now to put
those together into videos because
everything's recorded so I hope you
enjoyed this video it was a lot of fun
to make it and I'm looking forward to
putting the future episodes together and
more importantly I like to play it and
more importantly I want to play this
game so I wonder if I can make it
multiplayer as well I should be fun give
a thumbs up if you like this video hit
the subscribe button if you want to see
some more stuff like this and I'll see
you soon in the next video take care
stay safe have fun to stuff did I say
too little
[Music]
you