hi guys this stefan fashion also known
as infancia
and i'm making a game called that's
racing which is a low polygon racing
game and for that game I'm gonna need a
lot of low poly trees and I've started
to make some in blender here and I
wanted to go through the process of how
I make them and maybe I can share some
tips and tricks on how you can make your
own polygon trees and I'll also bring
them into unity and show you some of the
shader effects that you can apply to get
them to sway a little bit in the wind
and also add some weather effects to
them so as you can see here already got
got a bunch of trees and I've been able
to screencast keys here so you should be
able to see all the keystrokes that I do
and I'm gonna be trying to say them all
out loud as well and I'm by no means a
blender expert so bear with me when I
hit the wrong Keys all the time but just
gonna have to live with it maybe I'll
try to edit some of it out as well but
what's huh let's see how it goes so as
you can see I've made a bunch of trees
here and I've also got a whole bunch of
tree trunks here that I'm going to be
adding foilage to later on and I but I
will be making a tree from scratch so I
can show you that a whole process here
and so I press shift C to get the cursor
back into the center mode and then I
press the del key to get the rotation
the way I want it and I'm also usually
in orthographic mode which is when I
make these trees rather than perspective
so shift a to add a mesh and I always go
start with a cube and let's go into the
front view in orthographic and I also
want to make sure that trees that
they're at the base so when you place it
in the terrain it's gonna be a lot
easier so I press tab and then I press s
to scale it down a little bit to get a
smaller stem and then I also want to
move the bottom mesh here so I've got
the face select here and I want to move
that face up to is that zero to make
sure that it's at the very base of the
object at the pivot point and from there
I might as well actually do the UV
mapping here as well so I select all the
faces and I go into the UV editing mode
and I've already loaded this very simple
pallet for a tree
that I'm gonna be using and we clicked
all meshes oops
unwrap it just like this and since I'm
not text you're mapping it I just want
the colors from the texture so I just
shrink all these meshes meshes or faces
down and then I press G to grab it and
then I move it into the center of the
brown because this time it's gonna be
brown at all times so that I have three
different shades for the leaves later on
and then I go back into the default mode
and then we're gonna make a model a
basic stem here so I make sure I'm in
face mode here actually I'll go into
perspective mode now I think which is
long pod for five again and then I just
work by extruding let's see I have to
get this off this is the proportional
editing which I don't want no it moves
faces which are in in the neighborhood
so I disable that and then basically I
just exclude and I press the S key to
scale the face and then I can extrude
again and then shrink that down a little
bit and then basically I just work with
the S key for scale and G for if I press
D to grab I move it a little bit offset
like that and then you can also click on
these gizmo arrows to move it on a
specific axis here so and then press key
again to extrude up G to move it a
little bit and then let's say here I
come to a point where I want to split
this into multiple branches and since I
want the low-poly look I just do efore
extrude again and I just go up a little
bit like this because now I can grab a
face here and then extrude this one with
E and then I might move it a little bit
and then maybe a little bit by using the
axes and then s to scale and then also
we can go on top here and mix through
this one again scale and then I work
like this and by just extruding the
faces pressing G to grab them and move
them basically extrude here grab scale
grab let's move this one up a lot now
let's say we want this one to move over
a little bit more like this then also
you can grab the bait out extra this one
again and then I'll split this into
multiple branches here this scale grab
up and let's do one more here extrude
with es4 scale this one up and here as
well now you can grab a whole bunch of
faces I like to work with that ctrl key
I go into vertex select instead then I
hold the ctrl key and then I can draw
all the vertices that I want to select
and I press R to rotate and as you can
see now it didn't pick the back ones so
I press esque
escape to go out of that and I enable
this one so now it also shows me the
vertices that are behind and I redo this
I press all to select a to select
everything and a to deselect everything
again is wrong so the ctrl key click
drag around all the vertices I want and
then R to rotate G to grab and move it a
little bit again and then I basically
just worked like this
in different view modes just get an
interesting tree look and then I can
also do the same thing with a scale here
and you can also set the if you want it
to scale in a let's see if I press you
see when I scale now it scales from the
center of the object which I wouldn't
want to do that if I scale a whole tree
up so if I press the period key on the
keyboard
it changes the scaled center to the
pivot point word to the yeah the pivot
point of the object so if I scale now as
you can see it grows the whole tree and
it's also important to be in face mode
here so with the tub so you can see the
faces so you scale all the time within
the this one because if I go out of edit
mode it's important that this scale is
always 1 it makes it easier later on you
can fix it later on as well but try to
stick to keep it at one day so when you
have a tree like this maybe that's all
we want for this one and then we want to
add this foilage look to it their leaves
and there are a number of ways I do that
but I'll take you through one of them
for this particular tree and so I press
tab to get out of the object mode and
then I press a to deselect everything
and then let's say I want to add I click
on this face here and it'll put the
cursor right there and then I press
shift a to add in this case I'll add a
cube and then I want to apply a modifier
here which is the subdivision surface
and let's bring it up to 2 and that
basically just creates a sphere cube map
sphere and I like to work with different
shapes you could have used this one
called the ICO sphere for example which
I use sometimes as well but for this
case I'll just use the cube and
subdivide it and then I click apply to
get this mesh the way I want and then I
press tab to go into edit mode face
select a to select all the faces and
then I go into the UV editing sorry
and then I press on rap and again it
doesn't matter that all the faces are
showing like this because we're not
going to text your map it in the
traditional way way of UV doing UV
Islands so I'll press s to scale this
down let's do that again G to grab them
and then I'll move them up just to get
this solid green color there and then
what I want to do is I want to go back
into the default view here and then I
can switch off the transparency there
and then press a twice first to deselect
everything and then again to select and
then I press shift D to duplicate this
and then I put this G to grab I want to
place it just at the tip of that branch
like this shift D again to duplicate and
I'm this is I'm in the same object now
this is still the same object I'm just
duplicating all the mesh the vertices
and the faces here I used G to grab it
and move it into the place and then I
press shift D again let's add that one
up there G to grab it and move it a
little bit and if I want to change now
as you can see that this gizmo is
controlling and that's because I used
the pivot point of the object when I
wanted to resize the tree but if I press
the key that comma key no then it'll
change it to the center of the vertices
that I've added or these faces here and
I press shift D again now I can actually
use these arrows as well as since I
press the comma key to get the center
point of the mesh so now I've added some
then that looks crap to be honest but
we're not done yet so let's fix this we
don't want this like perfect symmetrical
or spherical shape so basically what you
can do now is if you press tab mode
you can actually select if I press L now
it will select all the linked faces or
vertices for this particular group of
vertices and I if I just go and click
the L key now on all these I aim with
the mouse and I click L then I can
select all the faces here I could have
clicked a actually so if I deselect
everything in click again so in this
case I could have used a but sometimes
it's really useful to use the L key to
get the linked vertices and first thing
we can do for example is let's let's
actually rescale this and make these a
little bit bigger and then I can't be in
this with everything selected because if
I do that as you can see that all like
just sent outwards so this operation
actually need to do on these
individually so I click again to
deselect I click L or let's see I mean
select the face first L to select this
face and then now if I scale it scales
it in place here so let's just click
these L to get the links and then just
to make these a little bit bigger L for
the link once I select with the right
with the right mouse button l scale up a
little bit and this one again L scale so
and now we want to get some irregularity
to this these look weight around so what
you can do then for example is if I
click a to select everything or actually
I don't need to do that because this
operates on the whole mesh mode or on
the whole object level so and I go to
the modifier and I want to end a
displace modifier and here I want to
click on new and change this into I'll
click on this one here and I change this
into a cloud texture resume this in a
little bit then I go back to the
modifier and if I change the strength
here now I need to go out of edit mode
actually so I tab now you can see that
it warps this the mesh is a little bit
thing gets out of that it regular so
when I do that
you get starting to get a little bit of
a different view to it I'll do it
you can also change change this one the
level so let's say we wanted it like
that
maybe that's and then I click apply here
now so this could be one tree if you
wanted like this I still think it needs
a little bit of work to it so usually I
just play around in in this edit mode
here so maybe for example I want to do
if I add another modifier here saying
let's subdivide this one into let's see
that work no that's gonna be way too
many meshes so that's not subdivide it
let's instead do this decimates modifier
and then scale it down then I start
reducing actually vertices here to get
even more of a low poly look like that
and when I go into edit mode you see
that effect disappears and it's because
it's showing me the mesh instead this
modifier operates on not on on the mesh
edit mode but on the object mode so I
need to be out of the mesh edit mode
with a table here let's apply this one
and I still think that these groups of
these chunks should be a bit bigger so
let's make them a little bit bigger
again tab into edit mode I'll click on
one face ll to select all the link s to
scale it let's scale all of these up l
scale select L scale just like that face
owl scale and then L to select links and
then scale here we go so now we're
starting to get a tree that I like the
look of then I like to name them
properly I press shift C to get back
into the cursor mode in if it
if it's when you rotated you and it
doesn't pivot around this you can press
the del Delete key I think now I should
have fully rotates nope there we go
I needed up in object mode so I press I
don't want to go into orthographic mode
again here now and then number one to
get the front view so let's say I was
happy with this tree now and then I want
to rename my objects I'm up to treat 12
here so I'm gonna make 3 13 so this cube
I'll double click on that one and rename
it tree Oh 13 there because this one as
you can see has not doesn't have the
leaves
let's now let's move that one out
because we want to keep that one for a
bear tree but I'm pleased chef D to
duplicate the whole object escaped
because and then we can move it back to
0 here and now what I want to do is I
want to parent or I want to join so I
select these this object with all the
leaves and then I shift and oh no yeah
sorry I shift and right click on the
tree and I press ctrl J to join these
together so now it's a single mesh and
let's call this one regular so this is
the normal look of this tree and this
tree model is actually finished I think
I'm allergic to blender maybe so let's
go this tree is finished now but let's
say I want to make a different
variations as you can see here I've got
got a bunch of four variations of each
tree and I want to make another one so
I've moved out onto this side I crap
press shift D to duplicate it escape
back and then I'll move it to here and
now I want to operate just on these
leaves I want to keep the stem the same
way so if I go into edit mode now I want
to break this into a separate mesh again
so I can operate on just the leaves and
not this the easiest way to do that one
is to select something on the tree here
and repress l-4 linked and that will
pick all the vertexes and/or vertices
and faces for the tree trunk there press
ctrl I to invert that selection and then
I press P to separate and I separate by
selection here and now this is snapped
back into a separate object as you can
see here so if I select this one last
you can see this is a separate object
now and that's how I want to work on on
this and now let's make a little
variation so I go into edit mode and I
select all the vertices and then maybe I
want to scale them up a little bit and
here I like to start playing as well
with this proportional editing so I
enabled this proportional editing and
then maybe I want to select some random
vertices at the top here of the mesh
press one to get into the front view
again
let's select shift select this vertex
this one and then if I move this up now
you can see not only does it move the
vertices that are selected but it moves
the ones that are in the vicinity as
well this is insanity so you say in the
neighborhood and if I press controls and
I do that again I can also press G to
grab this and then I press Z or Z to
force it to move it on the the z-axis up
and down and then if I use the scroll
wheel now I can change how much this
proportional editing should be affecting
this so I can pull this up so if I
change this one maybe I want to create
the tree that looks a bit like this and
I can also use scaling and that's also
proportional so now we suddenly got a
trade with a different look to it
similar but still enough different to
maybe save that one and to keep this
tree I want to have it as one mesh
or one object at least so I click on
this one and I shift and right click on
the tree trunk I press ctrl J to join it
I'm gonna rename this one to Lush maybe
because it's nice and lush it's got some
more foilage to it let's one make one
last variation of this tree as well just
to cement this whole thing in I press I
select this one
press shift D to duplicate it escape to
snap it back I move it into view here
where I would like to work on it it's
not a must that you do it
that's origin here but I like to do it
that way let's go into tab mode again
edits this object and remember here we
want to select something on the tree
trunk press L to get all the link
vertices ctrl I to invert the selection
and then press P to the touch
selection separator now I can work on
this object alone and here maybe we want
to I like to twist these around as well
so if I select the top vertices here
again like I did last time
and one nice effect for these low poly
trees I found was if you select this one
you keep this proportional editing
enabled and you press R to rotate and
then Zed to make sure that it rotates
around the center is that axis let's
scale this one up with me so if you just
add a little slight twist to it that can
make the trees look a bit interesting as
well like that for example I've got
quite a nice aesthetics - I think and
then let's add a little bit more let's
try a little bit more on this particular
mesh let's see how this goes so I go tab
out of into object mode let's add this
modifier now and do a subdivision to
levels and the let's apply this modifier
and this is going to be too many
polygons now for this low poly look this
is starting to get too detailed but
before we decimate this one that still
add a modifier and displace this one a
little bit let's pick that texture that
we did before which was the cloud
texture
and let's play around with a strength a
little bit maybe like that apply this
modifier and then finally let's do a big
decimate here as well this way too many
their faces on this one so let's do
decimates bring it down to and then
apply this one and as you can see now
it's a lot further it's a lot fewer
here's what another trick yard to get a
little bit different as you can if you
remember I had a palette here in the UV
mapping with some different colors so if
I do seven to get the top view here and
then make sure I don't have this
transparency thing selected so that's
disabled I press the B key for box
select and now it's selected all the
faces that have that can be viewed from
on top and I want to reduce the
selection a little bit by shrinking it
so press ctrl - on the numpad and that
shrinks down my selection a little bit
and then I press G here when I'm over
the UV map and I'll move this to there
and now I've got some parts some
polygons that are brighter up here with
a different shade and also if I press
ctrl 7 I'll in the same way I'll get the
base of the tree so b4 box selected and
then ctrl - to shrink it down a little
bit
actually let's go into the face then
maybe I'll keep the shift key and I'll
press a few of these as well I'll just
select some random meshes down here or
faces sorry maybe these pose as well
like that and then I go over here on the
left side press G and I move this down
to the darker shade so now we've got a
little bit of color variation in this to
usable so there we go finally is to join
this one so I'll go back into the
default view here press one to get the
front view select this one shift selects
tree trunk control J and then let's call
this one twisty here we go so that's the
low-poly
editing of this tree maybe that gave you
some hints and tips and tricks on how to
do low poly edit modeling in blender and
in the next video I'll import this tree
into unity and I'll show you an
amplified shader that I made using the
amplify acid and it'll add some
character to the tree by making its way
a little bit in the wind using the
vertex shader and it'll also I'll make a
little weather effect to them as well
that you can look at so have a look at
that video you can view it so I'll put a
link here somewhere just click on that
enjoy I hope you have fun modeling in
blender take care see ya
[Music]