what's up guys justin here with the
cgessentials.com back with another
blender rendering tutorial for you
so in today's video we're going to check
out how to use freestyle in order to
render out the
edges so they actually show up inside
your renders
in blender so let's go ahead and get
started alright so i will link to the
information about freestyle
in the blender documentation so that you
can check that out and take a look but
in this video we're going to
start by looking at how to render out
our image
with different line styles so
first things first if we were to render
this right now so if we just render the
image it's going to look something like
this
right so depending on if you have ev
activated or cycles you might get some
shadows in here
but you can see how right now um this is
a very kind of blocky shape
with not a lot of definition what we
might want to do is we might want to
come in here and render this out
so that the edges actually show up as
lines
in our rendering and so the way that
we're going to do that is we're going to
jump over
into our let's see we're going to jump
over into our render properties
and so the easiest way to start adding
freestyle is just to come down here
and just check the box for freestyle and
so when we activate freestyle
if we run a render so i'm just going to
tap f12 in order to do this
you can see how you're going to get a
rendering in here that now has
edges highlighted inside of our
rendering
so you can use this to quickly add those
edges inside of your scenes
so now let's take a look at this if we
were to adjust the line thickness
so i'm just going to come in here and
set my line thickness to 3
instead of 1. so if i set my line
thickness to three
and then we were to rerun this render
so i'm just going to tap f12 you can see
how these edges are going to be thicker
so you can control the thickness of
those edges from this section
right here but let's say we wanted to
get a little more in depth on what's
actually being created
right so that's great but it doesn't
really give us any control
over anything other than there's some
edges in here so what we want to do
is we want to jump over into our view
layer properties
and we want to scroll down to our
freestyle
line sets and so what our freestyle line
sets is going to do is that's going to
let us control
the kind of lines that are being created
notice how you can add multiple
different line sets in here
if you were to run this render without a
line set in here so if i was to delete
this
even though we have freestyle enabled if
we were to run this
you can see how no edges are going to
show up so you need to have a line set
in here because that's what this is
going to reference in order to create
those edges
and so there's a lot of different
options in here for
different things that you can do with
this and so there's some different
options in here
for things that you can do in order to
change the way
that your edges look inside of freestyle
so
um we'll look at these i'm not going to
worry too much about these right here
um so we may take a look take a look at
the render pass option a little bit
later
but for right now we're just going to
leave it as is so you can use this to
render this as a separate
pass instead of on the combined pass
which gives you some interesting options
but for now let's take a look first at
this option right here
so your edge detection option your
crease angle
that's going to control what edges are
being picked up
that are actually getting those darkened
edges so right now we have a crease
angle of 134 degrees well if we were to
bump this up
to 180 degrees and then re-run this so
if we're to do an f12
notice how you're going to get freestyle
edges
basically on all of the different edges
inside
of your model so now i'm seeing all of
the geometry in here
so you can control how heavy that is by
adjusting the
degrees of your edge detection so if i
were to drop that down to 90
for example you're going to get a lot
less edges in here you're really only
getting the edges around the perimeter
at that point so you can use that to
kind of adjust the overall
in here to whatever you want i'm going
to put it back to 134 degrees for right
now
so culling is helpful because it can
hide the out of view
edges so you're not doing that extra
processing work and so there's also some
advanced options in here which i don't
want to focus on too much for right now
so we can mess around with that in the
future if you're really interested in it
but i don't think we're going to use
those
too much so as of right now though
what's happening
is the system is kind of dictating
the way that our edges are showing up
right so it's finding them for us
using its algorithm and so there's
different things in here
that can adjust that and affect that and
so you can use
these options down below to get a little
bit more specific about what's being
shown in here
and so i'm going to stay kind of high
level on this um just note that these
different options
are going to are going to bring in
different edges
when you render this so for example if
you were to select ridge and valley
and then rerun this notice how you're
getting some
different edges in here than you were
before
in some different areas but it's a
little bit clunky so you're going to
have to do a little bit of trial and
error in here to figure out the
exact view that you really want or the
exact settings that really work
but what i do want to focus on right now
is at the moment
we're currently set to do this based on
our crease edges
right so it's using the crease angle in
here in order to generate those edges
and so let's say for example that we
were to uncheck this box for crease
edges
and then rerun this well notice how now
you're really only getting the border
or the silhouette of the object and
that's being added based on the
silhouette and border options
right here so if i was to uncheck those
notice how we start getting some kind of
weird results in here
so we want to leave this to include the
silhouette and the border
but let's say that we wanted some edges
that were running along the bonnie model
to be highlighted right so let's say for
example and we're going to tab
into edit mode real quick let's say that
we wanted
these edges right here to show up
in our freestyle well what we could do
is we could select the edges that we
want
but then you can right click in edit
mode and there's an option here for mark
freestyle edge so if you mark this as a
freestyle edge
and you check the box for edge mark in
here what that's going to do is that's
going to include that
in your rendered image so notice how now
this edge right here
is being included inside of our image
so you can use that to be more specific
about what exactly you want the
freestyle edges to show in here
if you decide you don't want that to
show up then you could just come in here
and select it
and then right click and you can just
clear the freestyle edge
if you clear the freestyle edge it's not
going to show up in your rendering
anymore so you can also down below
set your freestyle line styles as well
so up till now we've been basically
setting what's going
to show up as a part of that freestyle
but if you go down into your line style
you can also set the way
that this is going to show up so for
example
you can set the kind of line strokes
that are in here you can set the color
of your edges so for example let's say i
wanted these to render out
something other than black i could come
in here and set this to maybe like blue
then if we were to do an f12 our edges
are going to render out as blue
and so you could set the color by
clicking in here but if we were to go
back into the strokes
setting there's an option down here for
things like dashed line
so if you wanted your lines to be dashed
you could set this
so that your first dash is has a length
of 5 and then the gap has a length of
five
so i just checked the box and then
entered some values in here well now if
i was to render this out
instead of having straight lines what
we're going to have is we're going to
have dotted lines in here
so you could use this to create some
kind of a blueprint view or a
highlighted view
or something like that alright so your
alpha is going to allow you to adjust
how solid the lines are so for example
right now if i render this right and we
look at it right here i've got some
thicker edges
and they're all kind of just like
uniform black lines but
if you were to come in here and adjust
your alpha transparency down
notice how your lines are much less
defined
right it's like you kind of drew them on
here with a pencil or something like
that
so there's also options in here to do
things like add modifiers
to that as well so you could add some
noise
to your alpha so if you add noise what
that's going to do is that's going to
randomly give you
darker and lighter areas those are all
adjustable based on things like
amplitude
other things like that they're just
going to give you different effects
so you can use that to make this more
like a noisy
like hand drawn stroke type thing so
you can also adjust your thickness of
your edges in the thickness tab
so if i bring this down notice how my
edges are going to be more narrow
if i bring this up my edges are going to
be a lot thicker so you can use that to
adjust the thickness
in here and you can also
set this with a modifier so for example
you could come in here and add a noise
modifier
to your thickness and what that's going
to do is that's going to adjust your
thickness
randomly and so you can adjust like how
strong that
that is by adjusting these settings
so you can adjust that thickness down
for example
in order to just give like a little bit
of wobble to these lines
so you could couple that with maybe
something like
so you could couple that with something
like your alpha transparency to create
some really interesting
results all right so one last thing i
wanted to show you
for right now we can talk about this
more in the future but
um what i wanted to do is i wanted to
show you how to create
this image so this is just some cabinets
i created in the piclone build of
blender and i wanted to show you how to
render out just the
edges from this image so right now right
we have this just set up a standard
freestyle so it's going to create our
rendered view
then it's going to add the edges over
here what we want to do is we want to
use the compositor to create an
image that only includes the edges and a
color
background and so the first thing i want
to do is i'm going to go back
into my view layer properties under
freestyle
and i want to check the box for as
render pass
and so what we're going to do when uh
this is rendered as a render pass
what that means is that means that now
instead of this using this as a
composite
like this if we were to go into our view
layer and look at our freestyle
you can see how those edges are being
created as a completely separate pass
in your rendering engine so now
what i want to do is i want to jump over
into the compositing
tab
and what i've done is i've just created
a view
with my image editor up above and then
my compositor
down below we'll go ahead and drag this
up a little bit so we can zoom in
a little bit more and so right now what
this has is this has our render layers
and it has our composite and so what we
want to do
is we want to go in here and so what
this has is this has a check box for as
render pass
well notice how when i check the box for
as render pass
right here what that's doing is that's
adding a node to my render layers
that i can drag into my composite so
instead having my freestyle
in here right now or instead of having
my image dragged in here right now i'm
just going to drag
the line for my freestyle over here so
you can see how what that's doing
is that's creating this image right here
that only has my freestyle
edges but we also need a color
background
so what we want to do is we just want to
do a shift a and we want to add
a mix node so i'm just going to type in
search i'm going to type in
mix we're going to click right here and
what we want
is we want this freestyle running into
this mix node
and then the image running out to the
composite but what we want to do is
we're going to drag the freestyle
into the bottom box and undrag it from
the top box
and so what that's going to do is that's
going to give us a black screen
right so we don't have anything in here
right now so what we want to do is we
want to click on the button right here
for alpha in order to include the alpha
of the second
input what that means is that means that
we're basically going to use the
transparent background for the second
input so when you click on this
notice how now what you're getting is
you're getting an
image in here with a white background
and your edges
over top of it and so one thing to note
about this is if we were to go back for
example
and adjust our line thickness so if we
were to scroll into our freestyle line
style
and adjust this so our thickness
is bigger so maybe to a value of like
six and then
if we were to type the f12 key what
that's going to do is that's going to
re-render this
and notice how then this update's in
here i've not figured out how to get the
image editor to
update automatically so if anyone knows
let me know
but now what this is going to allow us
to do is that's going to allow us
from our 3d model so if i was to drag
this
over and have a 3d viewport node
right here you can see our 3d image
is over here but we're generating this
2d
line style image inside a blender so
then if we were to type f12
and then export this notice how this is
exporting this is a render result that
we can then save
as an image so that's from in this video
leave a comment below and let me know
what you thought was this helpful to you
have you used freestyle before it's love
having that conversation with you guys
if you like this video please remember
to click that like button down below
if you're new around here remember to
click that subscribe button for new
blender content
every week if you like what i'm doing on
this channel please consider supporting
me on patreon
every little bit helps so make sure you
check out that link in the notes down
below but in any case thank you so much
for taking the time to watch this
i really appreciate it and i will catch
you in the next video thanks guys